[
  {
    "question": "The trim tab :",
    "feedback": "reduces hinge moment and control surface efficiency."
  },
  {
    "question": "A thermal circuit breaker:",
    "feedback": "protects the system in the event of a prolonged overcurrent"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.  GEN 1 can be used to feed the AC BUS 1, when: (NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumed to remain open)",
    "feedback": "C1.1 is closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "A turbocharger in a reciprocating engine consists of a :",
    "feedback": "compressor and turbine mounted on a common shaft."
  },
  {
    "question": "The type of a aircraft oxygen system intended for use by passengers, is mostly :",
    "feedback": "a continuous flow system"
  },
  {
    "question": "On large pressurised jet transport aeroplanes, the maximum cabin differential pressure is approximately:",
    "feedback": "7-9 psi"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the correct sequence during the in-flight wind-milling start of a turbine engine?",
    "feedback": "Rotation, ignition, fuel"
  },
  {
    "question": "The most important oil system instrument indication during gas turbine engine start is:",
    "feedback": "oil pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which part of the nose landing gar is shown by the number 2?",
    "feedback": "Retraction actuator"
  },
  {
    "question": "On most large aeroplanes, the main source of braking power is derived from:",
    "feedback": "the hydraulic system"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements is correct about a flight crew oxygen mask?",
    "feedback": "Above a certain altitude oxygen is always delivered at a slight overpressure independent of selected mask position"
  },
  {
    "question": "A circuit breaker :",
    "feedback": "may be reset manually after the fault has been rectified."
  },
  {
    "question": "In accordance with EASA AIR OPS and if necessary, the number of liferafts to be found on board an aircraft must allow the transportation of the entire aircraft occupants:",
    "feedback": "in the case of a loss of one raft of the largest rated capacity."
  },
  {
    "question": "How many megaphones are required in an airplane with two passenger decks and a maximum approved seating configuration of 50 seats on the lower deck and 15 seats on the upper deck, with a total of 28 passengers on board?",
    "feedback": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "The primary performance indicator (cockpit instrument) for the thrust of a turbofan engine is:",
    "feedback": "either EPR or N1"
  },
  {
    "question": "The correct formula to calculate the total displacement of a multi-cylinder piston engine is the:",
    "feedback": "piston area x piston stroke x numbers of cylinders"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which part of the nose landing gear is shown by the number 1?",
    "feedback": "Steering actuator"
  },
  {
    "question": "Usually, electric heating for ice protection is used on:",
    "feedback": "Pitot tubes."
  },
  {
    "question": "Define the term \"fatigue\":",
    "feedback": "If a material is continually loaded and unloaded it will eventually break even though the load remains the same"
  },
  {
    "question": "The flight crew must be notified if a large amount of lithium batteries are being carried in cargo compartments, as these batteries ....",
    "feedback": "have the potential to start an uncontrolled chain reaction when an individual cell is damaged"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where are smoke detectors if installed, located in an aircraft?",
    "feedback": "In the avionics, lavatory and cargo compartments"
  },
  {
    "question": "The blade angle of a propeller is the angle between the :",
    "feedback": "reference chord line and the propeller plane of rotation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What regulates the speed of a turbocharger?",
    "feedback": "Waste gate."
  },
  {
    "question": "The advantages of thermal anti-icing are :\n1. Simple and reliable system\n2. Profiles maintained\n3. Greater efficiency than that of an electrical resistor\n4. Direct use of the hot air from the jet engine without substantial reduction in engine thrust\nThe combination of correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1,2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The compressor pressure ratio of an axial compressor is primarily determined by the:",
    "feedback": "number of stages"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the system depicted in the graph, the main purpose of the DC fuel pump in the left main tank is to:",
    "feedback": "supply fuel to the APU"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about fire-extinguishing agents are correct or incorrect?\n1) The fire extinguishing effect of Halon is based on suppressing the chemical reaction of a fire\n2) Halon should be used with caution because it is highly corrosive particularly for aluminium",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "The fuel system boost pumps are submerged in the fuel ..",
    "feedback": "To prime the pumps."
  },
  {
    "question": "In an automatic electrical starting system the ignition commences:",
    "feedback": "at the same time the starter motor engages."
  },
  {
    "question": "Spark timing is related to engine speed in the way that the:",
    "feedback": "faster the engine functions, the more the spark is advanced"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the possible causes and indications of a tailpipe fire?",
    "feedback": "Fuel may puddle in the turbine casings and exhaust during start-up or shutdown, and then ignite. This can result in a highly visible jet of flame out of the back of the engine"
  },
  {
    "question": "A manual inflation handle:",
    "feedback": "serves to actuate inflation of a slide when automatic inflation fails"
  },
  {
    "question": "The demand valve of a diluter-demand type oxygen regulator in normal mode, operates when the :",
    "feedback": "user breathes in"
  },
  {
    "question": "The safest method of priming a piston engine for starting is:",
    "feedback": "injection of fuel in the cylinder intake ports"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct about the flow in a divergent (subsonic) gas turbine engine intake?\n\n1) The static pressure increases in flow direction\n2) The total temperature remains constant in flow direction",
    "feedback": "1) is correct,2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Compare the pressure ratio of a centrifugal compressor with the pressure ratio of an axial flow compressor. A typical value of the pressure ratio of an axial compressor is:",
    "feedback": "35:1"
  },
  {
    "question": "If an engine detonates during climb-out, the normal corrective action would be to:",
    "feedback": "retard the throttle"
  },
  {
    "question": "A static inverter is a:",
    "feedback": "transistorized unit used to convert DC into AC."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following conditions most likely lead to detonation?",
    "feedback": "Use of fuel with too low octane rating."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about composite and metal structures are correct or incorrect?  1) In a structural component with given dimensions constructed of composite materials, the strength is the same in all directions 2) Composite materials enable structures with higher strength/weight ratio than metal structures",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "A starter-generator is an electrical generator that ....",
    "feedback": "operates as an electric motor during engine start"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FADEC (Full Authority Digital Engine Control) provides:\n1) Engine automatic shut-down if maximum N1 is exceeded\n2) Engine automatic shut-down if maximum EGT is exceeded\n3) Automatic thrust rating control\n4) Fully automatic engine starting\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a threat to aircraft and affects the risk of lithium type batteries?\n1) Numbers of batteries on board an aircraft including those brought on board by passengers2) Temperature of both battery and environment3) Physical condition of the battery4) Battery charging\nThe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a compensated capacitance fuel contents system, what happens to the fuel weight of 14.000 lbs if its volume decreases by 5% due to colder temperature?",
    "feedback": "Remains the same."
  },
  {
    "question": "A continuous loop detector system is a .......",
    "feedback": "overheat detection system"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.\n\nOn ground, external power (EXT PWR) can be used to feed both AC BUS 1 and AC BUS 2, when:\n(NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumend to remain open)",
    "feedback": "C1.2, C2.1 and C2.2 are closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "The auto-brake system is disarmed or switched off after touch-down by:",
    "feedback": "application of manual braking"
  },
  {
    "question": "Flaps which not only move down, but also increase the wing area by extending backwards on tracking are called:",
    "feedback": "fowler flap."
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.\n\nOn ground, APU GEN can be used to feed the AC BUS 2, when:\n(NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumend to remain open)",
    "feedback": "C1.3 and C2.2 are closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "A fuel strainer when fitted to a carburettor will be positioned :",
    "feedback": "upstream of the needle valve."
  },
  {
    "question": "A main landing gear is said to be \"locked down\" when:",
    "feedback": "the strut is locked by an overcentre mechanism."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about oxygen in transport aeroplanes is correct?",
    "feedback": "If the automatic passenger oxygen mask presentation fails, it is possible to retrieve an individual mask by opening the mask storage compartment with a sharp pointed object"
  },
  {
    "question": "In modern aircraft, a pilot can actuate the feather system by :",
    "feedback": "pulling the RPM lever backwards."
  },
  {
    "question": "What could happen if the center tank low pressure fuel pumps have failed?",
    "feedback": "All, or parts of the fuel in the center tank are unusable"
  },
  {
    "question": "Diesel engines always produce a certain amount of soot, because:",
    "feedback": "the fuel droplets coming from the atomiser do not burn completely"
  },
  {
    "question": "A smoke mask is a :",
    "feedback": "mask with flow on request and covers the whole face."
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the fuel schematic of the two-engine aircraft. Where on the diagram is a jettison valve located?",
    "feedback": "Position 7"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an AC power generation, the Constant Speed Drive (CSD):\n\n1- can be disconnected from the engine shaft.\n2- can be disconnected from the generator.\n3- is a hydro-mechanical system.\n4- is an electronic system.\n5- can not be disconnected in flight.\n6- can be disconnected in flight.\n\nThe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 6"
  },
  {
    "question": "An engine pressure ratio (EPR) can be defined as the ratio of:",
    "feedback": "jet pipe pressure to compressor inlet pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "A relay is :",
    "feedback": "a magnetically operated switch."
  },
  {
    "question": "Generally, on modern jet transport aeroplanes, if there is a complete hydraulic system failure, the landing gear can be extended by:",
    "feedback": "gravity extension"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some turbine-engined aeroplanes are fitted with trim tanks. Where are these normally placed and what is their purpose?",
    "feedback": "They are placed in the tail of the aeroplane, and their function is to control the CG location during flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "A smoke hood is a device covering:",
    "feedback": "the whole head and with a continuous oxygen flow"
  },
  {
    "question": "Assume an initial condition at a high cruise altitude with a constant speed propeller. What will happen if the altitude is decreased while the throttle remains fully open and the waste gate is seized in the cruise position?",
    "feedback": "The manifold absolute pressure (MAP) value may exceed the maximum allowed value"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main function of an air cycle machine is to :",
    "feedback": "cool the bleed air."
  },
  {
    "question": "In which part of a gas turbine engine are high temperature requirements most critical for the materials used?",
    "feedback": "The combustion chamber and front part of the HP turbine"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the brake assembly there is an anti-skid system. From which device does the anti-skid control box get the information to regulate the brake pressure?",
    "feedback": "From a wheel speed sensor."
  },
  {
    "question": "The services connected to a supply bus-bar are normally in:",
    "feedback": "parallel, so that isolating individual loads decreases the bus-bar current consumption."
  },
  {
    "question": "The rate of decrease of thrust from a twin spool compressor engine, compared with a single spool engine, as altitude increase:",
    "feedback": "is less."
  },
  {
    "question": "The reason for the pressure accumulator in the hydraulic system is:",
    "feedback": "The accumulator serves as an internal shock absorber for the hydraulic system."
  },
  {
    "question": "During level flight at a constant cabin pressure altitude, the cabin outflow valves are:",
    "feedback": "partially open"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the variable-pitch propeller of a turbo-prop.\nDuring deceleration :",
    "feedback": "when braking, the propeller supplies a negative thrust and absorbs engine power."
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is scheduled to fly from PARIS to MARSEILLE at FL 390 and has the following characteristics:\nMaximum permissible number of passenger specified by the certificate of airworthiness= 230\nNumber of seats on board= 200\nScheduled number of passengers on board= 180\nThe minimum number of inhaler systems provided in the aircraft cabin should be:",
    "feedback": "220."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the freezing/waxing point of Jet A-1?",
    "feedback": "-47°C"
  },
  {
    "question": "The majority of fixed aircraft fire extinguisher systems use:",
    "feedback": "Bromochlorodifluoromethan Halon (1211) extinguishant."
  },
  {
    "question": "In an engine equipped with dual channel FADEC, what happens in the event of total FADEC failure?",
    "feedback": "The engine will fail"
  },
  {
    "question": "Associate the correct legend to each of the numbered diagrams :",
    "feedback": "1- cantilever   2- fork   3- half fork   4- dual wheels"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the advantages of multiple-spool jet engine designs is that:",
    "feedback": "a smaller air starter driving only a single spool can be used"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about chemical oxygen generators are correct or incorrect?\n1) Chemical oxygen generators are often used to supply passenger oxygen\n2) The oxygen supply of chemical oxygen generators, once activated, cannot be switched off",
    "feedback": "1) is correct,2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a gas turbine engine, compressor blades, which are not rigidly fixed in position when the engine is stationary, take up a rigid position when the engine is running due to :",
    "feedback": "the resultant of aerodynamic and centrifugal forces."
  },
  {
    "question": "The essential difference between aircraft AC alternators and DC generators (dynamos) is that the:",
    "feedback": "induced (output) windings of the alternators are fixed (stator), and the dynamos have a fixed inductor (field) coil."
  },
  {
    "question": "On a normally aspirated engine, the manifold pressure gauge always indicates:",
    "feedback": "a lower value than atmospheric pressure when the engine is running"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about chemical oxygen generators are correct or incorrect?\n1) Chemical oxygen generators are used to supply the cockpit system\n2) The oxygen supply of chemical oxygen generators, once activated, can be switched off",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "In computer technology, a storage peripheral is a:",
    "feedback": "hard disk drive"
  },
  {
    "question": "The fuel system boost pumps are used to :",
    "feedback": "avoid the bubbles accumulation and feed the lines with fuel for directing it to the engine at a positive pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of magnetic chip detectors is to:",
    "feedback": "warn of impending failure"
  },
  {
    "question": "The capacity of a battery is given in:",
    "feedback": "Ampere hours"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which answer is correct regarding stress, strain and loads on an aircraft?",
    "feedback": "Strain is the deformation caused by the action of stress on a material"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider a turbine-engined aeroplane with two underwing engines, fitted with two wing tanks and one centre tank. If all centre tank fuel booster pumps fail:",
    "feedback": "Part or all of the fuel in the centre tank is considered unusable"
  },
  {
    "question": "After a successful start of a high bypass turbofan engine, the air starter:",
    "feedback": "is disengaged by the coupling between engine N2 spool and starter by the use of centrifugal forces"
  },
  {
    "question": "A propeller is said to be \"double-acting\" when it:",
    "feedback": "uses oil pressure to move the blades towards fine and coarse."
  },
  {
    "question": "Select the correct answer from the following statements regarding the rotor of an AC or DC motor:\n1) Poor lubrication, misalignment or load unbalance may lead to the seizure of the drive shaft2) The rotor is supported by a bearing on one end",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is not correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is correct regarding ice protection of the horizontal stabiliser on a modern large commercial transport aircraft?",
    "feedback": "Some aircraft do not require tail anti-icing"
  },
  {
    "question": "In accordance with EASA AIR OPS, an airplane must be equipped with equipment or systems at each emergency exit that allow to reach the ground safely in the case of an emergency when the sill height of the passenger emergency exit is higher than:",
    "feedback": "1,83 m."
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the baffles in wing fuel tank is to:",
    "feedback": "restrict undesirable fuel movement during sideslip"
  },
  {
    "question": "The average stage compression ratio of a centrifugal compressor is approximately:",
    "feedback": "4:1"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the case of a thermal de-icing system overtemperature, this indicated by:",
    "feedback": "warning lights"
  },
  {
    "question": "When measuring the two terminals of a charging 12 V lead acid battery with a voltmeter, what reading will be observed?",
    "feedback": "14 V"
  },
  {
    "question": "By-pass ratio in a turbine engine is the ratio of the:",
    "feedback": "cold air mass flow to the hot air mass flow"
  },
  {
    "question": "An airplane whose maximum approved passenger seating configuration is 201 to 300 seats must be equipped with at least:",
    "feedback": "4 hand fire-extinguishers conveniently located in the passenger compartment."
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the system depicted in the graph with all tanks containing fuel, the APU can receive fuel from:",
    "feedback": "all tanks"
  },
  {
    "question": "Automatic temperature control of the system as shown would be accomplished by:",
    "feedback": "the temperature selector in conjunction with cabin sensors and the temperature regulator, modulating the mix valve."
  },
  {
    "question": "Modern fly-by-wire systems usually feature different modes of operation. Which are the most common ones?",
    "feedback": "Normal mode, Alternative (secondary) mode, Direct mode and Mechanical backup"
  },
  {
    "question": "The detection of a feeder fault on a direct current circuit results in:\n1. automatic disconnection of the generator from the aircraft AC busbar\n2. opening of generator field current relay\n3. opening of the main relay of the generator breaker\n4. opening of balancing circuit connecting two generators\n5. lighting of an indicator lamp\nThe combination of correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "The useful work area in an ideal Otto engine indicator diagram is enclosed by the following gas state change lines",
    "feedback": "2 adiabatic and 2 isochoric lines."
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\np0 = static ambient pressure\nt0 = static ambient temperature\nm = air mass flow\nVv = True Air Speed\nVj = jet efflux (exhaust) velocity\npj = jet efflux (exhaust) static pressure\ntj = jet efflux (exhaust) static temperature\nA = exhaust cross-sectional area\n\nThe thrust T of a jet engine is:",
    "feedback": "T=m(Vj-Vv)+A(pj-p0)"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the attached diagram, which image represents shear force?",
    "feedback": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "The indication of an internal leak in a hydraulic system will be:",
    "feedback": "a rise in fluid temperature"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about the capacity of a battery and its measurement are correct or incorrect?\n1) The battery capacity is determined by multiplying a current flow in Amperes by the time in hours that the battery is being discharged2) The total battery capacity is dependent on the voltage rating of its battery cells",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is not correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the hydraulic press schematically shown, what balancing Force would be acting on the right hand side ? (The diagram is not to scale)",
    "feedback": "4 N."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following correctly describes the beta range of a turboprop engine?",
    "feedback": "From just below flight idle to maximum reverse"
  },
  {
    "question": "The engine fuel control unit (FCU) is protected from damage by debris by:",
    "feedback": "the fine filter located between the high pressure fuel pump and the governor unit."
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of the drain valve in the combustion chamber is:\n\n1) to prevent a \"wet start\"\n2) to drain excessive air pressure during cruise flight\n3) to check if fuel is leaking at the nozzle guide vanes\n4) to drain remaining fuel off the cumbustion chamber after an engine shut down\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "An electrically heated windscreen is manufactured from:",
    "feedback": "a glass and polycarbonate laminate."
  },
  {
    "question": "Fuel for gas turbine engines is usually heated in order to:",
    "feedback": "prevent icing-up of the LP filter"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of the Generator Breaker is to close when the voltage of the :",
    "feedback": "generator is greater than battery voltage and to open when the opposite is true"
  },
  {
    "question": "The number in the graph that shows the steering actuator is:",
    "feedback": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about a gust lock system are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) There should be suitable design precautions to prevent flight with the gust lock engaged\n2) There is no need for a gust lock on reversible flight controls",
    "feedback": "1) is correct 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "The fuel is atomized:",
    "feedback": "in the combustion zone."
  },
  {
    "question": "On a normally aspirated aero-engine fitted with a fixed pitch propeller :",
    "feedback": "manifold pressure decreases as the aircraft climbs at a fixed throttle setting."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the possible causes of a hot start, and what are the indications for a hot start?\nA hot start may be caused by.....",
    "feedback": "an eary starter cut-out, fuel mis-scheduling, or strong tailwinds. The engine may spend a considerable time at very low RPM (sub-idle), but should continue to accelerate, the turbine temperatures may appear high or exceed the limitations"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is increased?\n\n1) The propeller blade angle increases\n2) The free power turbine speed remains constant",
    "feedback": "1) is correct,2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Whilst stationary on the ground in a hangar the most important loads on a cantilever wing are:",
    "feedback": "tension in the upper surface, compression in the lower surface"
  },
  {
    "question": "Describe the operating principle of the advisory ice detection system:",
    "feedback": "The flight crew activates the ice protection systems manually, based on limitations stated in the AFM"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the correct sequence during the start of a turbine engine on the ground?",
    "feedback": "Starter, rotation, ignition, fuel"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about rudder pedal nose wheel steering of a jet transport areoplane is correct?",
    "feedback": "When performing a rudder check during taxiing, an additional pilot action is necessary to avoid deflection of the nose wheel"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a blown fuse is replaced with one of a higher ampere rating.....",
    "feedback": "the entire circuit will overheat, with the potential for an electrical fire"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of an ignition switch is to :",
    "feedback": "control the primary circuit of the magneto"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot can actuate the feathering system by:",
    "feedback": "pulling the propeller control lever rearwards"
  },
  {
    "question": "The indications of a failure of the capacitive fuel indication system will be:",
    "feedback": "a full deflection of the gauge to empty"
  },
  {
    "question": "A CSD unit is normally provided with means of monitoring during flight the:",
    "feedback": "oil temperature and pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "The turbine in the air conditioning machine:",
    "feedback": "drives the compressor and creates a temperature drop in the conditioned air."
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the advantages of a turbocharger over a supercharger is that:",
    "feedback": "it uses the exhaust gases energy which normally would be lost"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is located in the box between DC ESS BUS and AC ESS BUS (marked with the red number 1)?",
    "feedback": "Static Inverter"
  },
  {
    "question": "The most favourable conditions to apply the flexible take-off procedure are:\n\n1) high take-off mass\n2) low take-off mass\n3) high outside temperature\n4) low outside temperature\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The high pressure fuel pumps are driven by:",
    "feedback": "the engine."
  },
  {
    "question": "The viscosity of a liquid is a measure of its",
    "feedback": "resistance to flow."
  },
  {
    "question": "The failure of an anti-skid system:",
    "feedback": "at least doubles the minimum braking distance on a dry runway"
  },
  {
    "question": "Longitudinal stability involves the motion of the aircraft about its:",
    "feedback": "Lateral axis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.  In case of failure of the TRU 1: (NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumend to remain open)",
    "feedback": "DC BUS 1 can be fed by TRU 2 via DC BUS 2 and DC BAT BUS if C5.3, C7.4 and C7.1 are closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "On most transport aircraft, flight deck windows are protected against icing by:",
    "feedback": "electric heating"
  },
  {
    "question": "In flight, with centre tank empty and APU operating, a fuel unbalance is detected (quantity in tank 1 is less than quantity in tank 2). Re-balancing of the two tanks is:",
    "feedback": "possible with \"crossfeed\" open and tank 1 pumps \"off\" and tank 2 pumps \"on\"."
  },
  {
    "question": "In transport aircraft equipped with retractable landing gear, an aural alert must be given to the pilot:",
    "feedback": "whenever a landing is attempted and any gear is not locked down"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an impulse turbine are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The pressure remains constant across the nozzle guide vanes\n2) The pressure remains constant across the rotor blades",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a ditching situation, the passenger life jackets will be inflated :",
    "feedback": "when the passenger has left the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "On an aircraft utilising AC as primary power supplies, the batteries are charged in flight from :",
    "feedback": "a Transformer Rectifier Unit."
  },
  {
    "question": "The oxygen masks have dropped down from the passengers service units. The oxygen flow starts :",
    "feedback": "after pulling the oxygen mask downwards"
  },
  {
    "question": "To enable proper functioning of a piston engine during throttle advance a carburettor is fitted with:",
    "feedback": "an accelerator pump"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type(s) of hydraulic fluids are commonly used in civil aviation?",
    "feedback": "synthetic and mineral"
  },
  {
    "question": "The de-humidifier (water separator) is fitted:",
    "feedback": "after the cooling system, and operates on a condensation principle."
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the fuel schematic of the two-engine aircraft. Where on the diagram is a booster pump located?",
    "feedback": "Position 1"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a variable bypass valve, fitted between the LP and HP compressor of an axial flow compressor, is to:",
    "feedback": "prevent stall in the LP compressor"
  },
  {
    "question": "The following areas are most prone to experiencing stress and should be given particular attention during a preflight inspection:\n1) Wing spar and skin near the root of the wing2) Wing spar and skin near the tip of the wing3) Fuselage skin near the bulkhead4) Aircraft skin on the bottom and top of the fuselage5) Fuselage around the windows6) Engine nacelles",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.\n\nOn ground, APU GEN can be used to feed both AC BUS 1 and AC BUS 2, when:\n(NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumend to remain open)",
    "feedback": "C1.3, C2.1 and C2.2 are closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "During cruising flight, when the throttle is slightly pulled back on an aeroplane equipped with a constant speed propeller, the propeller pitch automatically:",
    "feedback": "decreases and the RPM remains the same"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the cabin pressure tends to decrease below ambient:",
    "feedback": "the inward relief valve will open."
  },
  {
    "question": "The gas turbine compressor is driven by:",
    "feedback": "the turbine which is connected to a common shaft."
  },
  {
    "question": "As regards three-phase AC generators, the following conditions must be met for paralleling AC generators:\n\n1. Equal voltage\n2. Equal current\n3. Equal frequencies\n4. Same phase rotation\n5. Voltages of same phase\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "A public transport jet aeroplane may be operated up to FL 450. The cabin includes 180 passenger seats, made up of 30 rows (3 seats from each side of central aisle). The minimum number of cabin oxygen masks for this aeroplane must be:",
    "feedback": "198 (110% of the seating capacity)."
  },
  {
    "question": "About a twin spool compressor:",
    "feedback": "the low pressure spool runs at a lower RPM than the high pressure spool"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some aircraft are fitted with two gearboxes for each engine; usually the second gearbox is.....",
    "feedback": "low speed, connected to the LP shaft"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can FADEC systems on piston engines usually achieve a level of redundancy?",
    "feedback": "Each engine is fitted with two FADEC computers"
  },
  {
    "question": "The number in the graph that shows the retraction actuator is:",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Assuming the jet pipe is not choked, the equation to calculate jet engine thrust T (with mass flow m, airspeed Vv and jet velocity Vj) is:",
    "feedback": "T=m(Vj-Vv)"
  },
  {
    "question": "As air passes through the impeller of a centrifugal compressor the velocity:",
    "feedback": "increases."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a hydraulic braking system, an accumulator is precharged to 1200 psi.\nAn electrically driven hydraulic pump is started and provides a system pressure of 3000 psi. \nThe hydraulic pressure gauge which is connected to the gas section of the accumulator, reads:",
    "feedback": "3000 psi"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning the starting procedure of a gas turbine engine:",
    "feedback": "If the air starter is seized, the engine can only be relighted by windmilling"
  },
  {
    "question": "A reverse thrust door warning light on the flight deck instrument panel illuminates when:",
    "feedback": "the reverser doors are unlocked."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is decreased?\n\n1) The gas generator speed increases\n2) The EGT decreases",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "When quick donning masks are in use, the pilot is:",
    "feedback": "able to radiotelephone."
  },
  {
    "question": "On what principle does the fuel contents gauging system work on a modern large aircraft?",
    "feedback": "Changes in dielectric causes changes in capacitance."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are flaperons?",
    "feedback": "Combined ailerons and flaps."
  },
  {
    "question": "When a persistent top excitation limit fault on an AC generator connected to the mains with another AC generator, the overexcitation protection device opens:",
    "feedback": "the exciter breaker and the generator breaker."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of fuel tank vents?",
    "feedback": "To prevent a vacuum forming in the tanks in flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "If during pressurized flight the outflow valve closes fully due to a fault in the pressure controller, the:",
    "feedback": "safety valve opens when the differential pressure reaches structural maximum differential."
  },
  {
    "question": "Electrically powered ice protection devices on aircraft are:",
    "feedback": "used as anti-icing devices for pitot tubes, static ports and windshields"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a propeller reduction gear is ......",
    "feedback": "to keep the propeller rotation speed within a range which maintains good performance"
  },
  {
    "question": "A cabin pressurisation system is often installed on board turbine powered aircraft. If installed, it normally has",
    "feedback": "Two modes of operation."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a cabin air conditioning system with an air cycle machine (bootstrap), the mass air flow is routed via the:",
    "feedback": "secondary heat exchanger outlet to the turbine inlet"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an electrically operated gas turbine start system, the electric motor:",
    "feedback": "is automatically switched off after a specified period of time or the engine is at sustaining rpm."
  },
  {
    "question": "To remove the moisture content in compressed air, the following device is used:",
    "feedback": "A separator."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following parameters remain constant in a divergent (subsonic) gas turbine engine intake?",
    "feedback": "Total temperature"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is reducing the shocks on the landing gear in an oleo shock absorber?",
    "feedback": "Cushion of compressed air."
  },
  {
    "question": "Assuming cabin differential pressure has attained the required value in normal flight conditions, if flight altitude is maintained:",
    "feedback": "there will be a constant air mass flow through the cabin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about compressor stall are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) A compressor stall is most likely to occur in a compressor designed for a high pressure ratio operating at low RPM\n2) A compressor stall is most likely to occur when the air flow stagnates in the rear stages of the compressor",
    "feedback": "1) is correct,2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The reason for fitting thermal plugs to aircraft wheels is that they :",
    "feedback": "release air from the tyre in case of overheating."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an auto-brake system are correct or incorrect?\n1) Proper functioning of an auto-brake system requires proper functioning of the anti-skid system\n2) In the RTO mode a maximum constant deceleration is applied",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "In order that DC generators will achieve equal load sharing when operating in parallel, it is necessary to ensure that :",
    "feedback": "their voltages are almost equal."
  },
  {
    "question": "For piston engines, mixture ratio is the ratio between the :",
    "feedback": "mass of fuel and mass of air entering the cylinder."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why, in the bootstrap system, is the air compressed before it enters the heat exchanger?",
    "feedback": "To ensure maximum pressure and temperature drop across the turbine."
  },
  {
    "question": "Max. Exhaust Gas Temperature is theoretically associated with :",
    "feedback": "Mass ratio of 1/15."
  },
  {
    "question": "One advantage in the design of integral fuel tanks over other types of fuel tanks is that they ....",
    "feedback": "provide the highest volume of fuel storage space"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given a conventional transport aeroplane with irreversible flight controls on the ground with engines running. Which of these statements about rudder trim actuation is correct?",
    "feedback": "The rudder moves, the rudder pedals move in the corresponding direction"
  },
  {
    "question": "The elevators of a conventional airliner are used to provide rotation about the:",
    "feedback": "Lateral axis"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a gas turbine engine the creep phenomenon is the most severe in the:",
    "feedback": "turbine rotors"
  },
  {
    "question": "On an aircraft provided with resistance and capacitance variation type fire detection loops, a fire alarm is initiated by a temperature increase detected:",
    "feedback": "at any isolated point of the loops or else generally on all the loops"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a gas turbine engine, the Inlet Guide Vanes (IGV).....",
    "feedback": "direct the airflow at the optimal angle to the compressor's first stage"
  },
  {
    "question": "The turbine in a gas turbine engine generates shaft power using:",
    "feedback": "expansion of hot gas followed by conversion of kinetic energy (velocity) into (mechanical) work"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider a variable pitch propeller operating in a low RPM/high pitch condition. When feather is selected, the ....",
    "feedback": "condition lever (pitch control) is moved to the feather position and the blades move from high pitch directly to the feather position"
  },
  {
    "question": "Fuel tanks are fitted with baffles:",
    "feedback": "to damp spanwise fuel motion in the tanks"
  },
  {
    "question": "In flight, engine cowlings are fireproofed by:",
    "feedback": "the airflow."
  },
  {
    "question": "If a twin spool gas turbine engine is controlled by a conventional N2 control system, rupture of the LP shaft may result in:",
    "feedback": "overspeed of the LP turbine"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct?\n\n1) The freezing point for Jet A is at about the same temperature than that for Jet B\n2) The flash point for Jet A is at a higher temperature than that for Jet B",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The frequency of an AC generator is dependent upon the :",
    "feedback": "number of pairs of poles and the speed of the rotor."
  },
  {
    "question": "The development of a faulty attachment/bonding can be detected during the pre-flight inspection by looking for missing ....",
    "feedback": "rivets, bolts, and/or screws"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these signals are inputs, at least, in the stall warning computers?",
    "feedback": "Angle of attack and flaps and slats deflection."
  },
  {
    "question": "A modern aeroplane is equipped with warning lights in the cockpit to monitor the hydraulic system. What does the illumination of the hydraulic oil temperature light indicate?",
    "feedback": "Overheated hydraulic fluid in one of the pump return lines."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is decreased?\n\n1) The gas generator speed decreases\n2) The EGT increases",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "The auto-brake system is switched off during or after landing by:",
    "feedback": "positioning the auto-brake selector to DISARM or OFF"
  },
  {
    "question": "When two DC generators are operating in parallel, control of load sharing is achieved by :",
    "feedback": "an equalising circuit which, in conjunction  with the voltage regulators, varies the field excitation current of the generators."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why are additives added to Jet A fuel?",
    "feedback": "To prevent the fuel from forming any ice within"
  },
  {
    "question": "Assuming cabin differential pressure has attained the required value in normal flight conditions, if flight altitude is maintained :",
    "feedback": "a constant mass air flow is permitted through the cabin."
  },
  {
    "question": "When selected to normal, the oxygen/air ratio of the mixture supplied by the cockpit oxygen system regulator:",
    "feedback": "increases when the altitude increases"
  },
  {
    "question": "For FAIL-SAFE designed structural parts :\n\n1 The mounting principle is parallel mounting.\n2 No routine check is necessary.\n3 The member is removed at the end of the calculated life cycle.\n4 Certain components may not be accessible.\n5 The principle is the redundancy of components\n6 The failure of a member causes the loads to be shared between the other system components.\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1,5,6"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the air cycle system the air is cooled down by expansion:",
    "feedback": "in the turbine."
  },
  {
    "question": "On A/C with a fuel pressure gauge, where is the pressure normally measured?\n(Aircraft with fuel injection)",
    "feedback": "Inlet of the fuel injection metering unit."
  },
  {
    "question": "In an aircraft fitted with a constant frequency AC power supply, DC power is obtained from a:",
    "feedback": "transformer rectifier unit (TRU)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The characteristics of a centrifugal compressor (compared to an axial compressor) are:\n\n1) a higher pressure ratio per single stage\n2) a large diameter for a given mass flow\n3) a lower pressure ratio per single stage\n4) a small diameter for a given mass flow\n\nThe combination containing all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The cross-feed fuel system can be used to:\n\n1) feed any engine from any fuel tank\n2) dump the unusable fuel\n3) adjust fuel distribution\n4) transfer fuel from one tank to another located in the same wing\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "A sandwich structural part:",
    "feedback": "consists of two thin sheets separated by a light core material"
  },
  {
    "question": "Creep in a jet engine is most pronounced:\n\n1)  in the high pressure turbine vanes\n2)  in the high pressure turbine blades\n3)  in the secondary zone combustion chamber\n4)  in the free power turbine rotors\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "On most transport jet aircraft, the low pressure pumps of the fuel system are supplied with electric power of the following type:",
    "feedback": "115 V AC"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the proximity of the emergency evacuation path marking system is to :",
    "feedback": "replace the overhead emergency lighting during an emergency evacuation with a thick smoke."
  },
  {
    "question": "The advantages of a DC generator tachometer are:\n\n1) easy transmission of the information\n2) independence of the information relative to the electrical power supply\n3) freedom from any spurious current due to the commutator\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Connecting two 12 volt 40 ampere-hour capacity batteries in series will result in a total voltage and capacity respectively of :",
    "feedback": "24 volts, 40 ampere-hours."
  },
  {
    "question": "The gas turbine illustrated is of the following type:",
    "feedback": "double shaft turbine and centrifugal compressor"
  },
  {
    "question": "A piston engine may use a fuel of a different grade than the recommended:",
    "feedback": "provided that the grade is higher"
  },
  {
    "question": "A public transport aircraft is operated at FL 390. The total number of oxygen dispensing units and outlets in the cabin must be at least the same as the total number of :",
    "feedback": "seats exceeded by 10%."
  },
  {
    "question": "The type of brake unit found on most transport aeroplanes is a:",
    "feedback": "Multiple disk brake."
  },
  {
    "question": "An engine fire in a large transport aeroplane is indicated by a(n):",
    "feedback": "visual warning and an aural alert"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a trim tab (device) is to:",
    "feedback": "reduce or to cancel control forces."
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of an accumulator in a hydraulic system is:",
    "feedback": "to damp the fluid pressure variations"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of the swirl vanes on the fuel nozzles in the combustion chamber is:\n\n1)  to produce a backflow to control the flame\n2)  to mix air and fuel for the combustion\n3)  to increase the fuel flow at the nozzle\n4)  to provide proper atomization of the fuel together with the associated nozzle\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the following truth table represent?",
    "feedback": "A NAND gate"
  },
  {
    "question": "A bus-bar is :",
    "feedback": "a distribution point for electrical power."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct about the flow in a divergent jet engine inlet?\n\n1) The static pressure remains constant in flow direction\n2) The total temperature remains constant in flow direction",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Chemical oxygen generators are used to furnish oxygen to the:\n1) Cockpit\n2) Cabin\n3) Toilets\n4) Smoke hood\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is increased?\n\n1) The gas generator speed decreases\n2) The EGT remains constant",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "To start a turbine engine:\n1) The compressor must be rotated to get air into the combustion chamber2) The compressor must be rotated to cool the turbine blades3) Fuel must be provided in the combustion chamber(s)4) Ignition must be provided to start the fuel/air mixture burning5) The turbine blades must be rotated to extract the exhaust gases from the combustion chamber6) The turbine blades must be rotated by an APU to drive the accessories\nThe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the functions of an accumulator in a hydraulic system is:",
    "feedback": "to damp pressure surges in the system."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a hydraulic braking system, the accumulator is:",
    "feedback": "an accumulator designed to restore brake energy in the event of a hydraulic failure."
  },
  {
    "question": "In an engine fitted with an afterburner, relative to an identical engine without an afterburner, under normal operation without reheat it will produce:",
    "feedback": "less power."
  },
  {
    "question": "An inverter converts ....... to ......",
    "feedback": "28V DC, 115V AC"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a gas turbine engine accelerates from idle to take-off thrust and the compressor RPM is too high in comparison with the air inlet velocity, this may result in:",
    "feedback": "a compressor stall"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pneumatic mechanical ice protection systems are mainly used for:",
    "feedback": "Wings."
  },
  {
    "question": "The type of a aircraft oxygen system intended for use by passengers, is mostly:",
    "feedback": "a continuous flow system"
  },
  {
    "question": "The power required for field excitation of the main rotor in modern constant-frequency alternators is directly controlled by:",
    "feedback": "the voltage regulator"
  },
  {
    "question": "Modern jet aircraft: What are the fuel tank types and their location?",
    "feedback": "Integral tanks in the wings and in the fuselage."
  },
  {
    "question": "If one side has taken \"priority\" on a sidestick controller, how is the other pilot alerted to the fact?",
    "feedback": "Audio alert \"priority left/right\" and a red arrow on the sidestick priority light"
  },
  {
    "question": "A turbine engine with a dual channel FADEC has a single channel fault. Which of these actions should the crew take?",
    "feedback": "Continue the flight, since the healthy channel automatically assumes full engine control"
  },
  {
    "question": "When TRU 1 has failed, DC BUS 1:",
    "feedback": "Can be fed via GEN 2, AC BUS 2, TRU 2, DC BUS 2, and X-TIE"
  },
  {
    "question": "In inflammable gaseous materials, like propan for example, are set on fire; the following extinguisher types should be used for fire fighting:",
    "feedback": "BCF and CO2 type extinguishers"
  },
  {
    "question": "The hydraulic system of a transport aircraft is designed to produce:",
    "feedback": "high pressure and large flow."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a clamshell door type thrust reversal system, when reverse is selected, the exhaust gases are:",
    "feedback": "discharged at approximately 45 degrees."
  },
  {
    "question": "Synthetic hydraulic fluids:",
    "feedback": "are irritating to eyes and skin."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of inboard ailerons?",
    "feedback": "To reduce wing twist at high speed."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a large transport aeroplane the main temperature reduction of the conditioned air is achieved in:",
    "feedback": "the heat exchangers"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the volume of air passing through a carburetor venturi is reduced, the pressure at the venturi throat will",
    "feedback": "increase."
  },
  {
    "question": "The survival oxygen is:",
    "feedback": "the oxygen supplied to the airplane occupants in case of accidental depressurization."
  },
  {
    "question": "A flat rated turbofan will be temperature limited if:",
    "feedback": "OAT is higher than flat rated temperature"
  },
  {
    "question": "In addition to fire detention/protection, most auxiliary power units (APUs) have automatic controls for starting, stopping and maintaining operation within safe limits. These controls provide correct sequencing of the starting cycle as well as protection against :",
    "feedback": "high turbine gas temperature (TGT),  overspeed, loss of oil pressure and high oil  temperature."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an auto-brake system are correct or incorrect?\n1) During landing and rejected take-off auto-brakes stop operating and disarm below a certain low speed\n2) During landing auto-brakes keep operating when idle reverse thrust is selected",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements regarding cockpit windows are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) On some aeroplanes the cockpit windows have an additional speed restriction, related to bird impact, when window heating is inoperative\n2) Cockpit side windows are always provided with a de-icing system",
    "feedback": "1) is correct 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "The part of the flight that will cause the highest loads on the torsion link in a bogie gear is",
    "feedback": "Taxiing with a small turning radius."
  },
  {
    "question": "The approach flight idle value (RPM) is higher than the ground idle value ......",
    "feedback": "to allow the engines to more rapidly accelerate to full power, in case of a go-around"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a ditching control is to:",
    "feedback": "close the outflow valve(s)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Air release valves, or bleed valves:",
    "feedback": "reduce mass flow."
  },
  {
    "question": "As the gas flow passes through the turbine assembly the velocity of the gas flow will in basics:",
    "feedback": "initially fall and then rise in the jet pipe."
  },
  {
    "question": "How many megaphones are required in an airplane with a maximum approved passenger seating configuration of 165 seats and only 5 passengers on board?",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The engine component between station numbers 5 and 6 is the:",
    "feedback": "HP turbine"
  },
  {
    "question": "The empennage consists of the:",
    "feedback": "horizontal and vertical stabilizer"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a fire detection system with single-loop continuous components (with no fault protection), if the line is accidently grounded:",
    "feedback": "the fire alarm is triggered."
  },
  {
    "question": "When part of a continuous loop fire detection system is heated:\n\n1) its resistance decreases\n2) its resistance increases\n3) the current increases\n4) the current decreases\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the following truth table represent?",
    "feedback": "NOR"
  },
  {
    "question": "When an engine fire is detected, this is presented to the flight crew as ......",
    "feedback": "a bell, red warning, and red light"
  },
  {
    "question": "The rudder limiters on several aircraft have a specific function, which is to:",
    "feedback": "Prevent excessive loads from acting on the rudder."
  },
  {
    "question": "A hydraulic low pressure alert is the first indication of:",
    "feedback": "the pump output pressure is insufficient."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a long-range transport jet, where are smoke detectors located?\n1) Engines2) APU3) Cargo holds4) Toilets5) Avionics bay6) Crew rest area",
    "feedback": "3, 4, 5, 6"
  },
  {
    "question": "The disk brakes have more or less replaced the drum brakes. Why?",
    "feedback": "Owing to a loss of braking action due to heat generation problem."
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of a fusible plug is to",
    "feedback": "protect the tyre against explosion due to excessive temperature."
  },
  {
    "question": "Turbine blade “creeping“ may be reduced by:",
    "feedback": "material and air cooling."
  },
  {
    "question": "The station numbers before and after the LP compressor are:",
    "feedback": "2.5 and 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an auto-brake system are correct or incorrect?\n1) During landing and rejected take-off auto-brakes keep operating until the pilot presses the brake pedals\n2) During landing auto-brakes stop operating and disarm when reverse thrust is selected",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.\n\nWhen all AC generators are lost in flight and the EMER GEN is not available, the AC ESS BUS can be fed by the batteries, when:\n(NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumend to remain open)",
    "feedback": "C6.1 and C6.2 are closed and the bus is switched to the static inverter"
  },
  {
    "question": "Intermediate bleed valves are fitted:",
    "feedback": "at an intermediate stage within the compressor."
  },
  {
    "question": "To maintain a constant mixture at low and high power settings in a piston engine, a carburettor is fitted with:",
    "feedback": "a diffuser (compensating jet)"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the three elements of the fuselage structure of a large transport aeroplane?",
    "feedback": "skin, frames, stringers"
  },
  {
    "question": "A multi-engine aircraft with clockwise rotating propellers suffers an engine failure after takeoff. Considering the aircraft maintains a zero bank and no power changes, which situation would lead to the largest rudder deflection?",
    "feedback": "Left crosswind, left engine failure"
  },
  {
    "question": "A thermal circuit breaker:",
    "feedback": "protects the system in the event of overheating, even without exceeding the maximum permissible current."
  },
  {
    "question": "An artificial feel system:",
    "feedback": "functions in parallel with an irreversible hydraulic actuator"
  },
  {
    "question": "The primary function of the diffuser, located between the compressor and the combustion chamber, of a gas turbine is to:",
    "feedback": "decrease the flow velocity"
  },
  {
    "question": "The station numbers before and after the intake are:",
    "feedback": "1 and 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The crankshaft of a piston engine rotates at:",
    "feedback": "twice the speed of the camshaft"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the basic functionalities of a smoke hood?",
    "feedback": "Th provide breathable gas and protect the user's eyes, nose, and mouth from toxic fumes and smoke"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of an accumulator in a hydraulic system are to ....",
    "feedback": "damp pressure fluctuations and serve as a limited alternate source of pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "When powering up a hydraulic system, the level in the reservoir will:",
    "feedback": "decrease slightly."
  },
  {
    "question": "The resistors R1 and R2 are connected in parallel. The value of the equivalent resistance (Req) so obtained is given by the following formula:",
    "feedback": "1/Req = 1/R1 + 1/R2"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the door operation of a modern transport aircraft equipped with evacuation slides is controlled from the outside, the slide:",
    "feedback": "is disarmed automatically."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are Krueger flaps?",
    "feedback": "Leading edge flaps"
  },
  {
    "question": "The power source for hot air in de-ice / anti ice systems on jet A/C is :",
    "feedback": "Bleed air from the engines' compressor."
  },
  {
    "question": "The power output of a normally aspirated piston engine increases with increasing altitude at constant Manifold Air Pressure (MAP) and RPM because of the :",
    "feedback": "lower back pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "Spark plug fouling is more likely to happen if :",
    "feedback": "the aeroplane climbs without mixture adjustment."
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning a constant speed propeller of a twin engine aeroplane controlled by a single-acting pitch control unit:",
    "feedback": "oil pressure turns the propeller blades towards a smaller pitch angle"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the maximum operating altitude of an airplane is limited by the pressurized cabin, this limitation is due to the maximum:",
    "feedback": "Positive cabin differential pressure at maximum cabin altitude."
  },
  {
    "question": "The bypass air in a bypass type gas turbine engine has the effect of a lower specific fuel consumption by causing an overall:",
    "feedback": "decrease in exhaust gas flow average velocity and higher propulsive efficiency."
  },
  {
    "question": "In twin-engine aeroplanes with right turning propellers",
    "feedback": "the left engine is the critical motor."
  },
  {
    "question": "On some engine types, resonance may be reduced, during starting by:",
    "feedback": "partially closing the high pressure cock."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is artificial feel required and how is the degree of feel set?",
    "feedback": "Fitted to prevent overstressing of the aircraft and gives increased forces as the speed increases."
  },
  {
    "question": "Low oil pressure is sometimes the result of a",
    "feedback": "worn oil pump"
  },
  {
    "question": "The support struts of the cone in an exhaust system:",
    "feedback": "are sometimes used to straighten out the exhaust gases."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about a reaction turbine are correct or incorrect?  1) The pressure drops across the nozzle guide vanes 2) The pressure rises across the rotor blades",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "A servo tab moves?",
    "feedback": "Opposite of the control surface to which it is hinged."
  },
  {
    "question": "The connection in parallel of two 12 volt/ 40 amphours batteries, will create a unit with the following characteristics;",
    "feedback": "12 volt / 80 amp hours"
  },
  {
    "question": "During take-off, the angle of attack of the blades of a fixed pitch propeller, optimised for cruise condition is:",
    "feedback": "relatively high"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an engine equipped with a float-type carburettor, the low temperature that causes carburettor ice is normally the result of:",
    "feedback": "vaporization of fuel and expansion of the air in the carburettor"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the figures shows a buckling load?",
    "feedback": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeroplane equipped with irreversible flight controls:",
    "feedback": "need not to be equipped with a separate gust lock system"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the diagram (not to scale), the balancing force required on the right hand side is:",
    "feedback": "100 N"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider a conventional multi-engined turboprop aircraft. During go-around the critical engine fails, but the propeller does not feather automatically. Which of the following cases will result in the highest stress on the aircraft rudder when the IAS is slightly above VMCA?",
    "feedback": "Aft CG, skid towards the critical engine"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hydraulic fluids :",
    "feedback": "are irritating to eyes and skin."
  },
  {
    "question": "A single acting actuator:",
    "feedback": "is powered in one direction only by hydraulic power, the return movement being under spring force."
  },
  {
    "question": "Increasing the power setting of a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine causes:",
    "feedback": "both HP spool speed and EGT to increase"
  },
  {
    "question": "One design method to avoid control surface flutter is:",
    "feedback": "ensuring correct mass distribution within the control surface"
  },
  {
    "question": "Apart from flight into known icing conditions, the intake system of a diesel engine:",
    "feedback": "is never heated because a diesel engine is a injection engine"
  },
  {
    "question": "The installation and use of on-board oxygen generators is such that:\n\n1 - the smoking ban is imperative when used\n2 - in case of accidental drop of the \"continuous flow\" passenger masks, no crew action is required\n3 - no trace of grease must be found in the system assembly\n4 - the system's filling adaptors must be greased with non freezable or graphite grease\n\nThe combination which regroups all of the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1 - 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "A hot rod ice detector ......",
    "feedback": "accumulates ice and is visible from the cockpit"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.  In case of failure of the TRU 2: (NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumend to remain open)",
    "feedback": "DC BUS 2 can be fed by TRU 1 via DC BUS 1 and DC BAT BUS if C5.1, C7.1 and C7.4 are closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is decreased?\n\n1) The propeller blade angle decreases\n2) The free power turbine speed increases",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Should a hydraulic pump seize during operation:",
    "feedback": "the quill drive will shear to offload and protect the gearbox."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about chemical oxygen generators are correct or incorrect?\n1) Chemical oxygen generators are often used to supply passenger oxygen\n2) The oxygen supply of chemical oxygen generators, once activated, can be switched off",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Halon is used as a fire extinguishing agent because it:",
    "feedback": "acts as a very effective flame inhibitor"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the attached diagram, which image represents compression?",
    "feedback": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "To improve visibility during heavy rain, rain repellent fluid is used in conjunction with ....",
    "feedback": "windscreen wipers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning the fuel system high-pressure shut-off valve (HPSOV) of a gas turbine:",
    "feedback": "ignition is activated before fuel is delivered by the HPSOV to the fuel nozzles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements concerning a sandwich structural part are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The main function of the core material is sound insulation\n2) A sandwich structural part is well suited for absorbing concentrated loads",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a jettison valve used for?",
    "feedback": "To reduce aircraft weight to MLW"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gas turbine engine main bearing oil seals are normally:",
    "feedback": "of the air controlled type."
  },
  {
    "question": "With engine fire alarm activated, the extinguisher discharge:",
    "feedback": "is the pilot's task"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a four-stroke piston engine, the only \"driving\" stroke is :",
    "feedback": "firing-expansion"
  },
  {
    "question": "For most large aeroplanes, spoilers are :",
    "feedback": "upper wing surface devices and their deflection is symmetrical or asymmetrical."
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.\n\nGEN 2 can be used to feed the DC BUS 2, when:\n(NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumend to remain open)",
    "feedback": "C1.4 and C5.3 are closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a normal pressurised climb after take-off:",
    "feedback": "cabin pressure decreases more slowly than atmospheric pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the diagram, the component 2 is a:",
    "feedback": "TRU"
  },
  {
    "question": "The auto-brake system is disconnected during landing:",
    "feedback": "by pilot action"
  },
  {
    "question": "Bleeding air from the HP compressor of a turbofan, whilst maintaining thrust, increases:",
    "feedback": "EGT and fuel flow"
  },
  {
    "question": "A turbo compressor air conditioning system (bootstrap system) will:",
    "feedback": "cause a pressure drop as well as an associated temperature drop in the charge air."
  },
  {
    "question": "In flight, windshield icing occurs, within the view line of both pilots, what adjustments should the flight crew do?",
    "feedback": "Both flight crew members should adjust to see properly"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is true about \"plug type\" aircraft doors?",
    "feedback": "Each door can move inside and outside the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "When relighting the engine due to a flame-out:",
    "feedback": "the full start sequence may be by-passed and use of the relight button is made."
  },
  {
    "question": "Because of the input/output relationship of an AND gate, it is often referred to as the :",
    "feedback": "\"all or nothing\" gate."
  },
  {
    "question": "On most transport aircraft, the low pressure fuel pumps of the fuel system are:",
    "feedback": "electrically driven centrifugal pumps"
  },
  {
    "question": "The definition of electric current is:",
    "feedback": "The flow of electric charge per time unit. It is measured in Amperes (A)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements regarding cockpit windows are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) On some aeroplanes the cockpit windows never have an additional speed restriction, related to bird impact, when window heating is inoperative\n2) Cockpit side windows are always provided with a de-icing system",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hydraulic pressure can be described as:",
    "feedback": "force ./. area"
  },
  {
    "question": "A reverse thrust alert on the flight deck occurs when:\n\n1) the reverser doors are unlocked with the reverse lever in the stowed position\n2) the reverser doors are locked with the reverse lever in the stowed position\n3) the reverser doors remain stowed with the reverse lever in the deployed position\n4) the reverser doors have moved to the reverse thrust position with the reverse lever in the deployed position\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Aircraft toilets must be fitted with fire extinguishing and smoke-detection systems if the seating capacity is more than:",
    "feedback": "20"
  },
  {
    "question": "DURALUMIN alloys :\n\n1 have an aluminium-copper base.\n2 have an aluminium-magnesium base.\n3 are easy to weld.\n4 are difficult to weld.\n5 have a good thermal conductivity.\n6 have a poor air corrosion resistance\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1,4,5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.\n\nGEN 2 can be used to feed the DC BAT BUS:\n(NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumend to remain open)",
    "feedback": "via AC BUS 2 and DC BUS 2, when C1.4, C5.3 and C7.4 are closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "The crash/fire axe is part of the safety equipment fitted to passenger aircraft. Its function is to :",
    "feedback": "obtain forced access to a fire behind a panel and a general purpose tool during evacuation."
  },
  {
    "question": "The bypass ratio:\n\n1) is the ratio of inlet air mass flow to HP compressor mass flow\n2) can be determined from the inlet air volume flow and the HP compressor volume flow",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "When TAS increases, the blade angle of a constant speed propeller will (RPM and throttle levers are not moved):",
    "feedback": "increase"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of a hydraulic selector valve is to:",
    "feedback": "direct system pressure to either side of the piston of an actuator"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the attached diagram, the type of stress acting on the point indicated by the image number 1 is the:",
    "feedback": "tension"
  },
  {
    "question": "A general visual indicator of corrosion that a pilot could detect during a pre-flight inspection ....",
    "feedback": "is white spots on bare aluminium surfaces"
  },
  {
    "question": "A shuttle valve will:",
    "feedback": "automatically switch to a more appropriate source of hydraulic supply."
  },
  {
    "question": "Charging of a lead acid battery cell is a done by connecting a slightly higher voltage to the cell. The reverse current flow during charging will increase the specific gravity (SG) and ....",
    "feedback": "returns the cell voltage to just above 2 volts and removes the lead sulphate"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the cabin altitude rises (aircraft in level flight), the differential pressure:",
    "feedback": "decreases"
  },
  {
    "question": "Compared to a tyre fitted with an inner tube, a tubeless tyre presents the following characteristics :\n\n1 - high heating\n2 - valve fragility\n3 - lower risk of bursting\n4 - better adjustment to wheels\n\nThe combination containing all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3 - 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The angle-of-attack of a rotating propeller blade is measured between\nthe blade chord or face and which of the following?",
    "feedback": "The relative airstream."
  },
  {
    "question": "The current in a DC circuit, according to Ohm's law, can be described as:",
    "feedback": "Inversely proportional to the resistance and proportional to the voltage."
  },
  {
    "question": "The pressurisation load on the skin of a fuselage is:",
    "feedback": "tension"
  },
  {
    "question": "The modern anti-skid processes are based on the use of a computer whose input data is:\n\n1. idle wheel speed (measured)\n2. braked wheel speed (measured)\n3. brake temperature (measured)\n4. desired idle wheel train slipping rate\n5. tire pressure\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4."
  },
  {
    "question": "The shear neck is a device fitted to prevent.....",
    "feedback": "engine failure, in case of mechanical failure of the gearbox"
  },
  {
    "question": "A gas turbine engine is run at ground idle for a period of time prior to shutdown to:",
    "feedback": "prevent seizure of the rotor blades in their seats"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is increased?\n\n1) The HP spool speed increases\n2) The EGT remains constant",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding Ohm's law:",
    "feedback": "the current in a circuit is directly proportional to the voltage"
  },
  {
    "question": "The principle of damage tolerance in structural design of an aircraft is based on the:",
    "feedback": "capability to withstand a certain amount of weakening of the structure without catastrophic failure"
  },
  {
    "question": "The lubricating system of an air cooled piston engine is used to:",
    "feedback": "reduce internal friction and provide cooling"
  },
  {
    "question": "Specific fuel consumption for a turbo-prop engine can be expressed in kg per:",
    "feedback": "hour per unit of shaft power"
  },
  {
    "question": "The fuselage of an aircraft consists, among others, of stringers whose purpose is to:",
    "feedback": "assist the skin in absorbing the longitudinal traction-compression stresses."
  },
  {
    "question": "Compressor stall is due to:",
    "feedback": "an excessively high angle of attack of the rotor blades"
  },
  {
    "question": "In most cases aeroplane piston engines are short stroke engines. This permits a :",
    "feedback": "lighter construction."
  },
  {
    "question": "The oil system for a piston engine incorporates an oil cooler that is fitted :",
    "feedback": "in the return line to the oil tank after the oil has passed through the scavenge pump"
  },
  {
    "question": "The high pressure fuel cock:",
    "feedback": "is used to control fuel flow to the engine."
  },
  {
    "question": "Vapour lock is :",
    "feedback": "vaporizing of fuel prior to reaching the carburettor"
  },
  {
    "question": "When increasing true airspeed with a constant engine RPM, the angle of attack of a fixed pitch propeller:",
    "feedback": "reduces"
  },
  {
    "question": "The speed of an asynchronous four-pole motor supplied at a frequency of 400 Hertz is:",
    "feedback": "12000 revolutions per minute."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements correctly details the reasons and implications for some aircraft designs mounting the horizontal stabiliser on top of the fin (T-tail)?",
    "feedback": "It has a smoother airflow and therefore more predictable flight characteristics, but requires a stronger, heavier fin, and is susceptible to loss of effectiveness at high angles of attack"
  },
  {
    "question": "Overcentre mechanisms in landing gear systems are used to:",
    "feedback": "lock the landing gear in the up and/or down position."
  },
  {
    "question": "On a large transport aeroplane, the auto-slat system:",
    "feedback": "extends (part of) the slats automatically when a certain value of angle of attack is exceeded"
  },
  {
    "question": "Fire precautions to be observed before refuelling are :",
    "feedback": "All bonding and earthing connections between ground equipment and the aircraft should be made before filler caps are removed."
  },
  {
    "question": "In order to turn a magneto off, the primary circuit must be:",
    "feedback": "Grounded."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about rudder limiting are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) A rudder ratio changer system limits both rudder and rudder pedal deflection as the IAS increases\n2) A variable stop system reduces the rudder deflection for a given rudder pedal deflection as the IAS increases",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which part of the nose landing gear is shown by the number 3?",
    "feedback": "Shock absorber"
  },
  {
    "question": "When operating an aircraft with a sidestick, how could the captain take control from either the co-pilot or autopilot?",
    "feedback": "By use of a takeover push-button on the sidestick"
  },
  {
    "question": "Modern pressurized transport airplanes are equipped with :",
    "feedback": "two independent oxygen systems, one supplying the cockpit, the other the cabin."
  },
  {
    "question": "The first indication of carburettor icing, in aeroplanes equipped with constant speed propellers, during cruise would most likely be a:",
    "feedback": "decrease in manifold pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "The blades in an axial flow compressor decrease in size from the:",
    "feedback": "low pressure to the high pressure stages in an attempt to sustain axial velocity"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the event of an AC generator fault, on a twin engine aeroplane, the protection device will open:",
    "feedback": "the exciter control relay and the generator breaker"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is decreased?\n\n1) The propeller blade angle increases\n2) The free power turbine speed remains constant",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a gas turbine engine, the power changes are normally made by controlling the amount of:",
    "feedback": "fuel supplied."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an auto-brake system (ABS) is correct?",
    "feedback": "Without pilot interference an auto-brake system continues to operate until standstill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the figure below:  In a pressurized aircraft whose cabin altitude is 8000 ft, a crack in a cabin window makes it necessary to reduce the differential pressure to 5 psi. The flight level to be maintained in order to keep the same cabin altitude is:",
    "feedback": "FL 230"
  },
  {
    "question": "The range of control surface movements is limited by:",
    "feedback": "providing control stops."
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.\n\nGEN 1 can be used to feed the DC BUS 1, when:\n(NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumend to remain open)",
    "feedback": "C1.1 and C5.1 are closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "The number of hand fire extinguishers which have to be installed in the passenger cabin according to EASA AIR OPS depends on the number of :",
    "feedback": "seats in the cabin."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about oxygen in transport aeroplanes is correct?",
    "feedback": "A passenger oxygen mask contains a device to check if a flow of oxygen is present"
  },
  {
    "question": "After the power stroke on a piston engine, the poppet valve sequence is?",
    "feedback": "Exhaust valve opens, inlet valve opens, exhaust valve closes."
  },
  {
    "question": "Among the different types of aircraft structures, the shell structures efficiently transmit the:  1. normal bending stresses 2. tangent bending stresses 3. torsional moment 4. shear stresses  The combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the advantage of an electrically driven air-conditioning system over a bleed-air system?",
    "feedback": "Reduces take-off distance and increases climb performance due to more thrust being available"
  },
  {
    "question": "A mixture setting richer than best power has to be used during climb segments. This results in a:",
    "feedback": "lower cylinder head temperature"
  },
  {
    "question": "The refueling in a transport jet aircraft is made ...",
    "feedback": "Through a unique point (an underwing refueling center)."
  },
  {
    "question": "A composite structural component consists of:",
    "feedback": "a matrix and fibres"
  },
  {
    "question": "On Jet aircraft the primary source of compressed air is:",
    "feedback": "Bleed air from engine driven compressor."
  },
  {
    "question": "For a subsonic airflow, air passing through a divergent duct:",
    "feedback": "decreases in velocity and increases in pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements concerning oxygen on board of passenger transport aeroplanes is correct?",
    "feedback": "A chemical oxygen generator is able to provide oxygen for about 15 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of a NOT logic gate within a circuit is to :",
    "feedback": "invert the input signal such that the output is always of the opposite state."
  },
  {
    "question": "A passenger oxygen mask is:",
    "feedback": "a continuous flow mask and in principle should not be used if there is smoke in the cabin"
  },
  {
    "question": "An artificial feel unit  is necessary in the pitch channel when:",
    "feedback": "the elevators are actuated by irreversible servo-control units."
  },
  {
    "question": "Jet engine total efficiency indicates the efficiency at which:",
    "feedback": "chemical power in the fuel is transformed into propulsive power (T x V)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The total number of hydraulic pumps in this hydraulic system (excluding the PTU pump) is:",
    "feedback": "5"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an oxygen mask selected to the DILUTE DEMAND position:\n1) Oxygen is delivered when inhaling\n2) Oxygen is always delivered with a continuous flow\n3) Air outside the mask is added to the oxygen flow\n4) A special oxygen reservoir is used containing diluted oxygen\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "For takeoff, a constant-speed propeller is normally set in the",
    "feedback": "LOW PITCH, high RPM position."
  },
  {
    "question": "Continuous loop fire detector systems operate on the prinicple that an increase in temperature produces :",
    "feedback": "a decrease in resistance"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to CS 25, which of the following is a secondary flight control?",
    "feedback": "Trim tab."
  },
  {
    "question": "The relationship between compression ratio of a piston engine and the required fuel octane rating is that the:",
    "feedback": "higher the compression ratio, the higher the octane rating required"
  },
  {
    "question": "The richness of a fuel/air mixture ratio is the :",
    "feedback": "real mixture ratio relative to the theoretical ratio."
  },
  {
    "question": "The take off of a jet aeroplane may be performed with \"reduced thrust\" in order to:",
    "feedback": "reduce maintenance costs"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about a reaction turbine are correct or incorrect?  1) The pressure remains constant across the nozzle guide vanes 2) The pressure drops across the rotor blades",
    "feedback": "1) is correct,2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a centrifugal compressor:",
    "feedback": "the air enters the impeller axially at the eye and leaves at the periphery tangentially"
  },
  {
    "question": "Assuming a hydraulic accumulator is pre-charged with nitrogen to 1000 psi. If the hydraulic system is then pressurised to its operating pressure of 3000 psi, the indicated pressure on the nitrogen side of the accumulator should be :",
    "feedback": "3000 psi."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is the heater combustion chamber in an aircraft pressurisation system \ncompletely separated from the ventilating system?",
    "feedback": "To prevent any exhaust gases from contaminating the cabin air."
  },
  {
    "question": "In jet aeroplanes the 'thermal anti-ice system' is primary supplied by",
    "feedback": "bleed air from the engines."
  },
  {
    "question": "Stall fences mounted on an aircraft wing are used:",
    "feedback": "To prevent the tendency of the outer portion of the wing to stall first."
  },
  {
    "question": "The rating of electrical fuses is expressed in:",
    "feedback": "amperes"
  },
  {
    "question": "The engine anti ice system should be used based upon the following information:",
    "feedback": "Reported temperature when on ground, and ram air temperature when airborne."
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the fuel schematic of the two-engine aircraft. Where on the diagram is the fuel crossfeed valve located?",
    "feedback": "Position 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The following is normally true regarding hydraulic hand pumps. They are:",
    "feedback": "connected to the bottom of the reservoir"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which system ensures correct functioning during the start of the engine at high altitude and in cold temperatures?",
    "feedback": "Spark of large heat intensity"
  },
  {
    "question": "The phase relationship between two unparalleled AC generators:",
    "feedback": "is unimportant."
  },
  {
    "question": "A failed capacitive fuel contents indication system will:",
    "feedback": "cause the gauge to indicate zero regardless of content."
  },
  {
    "question": "A Krueger flap is:",
    "feedback": "A leading edge flap type which is formed by extending an area of the wing\ndownwards and forward at the leading edge."
  },
  {
    "question": "Cylinder walls are usually lubricated by",
    "feedback": "splashed or sprayed oil."
  },
  {
    "question": "If an aircraft is equipped with a fixed gear, which of the mentioned factors will differ from a retractable landing gear?",
    "feedback": "Parasite drag"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cooling air for a reciprocating engine is obtained by means of:",
    "feedback": "ram air"
  },
  {
    "question": "Assuming cabin pressure decreases, the cabin rate of climb indicator should indicate :",
    "feedback": "a rate of climb."
  },
  {
    "question": "Compressor surge may be indicated by:",
    "feedback": "an increase in jet pipe temperature."
  },
  {
    "question": "After the gas leaves the combustion chambers it:",
    "feedback": "is directed onto the turbine by the nozzle guide vanes."
  },
  {
    "question": "Select the correct answer from the following statements regarding the rotor of an AC or DC motor:\n1) The rotor/driven-load assembly must be correctly aligned to avoid damage to the bearings2) Poor lubrication, misalignment or load unbalance may lead to the seizure of the drive shaft",
    "feedback": "1) and 2) are correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is described by the term \"alpha range\" when talking about a turboprop?",
    "feedback": "Flight idle to maximum power"
  },
  {
    "question": "Filtration in a hydraulic system is usually ensured by:",
    "feedback": "filters in both the pressure and return lines."
  },
  {
    "question": "The cabin air for modern airplanes is usually supplied by:",
    "feedback": "main engine compressors."
  },
  {
    "question": "An abortive (hung) start is the term used to describe an attempt to start in which the engine:",
    "feedback": "lights up, but fails to accelerate sufficiently"
  },
  {
    "question": "The operating pressure of a booster pump in the fuel supply system of a gas turbine aircraft is within the following range:",
    "feedback": "20 to 100 psi"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some aircraft use a fly-by-wire system to move the primary flight controls. This system is based on:",
    "feedback": "electrical signals from a computer sent to hydraulic actuators."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which part of the main landing gear is shown by the number 6?",
    "feedback": "Bogie beam"
  },
  {
    "question": "The SI cycle per unit of time, used for AC frequencies, is ......",
    "feedback": "Hertz"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the cockpit of a FADEC-controlled single engine piston aircraft with a variable pitch propeller, what engine control levers would you expect to have?",
    "feedback": "Power/throttle lever only"
  },
  {
    "question": "In flight, with the centre tank empty and APU operating, a fuel imbalance is detected (quantity in left main tank is less than in right main tank). Rebalancing of the two tanks is:",
    "feedback": "possible with crossfeed valves \"OPEN\", left main tank pumps \"OFF\" and right main tank pumps \"ON\""
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement about the auto-brake and anti-skid system is correct?",
    "feedback": "The auto-brake system can not operate without a properly operating anti-skid system"
  },
  {
    "question": "An intercooler is sometimes fitted between supercharger and inlet manifold to:",
    "feedback": "minimise the risk of detonation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the specific gravity of Jet A-1 fuel at 15°C?",
    "feedback": "0.82"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is decreased?\n\n1) The gas generator speed increases\n2) The EGT increases",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can the pressure of hydraulic fluid be indicated in transport aircraft?",
    "feedback": "Pressure transducer"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a fail safe component of the aircraft structure is damaged ......",
    "feedback": "the loads will be carried by an adjacent part for a limited time period"
  },
  {
    "question": "The station numbers before and after the LP compressor are:",
    "feedback": "2 and 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a gas turbine engine, the maximum gas temperature is attained:",
    "feedback": "within the combustion chamber"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a non-stressed skin type wing, the wing structure elements which take up the vertical bending moments Mx are:",
    "feedback": "the spars."
  },
  {
    "question": "Most large conventional aeroplanes are not provided with aileron and rudder trim tabs. Is it still possible to trim these control surfaces?",
    "feedback": "Yes, trimming is possible by adjusting the neutral point of the artifical feel mechanism by means of a trim switch"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these properties is desirable in the materials used for constructing an airframe?",
    "feedback": "High strength-to-weight ratio"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is increased?\n\n1) The HP spool speed remains constant\n2) The EGT increases",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The expression \"secondary flight control\" applies to the:\n\n1) elevator\n2) speed brake\n3) lift-augmentation devices\n4) roll spoiler\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the oxygen system of a large aeroplane is used:",
    "feedback": "with the setting on NORMAL, the cockpit crew is supplied with a mixture of oxygen and cabin air"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the attached diagram, which image represents tension?",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "A relay is :",
    "feedback": "An electromagnetically operated switch."
  },
  {
    "question": "If one of the 12 cells of a lead-acid battery has a broken connection rendering it inoperable, the battery:",
    "feedback": "is unserviceable."
  },
  {
    "question": "\"Vapour lock\" is the phenomenon by which:",
    "feedback": "heat produces vapour plugs in the fuel line."
  },
  {
    "question": "In straight and level flight the most important loads on a cantilever wing are:",
    "feedback": "compression in the upper surface, tension in the lower surface"
  },
  {
    "question": "With the anti-skid system unserviceable, how should brake application be made?",
    "feedback": "With an on and off braking action."
  },
  {
    "question": "In computer technology, an output peripheral is a:",
    "feedback": "screen unit"
  },
  {
    "question": "The smoke detection in the aircraft cargo compartments is carried out by four sensors: C1, C2, C3 and C4.\nThey are associated with the logic circuit as described.\nThe repeating bell is activated when:",
    "feedback": "the C1 and C2 sensors detect smoke."
  },
  {
    "question": "During the test sequence of the Fire Detection System, the \"TEST\" light does not illuminate and the pilot has no other visual confirmation. Which of the following statements is correct assuming the light indicator doesn't have a problem?",
    "feedback": "The circuit is not grounded because of a break in the wire between the detectors, therefore the light(s) will not illuminate"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a modern jet transport aircraft, how can the landing gear be extended if there is a complete hydraulic system failure.",
    "feedback": "Mechanically"
  },
  {
    "question": "The accumulator in a hydraulic system works as:",
    "feedback": "an energy storage."
  },
  {
    "question": "The elevators of a conventional airplane are used to provide rotation about the",
    "feedback": "Lateral axis"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a manifold pressure gauge consistently registers atmospheric pressure, the cause is probably ....",
    "feedback": "a leak in the pressure gauge line"
  },
  {
    "question": "As altitude increases, the mixture ratio of a piston engine should be adjusted to:",
    "feedback": "reduce the fuel flow in order to compensate for the decreasing air density"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a reheat system, with a variable position propelling nozzle, when reheat is selected the nozzle will:",
    "feedback": "will open."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an impulse turbine are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The pressure remains constant across the nozzle guide vanes\n2) The pressure rises across the rotor blades",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an air cycle machine (bootstrap system) the:",
    "feedback": "turbine drives the compressor, which makes the second heat exchanger more effective"
  },
  {
    "question": "An impulse coupling is installed on a magneto of a piston engine to:",
    "feedback": "provide a stronger spark on top dead centre for engine starting"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the maximum operating pressure of the oxygen system is exceeded the:",
    "feedback": "oxygen is discharged overboard via a safety plug"
  },
  {
    "question": "A component that provides 115 VAC output after an input of 28 VDC is called:",
    "feedback": "An inverter, static or rotary."
  },
  {
    "question": "The EMERGENCY position of a cockpit oxygen mask:",
    "feedback": "should be used when there is smoke on the flight deck"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gas turbine engine lubrication oils are normally:",
    "feedback": "synthetic based."
  },
  {
    "question": "A modern Auxiliary Power Unit (APU) is designed to provide power for ground starting of an engine. It also supplies both in the air (subject of certification limitations) and on the ground :",
    "feedback": "air conditioning and electrical services."
  },
  {
    "question": "To avoid the risk of tyre burst from overheating there is:",
    "feedback": "a thermal plug that deflates the tyre at a specific temperature"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a piston engine, the camshaft",
    "feedback": "rotates at half the speed of the crankshaft."
  },
  {
    "question": "The pack cooling fan provides:",
    "feedback": "cooling air to the primary and secondary heat exchanger during slow flight and ground operation."
  },
  {
    "question": "A hung (abortive) start of a gas turbine engine may be caused by:",
    "feedback": "a too low pneumatic starter pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the ground wire of a magneto is disconnected at the ignition switch, the result will be:",
    "feedback": "The engine will not stop running when the ignition switch is turned off."
  },
  {
    "question": "Under normal conditions ( CS 25) the cabin pressure altitude is not allowed to exceed:",
    "feedback": "8000 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "A turbocharger system in a reciprocating engine is normally driven by:",
    "feedback": "the exhaust system."
  },
  {
    "question": "A DC generator fitted to a commercial aircraft is cooled by :",
    "feedback": "air via a ram air intake."
  },
  {
    "question": "The reservoirs of a hydraulic system of a transport aircraft are typically pressurized:",
    "feedback": "by bleed air from the engine"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the blow-in-doors at the air inlets is to:",
    "feedback": "provide the engine with additional air at high power settings and low air speeds."
  },
  {
    "question": "The refuelling in a transport jet aircraft is made:",
    "feedback": "through a unique point (an underwing refuelling centre)"
  },
  {
    "question": "A torsion link assembly is installed on the landing gear to :",
    "feedback": "avoid rotation of the piston rod relative to the gear oleo strut."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a turbo-jet, the purpose of the turbine is to ...",
    "feedback": "drive the compressor by using part of the energy from the exhaust gases"
  },
  {
    "question": "With speed brakes deployed in flight and a pilot's input to turn left:",
    "feedback": "spoilers move up on the down-going wing and down on the up-going wing."
  },
  {
    "question": "The thermal efficiency of a diesel engine is higher than that of a petrol engine because:",
    "feedback": "the compression ratio is much higher"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is increased?\n\n1) The propeller blade angle remains constant\n2) The free power turbine speed increases",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Overheating of a piston engine is likely to result from an excessively :",
    "feedback": "weak mixture."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a single spool gas turbine engine, the compressor rpm is :",
    "feedback": "the same as turbine rpm."
  },
  {
    "question": "If the backup system of extending the landing gear is of the free-fall type, what is moved with mechanical power first?",
    "feedback": "The uplock mechanism"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a bootstrap system, the purpose of the heat exchangers is to:",
    "feedback": "cool bleed air and compressor air from the turbo refrigerator."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is increased?\n\n1) The gas generator speed decreases\n2) The EGT decreases",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an auto-brake system during RTO (Rejected Take Off) is correct?",
    "feedback": "In the RTO mode maximum anti-skid braking is applied"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the ground wire between the magnetos and the ignition switch becomes disconnected the most noticeable result will be that:",
    "feedback": "the engine cannot be shut down by turning the ignition switch to the \"OFF\" position"
  },
  {
    "question": "When fire is detected on engine n°2, the fire shutoff handle n°2 is pulled and the extinguishing agent n°1 is discharged. This results in :",
    "feedback": "the discharge of fire extinguisher bottle #2 and illumination of the DISCH indicator lamp of agent #1 on engine #2 and DISCH indicator lamp of agent #2 on engine #1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of this circuit diagram symbols represents an auto-transformer?",
    "feedback": "C"
  },
  {
    "question": "The chemical oxygen generator is a system:\n\n1. which is inexpensive\n2. requiring no external input\n3. which is lightweight\n4. requiring no maintenance\n5. with adjustable flow rate\n6. which is unsafe\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "In computer technology, an EPROM is:\n\n1. a read-only memory\n2. a write memory\n3. erases its content when power supply is cut off\n4. keeps its content when power supply is cut off\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1,4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main difference between a fuse and a circuit breaker is that:",
    "feedback": "The fuse has to be replaced, but the circuit breaker can be reset."
  },
  {
    "question": "Hydraulic fluids used in systems of modern airliners are:",
    "feedback": "Phosphate ester base fluids."
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of bonding is:",
    "feedback": "to keep all parts of the aircraft at the same potential."
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the risks associated with the use of lithium ion batteries in flight is ....",
    "feedback": "overheating during charging, which could lead to self-ignition if not properly monitored"
  },
  {
    "question": "When do you say that an aircraft has a cantilever wing?",
    "feedback": "When the wing is attached to the fuselage at or near one end only."
  },
  {
    "question": "The electronic engine control of a FADEC gas turbine engine checks:",
    "feedback": "all input and output data"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of a scissor (torsion link) in a landing gear is to:",
    "feedback": "prevent any rotation of the oleo strut in the undercarriage shock absorber."
  },
  {
    "question": "What logic function is achieved by the following circuit, where A and B are the inputs and C is the output?",
    "feedback": "NOR"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which formula is used to calculate the capacitance C of a capacitor where:\ne=dielectric constant\nA=area of the plates\nd=distance between the plates?",
    "feedback": "C = e * (A / d)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \"ply rating\" of a tire is?",
    "feedback": "A parameter indicating the tire relative strength."
  },
  {
    "question": "In the context of airframe load path philosophies a 'fail safe' component is:",
    "feedback": "a component incorporated in a large aircraft which is designed so that, following its failure, the remaining structure can withstand reasonable loads without failure until the damage is detected."
  },
  {
    "question": "In an alternator rotor coil you can find :",
    "feedback": "DC."
  },
  {
    "question": "How will the auto-brake system respond when a landing is performed with the system armed and the pilot presses the brake pedals after landing?",
    "feedback": "The system switches to DISARMED or OFF"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the \"Pressure Relief Valve\" in a high pressure oxygen system is to :",
    "feedback": "relieve overpressure if the pressure reducing valve malfunctions"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the diagram, the component 4 is a:",
    "feedback": "static inverter"
  },
  {
    "question": "For fail safe designed structural components:\n\n1) there is more than one load carrying component\n2) one load carrying component is sufficient, provided it is strong enough\n3) the component is removed at the end of the calculated life time or number of cycles\n4) the design is based on the principle of redundancy of components\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "For an aeroplane hydraulic supply circuit, the correct statement is :",
    "feedback": "the security components comprise the filters, the pressure relief valves, the by-passes, and the fire shut-off valve."
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is fitted with an electrical system according to the schematic. GEN 1 has failed. Power is provided to DC BUS 1:",
    "feedback": "By closing contacts GB 2, BTB 2, and TB 1"
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens once the pilot has operated the IDG (Integrated Drive Generator) disconnect button?",
    "feedback": "An electrical supply system will be lost"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the pilot moves the mixture lever of a piston engine towards a leaner position the:",
    "feedback": "amount of fuel entering the combustion chamber is reduced."
  },
  {
    "question": "Hydraulic fluid should have the following characteristic:",
    "feedback": "incompressibility"
  },
  {
    "question": "The fuel-oil heat exchanger:",
    "feedback": "cools the oil and heats the fuel"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct?\nIf the aircraft fuselage consists of formers, stringers or longerons and stressed skin, the fuselage is a:",
    "feedback": "Semi-monocoque type fuselage"
  },
  {
    "question": "Clamshell doors are selected and actuated by the following means:",
    "feedback": "mechanically and pneumatically respectively."
  },
  {
    "question": "For take-off, the correct combination of propeller pitch (1), and propeller lever position (2) at brake release is:",
    "feedback": "(1) low (2) forward"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an aircraft air conditioning system of short-haul jet aircraft the air cannot be treated for:",
    "feedback": "humidity."
  },
  {
    "question": "The air flow passages between adjacent axial compressor rotor blades are divergent, but the absolute exit velocity is higher than the absolute entry velocity of the rotor. This is because:",
    "feedback": "part of the compressor work delivered to the air is converted into kinetic energy"
  },
  {
    "question": "For a subsonic airflow, air passing through a divergent duct:",
    "feedback": "pressure increases, velocity decreases and temperature increases"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pressurisation system of an aeroplane:",
    "feedback": "has the capability to maintain cabin pressure higher than ambient pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.  In flight, the AC ESS BUS can be fed by the EMER GEN, when: (NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumend to remain open)",
    "feedback": "C4.1 is closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "To achieve control flutter damping the balance mass must be located:",
    "feedback": "in front of the control surface hinge"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a twin spooled compressor engine, on starting:",
    "feedback": "the high pressure compressor is started by the motor."
  },
  {
    "question": "The common used symbol of voltage is .....",
    "feedback": "U and it is measured in volts."
  },
  {
    "question": "In the diagram, the component 1 is a:",
    "feedback": "TRU"
  },
  {
    "question": "Circuit breakers protecting circuits may be :",
    "feedback": "used in AC and DC circuits."
  },
  {
    "question": "In the stator of a turbine, the gas velocity V and static pressure p vary as follows:",
    "feedback": "V increases, p decreases."
  },
  {
    "question": "Both gas turbine and piston engines use a cycle made up of induction, compression, combustion and exhaust phases. Which of these statements about a gas turbine are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The process in a gas turbine is intermittent\n2) Theoretically the combustion occurs at constant pressure",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Purposes of an accumulator in a hydraulic system are:\n\n1) to damp pressure fluctuations\n2) to cool the hydraulic fluid\n3) to serve as a limited alternate source of pressure\n4) to serve as a main pressure source for normal operation\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of this circuit diagram symbols represents a relay?",
    "feedback": "B"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a gas turbine engine lubrication system fitted with an oil to fuel heat exchanger the:",
    "feedback": "oil is cooled through thermal exchange with the fuel"
  },
  {
    "question": "The reading on the oil pressure gauge is the:",
    "feedback": "pressure of the oil on the outlet side of the pressure pump."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an auto-brake system is correct?",
    "feedback": "When a low auto-brake setting is used during landing use of reverse thrust reduces the brake temperature"
  },
  {
    "question": "The advantages of a chemical oxygen source compared with a gaseous one for the passenger cabin are:\n\n1) Easier maintenance\n2) Greater capacity\n3) Reduced risk of explosion\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a piston engine aircraft, the vent lines in the fuel system are installed to ....",
    "feedback": "allow atmospheric pressure to enter the fuel tank in order to avoid a vacuum"
  },
  {
    "question": "An axial compressor, when operating below its design speed, has:",
    "feedback": "a tendency to stall in the front stages."
  },
  {
    "question": "The station numbers before and after the HP turbine are:",
    "feedback": "5 and 6"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about trimming in a irreversible flight control system of a conventional aeroplane are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The zero force position of the control column does not change when using the elevator trim\n2) The zero force position of the control wheel changes when using the aileron trim",
    "feedback": "1) is correct 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Within the combustion chambers the burned fuel/air mixture:",
    "feedback": "increases in volume."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a By-Pass engine, the by-pass exhaust is:",
    "feedback": "sometimes mixed with the normal exhaust gases in the jet pipe."
  },
  {
    "question": "If the exhaust valve of a four-stroke cycle engine is closed and the intake valve\nis just closing, the piston is on the",
    "feedback": "compression stroke."
  },
  {
    "question": "The type of fuel tank used on most large aeroplanes is a(n):",
    "feedback": "integral tank"
  },
  {
    "question": "The term bootstrap, when used to identify a cabin air conditioning and pressurisation system, refers to the :",
    "feedback": "air cycle machine"
  },
  {
    "question": "On an aircraft landing gear, an under-inflated tyre:",
    "feedback": "will wear at the shoulders"
  },
  {
    "question": "Fuses are rated to a value by :",
    "feedback": "the number of amperes they will carry."
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of a constant speed drive (CSD) is to ensure:",
    "feedback": "that the electric generator produces a constant frequency."
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of a  constant speed drive (CSD) in an AC generating system is to :",
    "feedback": "drive the generator at a constant speed."
  },
  {
    "question": "In the following diagram A, B and C are respectively the:",
    "feedback": "battery master switch, starter switch, starter relay."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a HP brake hydraulic system:",
    "feedback": "a separate handbrake system is always fitted together with its own accumulator and its own system components."
  },
  {
    "question": "When performing a magneto ground check on an engine, correct operation is indicated by:",
    "feedback": "A slight drop in RPM."
  },
  {
    "question": "When detonation is recognised in a piston engine, the correct procedure is to:",
    "feedback": "reduce manifold pressure and enrich the mixture"
  },
  {
    "question": "As aircraft speed increases (up to the airspeed below which air is considered as uncompressible) the dynamic pressure within the subsonic air inlet of a turbofan engine (1) .... and the engine specific thrust (2) ....",
    "feedback": "(1) increases, (2) decreases"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a hydraulic braking system, an accumulator is precharged to 1600 psi. An electrically driven hydraulic pump is started and provides a system pressure of 3000 psi. The hydraulic pressure gauge, which is connected to the gas section of the accumulator, reads:",
    "feedback": "3000 psi."
  },
  {
    "question": "The main feature of BCF fire extinguishers is that they :",
    "feedback": "act as flame inhibitors by absorbing the air's oxygen."
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the number 100 indicate in AVGAS 100LL?",
    "feedback": "Its resistance to detonation."
  },
  {
    "question": "The most commonly used circuit protection device in modern aircraft is a",
    "feedback": "push and pull circuit breaker."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is normally used as a leak detector in an aircraft oxygen system?",
    "feedback": "A form of non-oily soap solution."
  },
  {
    "question": "Hydraulic power is a function of:",
    "feedback": "system pressure and volume flow"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a flight control system a device in which a small input operates a large output in a strictly proportionate manner is called:",
    "feedback": "a servomechanism."
  },
  {
    "question": "If the control stick of an aircraft is moved forward:",
    "feedback": "the elevator will move down."
  },
  {
    "question": "A rich mixture setting has to be used during climb segments. This results in a",
    "feedback": "lower cylinder head temperature."
  },
  {
    "question": "With respect to a piston engined aircraft, ice in the carburettor :",
    "feedback": "may form at OAT's higher than +10°C."
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.\n\nGEN 1 can be used to feed the AC BUS 2, when:\n(NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumend to remain open)",
    "feedback": "C1.1, C2.1 and C2.2 are closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the figure.\nIn flight, with the centre tank empty and the APU operating, a fuel imbalance is detected where the quantity of fuel in the left main tank is less than in the right main tank. Rebalancing of the two tanks is:",
    "feedback": "Possible with the crossfeed valves \"OPEN\", the left main tank AC pumps \"OFF\", and right main tank AC pumps \"ON\""
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of a surge box inside a fuel tank?",
    "feedback": "Prevent sloshing of fuel away from pump inlet during abnormal manoeuvres."
  },
  {
    "question": "The fuel supply system on a jet engine includes a fuel heating device, upstream of the main fuel filter so as to:",
    "feedback": "prevent, at low fuel temperature, the risk of ice formation from water contained in the fuel"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of an accumulator in a hydraulic brake system?",
    "feedback": "To supply an emergency reserve of power in the event of a hydraulic failure"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is increased?\n\n1) The propeller blade angle decreases\n2) The free power turbine speed decreases",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "An undercarriage leg is locked when:",
    "feedback": "it is mechanically locked by on over-centre mechanism"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FADEC (Full Authority Digital Engine Control) can provide:\n1) Thrust reverser control\n2) Engine operation within safe limits\n3) Automatic engine starting sequence\n4) Automatic thrust rating control\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding the chemical oxygen generator, to enable the oxygen to flow, the passenger must:",
    "feedback": "firmly pull the mask towards his face"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of the gearbox of a turboprop is to cause the propeller to rotate at an RPM",
    "feedback": "less than engine RPM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.\n\nGEN 2 can be used to feed the DC BAT BUS:\n(NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumend to remain open)",
    "feedback": "via AC BUS 2 and DC BUS 1, when C1.4, C3.2, C3.1, C5.1 and C7.1 are closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following options is a way that FADEC can enhance piston engine operation?",
    "feedback": "Automatically altering ignition timing with changes in RPM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider a flat rated twin-spool turbofan with conventional hydro-mechanical fuel control. \nWhen using maximum take-off thrust at an outside air temperature OAT that is below the flat rated temperature:",
    "feedback": "the thrust lever is not positioned at the maximum stop"
  },
  {
    "question": "An engine turbocharger is said to be \"ground-boosted\" when it:",
    "feedback": "maintains a manifold pressure above sea level conditions."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct about the flow in a divergent (subsonic) gas turbine engine intake?\n\n1) The speed decreases in flow direction\n2) The total pressure remains constant in flow direction",
    "feedback": "1) is correct,2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "If air is tapped from a gas turbine HP compressor (engine N2 controlled), the effect on the engine pressure ratio (EPR) and the exhaust gas temperature (EGT) is that :",
    "feedback": "EPR decreases and EGT increases."
  },
  {
    "question": "A lithium polymer battery is most likely to be a hazard to the aircraft when:",
    "feedback": "The battery is rapidly discharged"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the diagram, the component 3 is a:",
    "feedback": "TRU"
  },
  {
    "question": "An excessively rich mixture can be detected by :",
    "feedback": "black smoke from exhaust."
  },
  {
    "question": "As a pilot you perform the pre-flight check, including the wheels and tyres. Which statement is correct?",
    "feedback": "If tread separation is left undetected, the tyre may burst upon landing or take-off"
  },
  {
    "question": "The application of carburettor heating reduces the:",
    "feedback": "density of air entering the carburettor, thus enriching the mixture"
  },
  {
    "question": "The measured output power components of a constant frequency AC system are :",
    "feedback": "kVA and kVAR."
  },
  {
    "question": "When a persistent overexcitation fault is detected on only one AC generator, the protection device opens the :",
    "feedback": "exciter breaker and generator breaker."
  },
  {
    "question": "The temperature of hydraulic fluid is measured:",
    "feedback": "in the reservoir."
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.\n\nGEN 1 can be used to feed the DC ESS BUS:\n(NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumend to remain open)",
    "feedback": "via AC BUS 1, when C1.1, C3.1 and C5.2 are closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "The station numbers before and after the HP compressor are:",
    "feedback": "3 and 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The cabin differential pressure is:",
    "feedback": "cabin pressure minus ambient air pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an impulse turbine are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The pressure rises across the nozzle guide vanes\n2) The pressure remains constant across the rotor blades",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an aeroplane's hydraulic system is correct?",
    "feedback": "The filters, the pressure relief valve(s), the by-pass valve(s), and the fire shut-off valve are safety features installed in the system"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an auto-brake system during RTO (Rejected Take Off) is correct?",
    "feedback": "Using the RTO mode provides the best stopping performance during a rejected take-off"
  },
  {
    "question": "Fuel tank air pressure is maintained at ambient by:",
    "feedback": "the fuel vent system"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft with pressurised cabin has maximum cabin altitude of 8000 feet, which equals 10.9 PSI. Present flight altitude is 30.000 feet, which equals 4.36 PSI. Pressure at sea level equals 14.7 PSI.  Calculate the difference pressure that influences the cabin structure:",
    "feedback": "6.54 psid."
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, which statement is the most correct? \nWhile in cruise flight, a circuit breaker corresponding to one of the fuel boost pumps, trips. The circuit breaker can not be reset:",
    "feedback": "The pump remains inoperative."
  },
  {
    "question": "The FADEC on a gas turbine engine:",
    "feedback": "is single fault tolerant"
  },
  {
    "question": "When applying precautionary carburettor heating on a reciprocating engine with a fixed pitch propeller:",
    "feedback": "the RPM decreases"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a battery control unit is generally to isolate the battery:\n1) from the bus when the battery charge has been completed2) when there is a battery overhead condition3) in case of an internal short circuit4) in case of a fault on the ground power unit\nThe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the barometric correction in a carburettor is to:",
    "feedback": "maintain the correct weight fuel to air ratio when the altitude increases."
  },
  {
    "question": "Because of the connection in parallel of electrical systems on an AC bus bar, isolation of individual equipments:",
    "feedback": "decreases the bus bar current consumption"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the voltage regulator is to :",
    "feedback": "Keep a constant voltage output from the generator."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why are flaps and slats fitted to modern aircraft?",
    "feedback": "To reduce takeoff, approach and landing speeds to an acceptable level."
  },
  {
    "question": "One type of flap used on aircraft moves down and increases the wing area by moving aft when lowered. This flap is known as:",
    "feedback": "Fowler flap."
  },
  {
    "question": "Gas-filled fire detectors work on the principle that heat causes the internal pressure to ....",
    "feedback": "increase, causing a fire warning indication"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about the wing structure is correct?",
    "feedback": "A torsion box is formed by wing spars, ribs and wing skin reinforced by stringers"
  },
  {
    "question": "When an underspeed fault is detected on an AC generator connected to the aircraft AC busbar, the protection device opens the:",
    "feedback": "generator breaker."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an impulse turbine are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The pressure rises across the nozzle guide vanes\n2) The pressure rises across the rotor blades",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Fuel flow information for gas turbine engines is:",
    "feedback": "measured in the line between the fuel control unit and the engine burners."
  },
  {
    "question": "A CSD unit which has been disconnected in flight :",
    "feedback": "may be reset on the ground only, after engine shut-down."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an impulse turbine are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The pressure remains constant across the nozzle guide vanes\n2) The pressure drops across the rotor blades",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pneumatic mechanical ice protection systems are mainly used for:",
    "feedback": "wings"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Number in the graph that shows the retraction actuator is:",
    "feedback": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the aircraft electrical system diagram, assuming that there is no RAT and the APU cannot be used in flight. After a failure of both engines, which of the following will still be available?\n1) BAT 1 and BAT 22) DC EMER and AC EMER3) AC1 and AC24) AC ESS BUS",
    "feedback": "1) and 2)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Generally, on modern jet transport aeroplanes, if there is a complete hydraulic system failure, the landing gear can be extended:",
    "feedback": "by gravity extension."
  },
  {
    "question": "The high pressure fuel pump is normally driven:",
    "feedback": "mechanically by the engine."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is/are correct?\n1) An autobrake system will either apply maximum braking (RTO or MAX) or result in a given rate of deceleration2) The amount of braking applied by an autobrake system is not affected by the use of reverse thrust and/or by a slippery runway",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is not correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens following a total centre tank fuel pump failure?",
    "feedback": "All or part of the fuel in the centre tank may be unusable"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft magneto is switched off by:\n\n1) grounding the primary circuit\n2) opening the primary circuit\n3) opening the secondary circuit\n4) grounding the secondary circuit\n\nThe combination that regoups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \"cabin differential pressure\" is:",
    "feedback": "cabin pressure minus ambient pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "The operations of an airline plan the operation of a pressurized aircraft at a 240 flight level on its whole route with 150 passengers on board.\nAs concerns the regulatory requirements about oxygen:\n\n1. each crew member will have available a quick fitting inhaler device.\n2. the aircraft will be equipped with a warning system indicating that the cabin altitude is higher than 3 000 m.\n3 . the quantity of oxygen on board will be sufficient for the supply of 100 % of the occupants during the whole flight time above the flight level 150 after an eventual depressurization.\n4. the first aid quantity of oxygen will be sufficient for the supply of two passengers during the whole flight time when the cabin altitude is greater than 8 000 feet.\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2,3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Load shedding means ..",
    "feedback": "Temporarily or permanent switching off of certain electric users to avoid overload of electric generators"
  },
  {
    "question": "The action of the swirl vanes in a combustion system is to create a:",
    "feedback": "back flow."
  },
  {
    "question": "The primary purpose of bonding the metallic parts of an aircraft is to :",
    "feedback": "provide safe distribution of electrical charges and currents."
  },
  {
    "question": "The nozzles and blades of the turbine are manufactured with a state of twist to:",
    "feedback": "ensure the gas flow enters the exhaust system at uniform axial velocity."
  },
  {
    "question": "An unpressurised aircraft is flying at 12000 feet. The selection on the oxygen control box are NORMAL, NORMAL and ON. The flow which is fed to the pilot is:",
    "feedback": "Diluter-demand"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hydraulic fluids most frequently used in the systems of modern large transport airplanes are:",
    "feedback": "phosphate ester based fluids"
  },
  {
    "question": "The input and output of a static inverter are respectively:",
    "feedback": "DC and AC"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeroplane with a pressurized cabin flies at FL 310 and, following a malfunction of the pressure controller, the outflow valve runs to the open position. Given :\n\nCAB V/S: Cabin rate of climb indication\nCAB ALT: Cabin pressure altitude\nDELTA P: Differential pressure\n\nThis will result in a:",
    "feedback": "CAB V/S increase\nCAB ALT increase\nDELTA P decrease"
  },
  {
    "question": "The oil system of a gas turbine engine may be fitted with magnetic plugs, or chip detectors, that:",
    "feedback": "provide warning of impending failure without having to remove the filters for inspection"
  },
  {
    "question": "The diagram represents a twin engine aeroplane electrical system. Batteries are located at positions:",
    "feedback": "1, 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the control stick of an aircraft with properly rigged flight controls is moved rearward and to the left, the right aileron will move",
    "feedback": "down and the elevator will move up"
  },
  {
    "question": "A substance which may never be used in the vicinity or on parts of an oxygen installation is :",
    "feedback": "Grease"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements is correct about a flight crew oxygen mask?",
    "feedback": "In the position DILUTE, oxygen is mixed with air from outside the mask"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following may be controlled by FADEC in a piston engine?",
    "feedback": "The mixture ratio and ignition timing"
  },
  {
    "question": "The sequential pneumatic impulses used in certain leading edge de-icing devices:\n\n1) Prevent ice formation\n2) Can be triggered from the flight deck after icing has become visible\n3) Will inflate each pneumatic boot for a few seconds\n4) Will repeat more than ten times per second\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The hydraulic device, which functionality is comparable to an electronic diode, is a :",
    "feedback": "check valve."
  },
  {
    "question": "The accessory units driven by the accessory gearbox of a turbo-jet engine are the :\n\n1. tacho-generator N1\n2. tacho-generator N2\n3. thrust reverser pneumatic motors\n4. AC generator and its Constant Speed Unit (CSD)\n5. oil pumps\n6. hydraulic pumps\n7. high pressure fuel pumps\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "2, 4, 5, 6, 7"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements concerning a sandwich structural part are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) A sandwich structural part consists of fibres and a resin\n2) A sandwich structural part is not suitable for absorbing concentrated loads",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Turbine fuel may contain additives to ....",
    "feedback": "reduce the risk of ice crystals forming at low temperatures"
  },
  {
    "question": "Because of the input/output relationship of an OR gate, it is often referred to as the :",
    "feedback": "\"any or all\" gate."
  },
  {
    "question": "To unfeather a propeller during flight you have to :",
    "feedback": "use the electric unfeathering pump."
  },
  {
    "question": "Smoke detector systems are installed in the",
    "feedback": "upper cargo compartments (class E)."
  },
  {
    "question": "When a bimetallic strip is used as a switch in a fire detection loop, a fire alarm is triggered after a delay. The purpose of this delay is to:",
    "feedback": "avoid false alarms in case of vibrations"
  },
  {
    "question": "When carrying out battery condition check using the aeroplane's voltmeter :",
    "feedback": "a load should be applied to the battery in order to give a better indication of condition."
  },
  {
    "question": "A tubeless tyre is a tyre:\n\n1. which requires solid or branched wheels\n2. whose valve can be sheared in sudden accelerations\n3. whose mounting rim must be flawless\n4. which requires no rim protection between rim flange and tire removing device\n5. which does not burst in the event of a tyre puncture\n6. which eliminates internal friction between the tube and the tyre\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 5, 6."
  },
  {
    "question": "Internal leakage in a hydraulic system will cause :",
    "feedback": "an increased fluid temperature."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a possible pneumatic source in a single engine piston aircraft?",
    "feedback": "Compressor pump"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some emergency exits must be equipped with devices so as to help the occupants to get out and reach the ground if their threshold is at a height above the ground greater than:",
    "feedback": "6 ft, aeroplane on the ground, landing gear extended."
  },
  {
    "question": "What energy source is used to drive the turbines of turbocharged airplane?",
    "feedback": "Engine exhaust gases."
  },
  {
    "question": "The oil supply to gas turbine engine bearings is maintained in the event of the main oil filter becoming clogged by:",
    "feedback": "differential pressure opening the bypass valve of the main oil filter"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ignition occurs in each cylinder of an four-stroke engine (TDC = Top Dead Center)",
    "feedback": "before TDC at each second crankshaft revolution."
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of separate shielding of electrical wires within a cable bundle (wire harness) is to ......",
    "feedback": "Feedback not found"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the most frequent used materials in a monocoque or semi-monocoque structure?",
    "feedback": "Aluminium or magnesium alloy."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which components do a semi-monocoque fuselage consists of?",
    "feedback": "A stressed skin structure in which the skin is supported by a lightweight framework, such as longerons, stringers and formers."
  },
  {
    "question": "Fuel pumps submerged in the fuel tanks of a large aeroplane are:",
    "feedback": "centrifugal low pressure type pumps"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an auto-brake system is correct?",
    "feedback": "On most aeroplanes the auto-brake system provides a constant deceleration during landing on a dry runway (ignoring possible transition effects when the system begins to function)"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the combustion gases pass through a turbine the :",
    "feedback": "pressure drops."
  },
  {
    "question": "With reference to stringers, they:",
    "feedback": "integrate the strains due to pressurisation to which the skin is subjected and convert them into a tensile stress."
  },
  {
    "question": "The fuselage structure of a pressurised transport aeroplane is an example of a:",
    "feedback": "semi-monocoque structure"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the functions of a gas turbine engine subsonic intake is to:",
    "feedback": "decrease airflow velocity"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the density of JET A1?",
    "feedback": "0.8 kg/l."
  },
  {
    "question": "The engine component between station numbers 4 and 5 is the:",
    "feedback": "combustion chamber"
  },
  {
    "question": "The air-cycle cooling system produces cold air by:",
    "feedback": "Extracting heat energy across an expansion turbine."
  },
  {
    "question": "The crank assembly consists of",
    "feedback": "crankshaft, connecting rods and pistons."
  },
  {
    "question": "Landing gear torque links are used to:",
    "feedback": "prevent rotation of the landing gear piston in the oleo strut."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a compressor stage of a jet engine, the sequence is:",
    "feedback": "rotor - stator"
  },
  {
    "question": "The correct order of decreasing freezing points of the three mentioned fuels is:",
    "feedback": "Jet A, Jet A-1, Jet B"
  },
  {
    "question": "The state in which the breathing oxygen for the cockpit of jet transport aeroplanes is stored is :",
    "feedback": "Gaseous."
  },
  {
    "question": "If a gas-filled detector becomes broken, the result will be ....",
    "feedback": "a decrease in pressure, causing a loop fault indication"
  },
  {
    "question": "When applying precautionary carburettor heating on a reciprocating engine with a fixed pitch propeller:",
    "feedback": "the mixture becomes richer"
  },
  {
    "question": "On large aeroplanes equipped with power brakes, the main source of power is derived from :",
    "feedback": "the aeroplane's hydraulic system."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about a reaction turbine are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The pressure rises across the nozzle guide vanes\n2) The pressure drops across the rotor blades",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Auto-brakes are disengaged:",
    "feedback": "by the pilot."
  },
  {
    "question": "The principle of \"on condition\" maintenance is based on the ....",
    "feedback": "monitoring of critical parameters of a component or a piece of equipment and its replacement if a limit value is exceeded"
  },
  {
    "question": "The compression ratio of a piston engine is a ratio of:",
    "feedback": "volumes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Describe how stress in aircraft parts is calculated:",
    "feedback": "force / area"
  },
  {
    "question": "With which system is differential control associated?",
    "feedback": "Aileron system."
  },
  {
    "question": "Check the following statements with regard to certification specifications issued by EASA:\n1) CS-23 applies to Normal, Utility, Aerobatic and Commuter Aeroplanes2) CS-27 applies to Large Aeroplanes",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is not correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "An operator observes that the aircraft's metal parts have deteriorated over time. What is the measure to avoid further deterioration?",
    "feedback": "Replace the metal parts with plastic or composite materials"
  },
  {
    "question": "The complete combustion within a detonating cylinder of a piston engine:",
    "feedback": "takes less time than combustion without detonation"
  },
  {
    "question": "The common used symbol of resistance is",
    "feedback": "R and is measured in ohms."
  },
  {
    "question": "An airplane whose maximum approved passenger seating configuration is 31 to 60 seats must be equipped with at least:",
    "feedback": "2 hand fire-extinguishers conveniently located in the passenger compartment."
  },
  {
    "question": "When changing power on engines equipped with a constant speed propeller, engine overboost is avoided by:",
    "feedback": "increasing the RPM before increasing the manifold pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a pressurized aircraft, the first-aid (therapeutic) oxygen is designed to:",
    "feedback": "give medical assistance to passengers with pathological respiratory disorders."
  },
  {
    "question": "A 3 phase AC generator has 3 separate stator windings spaced at :",
    "feedback": "120°."
  },
  {
    "question": "Trimming of aileron and rudder in an irreversible flight control system:",
    "feedback": "is achieved by adjusting the \"zero force point\" of the feel system"
  },
  {
    "question": "For a fan jet engine the bypass ratio is the:",
    "feedback": "cold air mass flow divided by the hot air mass flow"
  },
  {
    "question": "A flight control surface actuator is said to be \"irreversible\" when:",
    "feedback": "there is no feedback to the pilot's controls of the aerodynamic forces acting on the control surface"
  },
  {
    "question": "Generally, when the fire handle of the fire-extinguishing system of an aircraft is pulled, the effects are :\n\n1) opening of the air bleed valves and HP valves on the engine concerned\n2) arming of the extinguishing system\n3) immediate discharge of extinguishing agent\n4) deactivation of the electric generators\n\nThe combination that regroups all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where are cooling fins usually located on air-cooled engines?",
    "feedback": "Cylinder head, cylinder barrel, and inside the piston head."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is meant by a wet sump engine?",
    "feedback": "One that carries its oil supply in the engine itself."
  },
  {
    "question": "Assuming the initiating cause is removed, which of these statements about resetting are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) A fuse is not resettable\n2) A circuit breaker is resettable",
    "feedback": "1) is correct 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the regulator of a flight deck oxygen system is to:\n\n1. decrease oxygen pressure from 1800 PSI (in the bottles) down to about 50-75 PSI (low pressure system)\n2. supply 100 % oxygen\n3. supply diluted oxygen\n4. supply oxygen on demand\n5. supply oxygen at positive pressure\n6. trigger the continuous cabin altitude warning at 10000 ft cabin altitude\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "On most large aeroplanes, the cabin pressure is controlled by regulating the:",
    "feedback": "airflow leaving the cabin"
  },
  {
    "question": "When baffles are fitted to aircraft fuel tanks, the purpose is to:",
    "feedback": "prevent surge of fuel within the tank during flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "What brakes are used on modern transport aircraft?",
    "feedback": "Multi disc brakes."
  },
  {
    "question": "What may happen during a continuous climb with a mixture setting fully rich?",
    "feedback": "Fouling of the spark plugs"
  },
  {
    "question": "In order to prevent/eliminate ice buildups on a pitot tube on light aircraft, the pilot can use",
    "feedback": "a heating system consisting of an electric resistor inside the tube itself."
  },
  {
    "question": "An anti-skid system will:",
    "feedback": "reduce brake pressure to slower turning wheels."
  },
  {
    "question": "For aircraft equipped with a landing gear anti retract latch, which of these statements is correct?",
    "feedback": "This system can be overridden under specified conditions"
  },
  {
    "question": "The global output of a piston engine is of:\n(global output = Thermal energy corresponding to the available shaft/power over the total thermal energy produced).",
    "feedback": "0.30"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the diagram showing the power output of a piston engine as a function of mixture ratio, best economy on lean side of the EGT top is shown at:",
    "feedback": "point 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an impulse turbine are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The pressure rises across the nozzle guide vanes\n2) The pressure drops across the rotor blades",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which logic gate is represented by symbol 3?",
    "feedback": "NOT"
  },
  {
    "question": "A turbine stage is represented by:",
    "feedback": "figure 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "During the ram recovery process in a gas turbine engine subsonic intake, the:",
    "feedback": "flow velocity decreases"
  },
  {
    "question": "Modern lithium batteries have high energy density cells. If these are exposed to mechanical or thermal abuse, this can result in strong ....",
    "feedback": "electric currents, leading to a thermal runaway"
  },
  {
    "question": "On most transport aircraft, the low pressure pumps of the fuel system are:",
    "feedback": "centrifugal pumps, driven by an electric motor."
  },
  {
    "question": "The advantages of fly-by-wire control are:\n1) reduction of the electric and hydraulic power required to operate the control surfaces2) lesser sensivity to lightning strike3) direct and indirect weight saving through simplification of systems4) immunity to different interfering signals5) improvement of piloting quality throughout the flight envelope\nThe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ice protection system currently used for most large turboprop aeroplanes is a(n):",
    "feedback": "Pneumatic system with inflatable boots"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the control surface that rotates an aeroplane about its \nlongitudinal or roll axis?",
    "feedback": "The ailerons"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ignition system of a running piston engine receives electrical energy from:",
    "feedback": "rotating permanent magnets"
  },
  {
    "question": "The indication of the fire detection systems is performed by a:",
    "feedback": "warning light and a warning bell."
  },
  {
    "question": "In normal operation the maximum cabin altitude for transport aeroplanes is:",
    "feedback": "8000 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Smoke detectors fitted on transport aircraft are of the following type :",
    "feedback": "optical or ionization"
  },
  {
    "question": "Aircraft fuel tanks should be checked for water:",
    "feedback": "before the first flight of the day"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about a reaction turbine are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The pressure rises across the nozzle guide vanes\n2) The pressure remains constant across the rotor blades",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Select the correct statement(s) regarding fly-by-wire control systems (FBW):\n1) In certain aircraft, the control takeover facility available to the pilot is provided by means of priority buttons (PB) on the sidestick controls2) Contradictory movement of the flying controls may be demanded by the pilots through dual inputs",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is not correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is increased?\n\n1) The gas generator speed remains constant\n2) The EGT decreases",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "The flexible take-off mode:\n\n1) can be used only on new engines\n2) reduces engine wear\n3) can be used in situations where take-off can be executed without the need for full engine power\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an aircraft electrical system where AC generators are not paralleled mounted, the changover relay allows :",
    "feedback": "power supply to the faulty AC generators busbar."
  },
  {
    "question": "A twin engine turbofan aircraft uses dual channel FADEC. Which of the following statements correctly describes the operation of each channel?",
    "feedback": "One channel is in command, and the other channel can take over in case of fault or failure"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a risk associated with lithium-ion batteries?",
    "feedback": "Self-ignition when the charging process is not properly controlled"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about structural design principles are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) In structural design, fail safe implies the structure will never fail\n2) A safe life structure is based on a declared time period or number of cycles",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ventilation system in a fuel tank:",
    "feedback": "prevents low pressure or excessive overpressure in the tank"
  },
  {
    "question": "The bypass ratio:\n\n1) is the ratio of the volume of air passing through the inlet to that through the HP compressor\n2) can be determined from the inlet air mass flow and the bypass mass flow",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Generator paralleling through busbars is done to assure that",
    "feedback": "different consumers can be fed from different sources."
  },
  {
    "question": "In the diagram (not to scale), the balancing force required on the left hand side is ....",
    "feedback": "100 N"
  },
  {
    "question": "Environmental system: in the air refrigeration unit, the water separation unit is placed:",
    "feedback": "after the cooling turbine."
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft has two accumulators, each of 12 V with 40 Ah capacity, connected in series. The resultant unit has:",
    "feedback": "a voltage of 24 V and a capacity of 40 Ah."
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens to air pressure as it passes over the turbine blades known as reaction blades (i) and to the velocity of the air as it passes over the nozzle guide vanes (ii)?",
    "feedback": "(i) decrease; (ii) increase"
  },
  {
    "question": "A tubeless tyre has :  1- a built-in-air tube. 2- no built-in-air tube. 3- a crossed side casing. 4- a radial side casing.  The combination of correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 4."
  },
  {
    "question": "On four-stroke piston engines, the theoretical valve and ignition settings are readjusted in order to increase the:",
    "feedback": "overall efficiency"
  },
  {
    "question": "In accordance with EASA AIR OPS, when an airplane flies at over 25000 ft, the total number of oxygen dispensing units and supply terminals must be at least greater than the number of:",
    "feedback": "seats by 10 %."
  },
  {
    "question": "The mixture controller of a carburettor:",
    "feedback": "varies the fuel supply to the main discharge nozzle"
  },
  {
    "question": "A hydraulic shuttle valve ....",
    "feedback": "enables an alternate supply to operate an actuator"
  },
  {
    "question": "A \"hung start\" is the failure of an engine to accelerate to its normal idle speed. It may be caused by:",
    "feedback": "an attempt to ignite the fuel before the engine has been accelerated sufficiently by the starter."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which controls act together in a V-tail aircraft?",
    "feedback": "The stick in one axis and the rudder pedals"
  },
  {
    "question": "A diffuser reduces the velocity of gas entering the combustion chamber. The purpose of this is to ......",
    "feedback": "increase the gas pressure, to ensure that the combustion does not stop"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a bootstrap air conditioning system what is the correct sequence describing the routing of the air?",
    "feedback": "Goes through the compressor, secondary heat exchanger, turbine."
  },
  {
    "question": "Severe compressor stall can be indicated, amongst others, by:",
    "feedback": "a rise in turbine gas temperature (TGT) and a change in vibration level."
  },
  {
    "question": "The pressurising function of the pressurising and dump valve in a gas turbine engine fuel system is:",
    "feedback": "to admit fuel to the nozzles only if the fuel pressure is high enough for sufficient atomisation"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main turbine/compressor engine shaft(s) is (are) normally mounted on:",
    "feedback": "ball bearings and roller bearings."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about a reaction turbine are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The pressure rises across the nozzle guide vanes\n2) The pressure rises across the rotor blades",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "In flight, the cabin air for large jet transport aeroplanes is usually supplied by:",
    "feedback": "engine compressors"
  },
  {
    "question": "To prevent flutter on control surfaces it helps to",
    "feedback": "balance the surface"
  },
  {
    "question": "What unit of measurement is used to express electrical current?",
    "feedback": "Ampère"
  },
  {
    "question": "Essential information whether to use the engine anti-ice system or not, is?",
    "feedback": "Reported temperature when on ground, and ram air temperature when airborne."
  },
  {
    "question": "Different fluids in an aircraft system can potentially present a corrosion hazard. Which fluids may be hazardous if spilt or leaked onto the aircraft structure?\n1) Hydraulic fluids2) Engine oils3) Chemical toilet fluids4) De-icing fluids5) Fluids carried as dangerous goods for transportation",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "The disadvantages of axial flow compressors compared to centrifugal flow compressors are :\n\n1 - expensive to manufacture\n2 - limited airflow\n3 - greater risk of rupturing\n4 - limited compression ratio",
    "feedback": "1 - 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The chemical oxygen generator supplies oxygen for about :",
    "feedback": "15 minutes."
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.\n\nOn ground, external power (EXT PWR) can be used to feed the AC BUS 2 when:\n(NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumend to remain open)",
    "feedback": "C1.2 and C2.2 are closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Control surface flutter can be avoided by:\n\n1) a high torsional stiffness of the structure\n2) a low torsional stiffness of the structure\n3) locating a balancing mass in front of the control hinge\n4) locating a balancing mass behind the control hinge\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about fire-extinguishing agents are correct or incorrect?\n1) The fire extinguishing effect of Halon is based on suppressing the chemical reaction of a fire\n2) Compared with other extinguishing agents Halon is very effective in suppressing fires",
    "feedback": "1) is correct,2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a subsonic convergent duct the:",
    "feedback": "pressure decreases, velocity increases and temperature decreases"
  },
  {
    "question": "At supersonic speeds, the airflow at the gas turbine engine inlet will be:",
    "feedback": "reduced to subsonic speed."
  },
  {
    "question": "The rotor blades of an axial compressor of a gas turbine engine are often mounted on a disk or drum using a \"loose fit\" because this:",
    "feedback": "limits damage to the blades due to vibration"
  },
  {
    "question": "The thrust reversers of jet engines may use clamshell doors in order to:",
    "feedback": "change the direction of the exhaust gas stream."
  },
  {
    "question": "For safe life designed structural components:\n\n1) there is more than one load carrying component\n2) one load carrying component is sufficient for a given load, provided it is strong enough\n3) the component is removed at the end of the calculated life time or number of cycles\n4) the design is based on the principle of redundancy of components\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a wing bends downwards, aileron flutter might occur if the aileron deflects:",
    "feedback": "upwards, because the location of the aileron centre of gravity lies behind the hinge line"
  },
  {
    "question": "Real load sharing in a parallel AC system is achieved by :",
    "feedback": "adjusting the torque on each generator rotor via the CSD unit."
  },
  {
    "question": "The axial compressor of a gas turbine engine usually has more stages than its driving turbine because:",
    "feedback": "the power output of a turbine stage is higher than the power consumption of a compressor stage"
  },
  {
    "question": "Different types of hydraulic fluids can be mixed. This statement is:",
    "feedback": "false."
  },
  {
    "question": "If piston A has an area of 2 cm² and piston B has an area of 10 cm², when piston B moves down by 5 cm, how far will piston A have moved?",
    "feedback": "25 cm"
  },
  {
    "question": "A complex hydraulic system may pressurise the oil reservoir by means of bleed air from the engines, this is",
    "feedback": "To secure reliable oil supply to the hydraulic pumps."
  },
  {
    "question": "If a hydraulic pump switch light \"LOW\" caption illuminates, the cause is assumed to be:",
    "feedback": "pump output pressure low."
  },
  {
    "question": "From the options given below, select three systems that could be provided with air from the pneumatic system of a piston engine:\n1) Gyroscopic instruments2) Pitot/static instruments3) Cabin heating4) Anti-ice5) Electrical generation6) Hydraulic pump",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.\n\nGEN 1 can be used to feed the DC BAT BUS:\n(NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumend to remain open)",
    "feedback": "via AC BUS 1 and DC BUS 2, when C1.1, C 3.1, C3.2, C5.3 and C7.4 are closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ohm's law claims the following",
    "feedback": "the current flowing in a circuit is proportional to the applied voltage, and inverse \nproportional to the resistance through which the current flows."
  },
  {
    "question": "A rectifier is a unit that",
    "feedback": "produces a DC output from AC input."
  },
  {
    "question": "The very rapid magnetic field changes (flux) around the primary coil in a magneto are accomplished by the:",
    "feedback": "contact breaker points opening."
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of the swirl vanes around the fuel nozzles is to:\n\n1)  increase air pressure at the fuel nozzles\n2)  reduce the average axial flow speed in order to stabilise the flame front\n3)  generate a swirl of incoming air to enhance mixing of the fuel with air\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "A CSD of an AC generator may be disconnected in flight. The primary reason(s) for disconnection are :",
    "feedback": "low oil pressure and/or high oil temperature of the generator drive."
  },
  {
    "question": "Fire from electrical components due to static electricity build up is minimized by:",
    "feedback": "bonding."
  },
  {
    "question": "The torque of an aeroplane engine can be measured at the:",
    "feedback": "gear box which is located between the engine and the propeller."
  },
  {
    "question": "For a reciprocating engine, fuel/air ratio or mixture is the ratio between the:",
    "feedback": "mass of fuel and mass of air entering the cylinder."
  },
  {
    "question": "The most common overload protection device used in aircraft is:",
    "feedback": "Circuit breakers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Shuttle valves will automatically:",
    "feedback": "Switch hydraulically operated units to the most appropriate pressure supply."
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider a gas turbine engine. The diffuser of a centrifugal-flow compressor stage creates a ......",
    "feedback": "divergent area at the impeller exit to reduce the air velocity and increase the air pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "In accordance with EASA AIR OPS, the minimum requirement for the survival oxygen needed to supply 100 % of the passengers during and following an emergency descent is:",
    "feedback": "10 minutes or the entire flight time where the cabin pressure altitude is above 15000 ft, whichever is the greater."
  },
  {
    "question": "A burst red disc at the atmospheric outlet of a fixed fire extinguisher system indicates:",
    "feedback": "the system is unserviceable."
  },
  {
    "question": "On a multi-engined aircraft a fire detection system includes :",
    "feedback": "a warning light for each engine and a single alarm bell common to all engines"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an auto-brake system is correct?",
    "feedback": "The achievable deceleration levels of full manual braking and the auto-brake RTO mode are the same"
  },
  {
    "question": "The octane rating of a fuel indicates its ....",
    "feedback": "resistance to detonation"
  },
  {
    "question": "A gaseous loop fire detector works as follows:\nAn increase in surrounding temperature will ......",
    "feedback": "increase the pressure inside a gas-filled tube, when reaching the upper threshold, a pressure switch will activate the alarm"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which areas of an aircraft need to be protected against ice accretion?",
    "feedback": "Wing leading edges, engine intakes, and pitot tubes"
  },
  {
    "question": "A magnetic plug in an engine oil system can be used to:",
    "feedback": "collect ferrous particles"
  },
  {
    "question": "As regards the Generator Control Unit (GCU) of an AC generator, it can be said that:\n\n1. The GCU controls the AC generator voltage\n2. Modern GCUs are provided with a permanent indication to record the failure\n3. All the commands originating from the control panel are applied via the GCU, except dog clutch release\n4. The Auxiliary Power Unit (APU) provides the excitation of the AC generator as soon as the APU starts up\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of an accelerator pump in the carburettor of a piston engine is to:",
    "feedback": "temporarily enrich the mixture by pumping more fuel into the induction system during rapid throttle movements"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of first-aid portable oxygen bottles?",
    "feedback": "They are used for passengers who, for physiological reasons, might require oxygen following a cabin depressurisation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What unit of measurement is used to express frequency?",
    "feedback": "Hertz"
  },
  {
    "question": "A turbofan engine with an inlet air mass flow of 1000 kg/s and a HP compressor mass flow of 111 kg/s has a bypass ratio of:",
    "feedback": "8.01"
  },
  {
    "question": "The wing of an aircraft in flight, powered by engines located under the wing, is subjected to a bending moment which causes its leading edge, from the wing root to the wing tip, to operate in:",
    "feedback": "compression, then in tension."
  },
  {
    "question": "To protect against excessive system pressure, a hydraulic system usually incorporates:",
    "feedback": "a high pressure relief valve"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about fire-extinguishing agents are correct or incorrect?\n1) The fire extinguishing effect of Halon is mainly based on cooling when the agent exhausts via a venturi during discharge\n2) Compared with other extinguishing agents Halon is very effective in suppressing fires",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does a gaseous loop fire detector work? An increase in surrounding temperature will ....",
    "feedback": "increase the pressure inside a gas-filled tube. When reaching the upper threshold, a pressure switch will activate the alarm"
  },
  {
    "question": "The primary purpose of the reverse current relay is to :",
    "feedback": "Prevent the battery from delivering current to the generator."
  },
  {
    "question": "The most widely used electrical frequency in aircraft is :",
    "feedback": "400 Hz."
  },
  {
    "question": "An EGT (Exhaust Gas Temperature) indicator for a piston engine is used to :",
    "feedback": "assist the pilot to settle correct mixture."
  },
  {
    "question": "The Auxiliary Power Unit (APU) has its own AC generator which:",
    "feedback": "supplies the aircraft with three-phase 115-200 V, 400 Hz AC."
  },
  {
    "question": "Whilst in level cruising flight, an aeroplane with a pressurised cabin experiences a malfunction of the pressure controller. If the cabin vertical speed indicator reads 200 ft/min rate of descent:",
    "feedback": "the differential pressure will rise to its maximum value, thus causing the safety relief valves to open"
  },
  {
    "question": "An accumulator in a hydraulic system will :",
    "feedback": "store fluid under pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "When the AC voltage across a capacitor is kept constant and the frequency is increased, the current through the capacitor will:",
    "feedback": "increase."
  },
  {
    "question": "When leaning the mixture for the most economic cruise fuel flow, excessive leaning will cause :",
    "feedback": "high cylinder head and exhaust gas temperature"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a fuel sample appears cloudy, this is:",
    "feedback": "an indication of water in the fuel."
  },
  {
    "question": "A public transport passengers aircraft, with a seating configuration of more than  61 seats, must have in its passenger compartment(s), at least 3 portable fire-extinguishers including:",
    "feedback": "2 halon fire-extinguishers."
  },
  {
    "question": "The FADEC of a gas turbine engine consists of:",
    "feedback": "an electronic engine control unit and its peripherals (fuel metering, actuators, electrical wiring, sensors..)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is one of the new features provided by Full Authority Digital Engine Control (FADEC) in modern piston aircraft engines?",
    "feedback": "Ignition timing control"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the following bleed air \"consumers\", which system requires the largest supply?",
    "feedback": "Air conditioning system."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct about the flow in a divergent jet engine inlet?\n\n1) The speed increases in flow direction\n2) The total pressure increases in flow direction",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an auto-brake system (ABS) is correct?",
    "feedback": "An armed auto-brake system at low settings will start operating with a certain time delay after main wheel touchdown"
  },
  {
    "question": "Prolonged running at low rpm may have an adverse effect on the efficiency of the:",
    "feedback": "sparking plugs."
  },
  {
    "question": "A framework of truss type fuselage is used in:",
    "feedback": "light training aircraft mainly"
  },
  {
    "question": "The engine component between station numbers 3 and 4 is the:",
    "feedback": "HP compressor"
  },
  {
    "question": "A battery capacity of 10 Ah means that the battery can provide:",
    "feedback": "5 Amperes for 2 hours"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about a gust lock system are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) There is no need for a gust lock on irreversible flight controls\n2) Manual flight controls should have a gust lock",
    "feedback": "1) is correct 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The reason for having a low pressure fuel-cooled oil cooler in a recirculatory type oil system is to:",
    "feedback": "cool the oil and heat the fuel."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which describes best the component (2) in a main landing gear assembly?",
    "feedback": "Main leg oleo strut"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"Conditioned\" air is air that has:",
    "feedback": "been controled in respect of temperature and pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "The Number in the graph that shows the axle is:",
    "feedback": "5"
  },
  {
    "question": "In  some aircraft, there is a protection device to avoid the landing gear being inadvertently retracted on the ground.  It consists of :",
    "feedback": "A latch located in the landing gear lever."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the functions of the lubricating oil in an aircraft engine?",
    "feedback": "Lubricates, seals, cools, cleans and prevents corrosion."
  },
  {
    "question": "A hydraulically operated nose gear steering cylinder has at least two functions. The first is to allow the pilot to steer the aeroplane, and the second function is?",
    "feedback": "Shimmy dampener."
  },
  {
    "question": "The anti-ice or de-icing system which is mostly used for the wings of modern turboprop aeroplanes is :",
    "feedback": "Pneumatic boots."
  },
  {
    "question": "A fan stage of a ducted-fan turbine is driven by:",
    "feedback": "the low pressure turbine"
  },
  {
    "question": "An electrical connection from the fly-by-wire (FWB) system to the left-hand aileron has become broken in flight. How can the pilot maintain directional control?",
    "feedback": "The FBW flight control laws may enter a degraded mode, however roll authority can still be maintained through use of the wing spoilers and right-hand aileron"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the purposes of compressor bleed valves is to:",
    "feedback": "decrease the airflow across the rear compressor stages, whilst that across the early stages is increased"
  },
  {
    "question": "Axial piston pumps are often used in hydraulic systems due to:",
    "feedback": "their ability to produce high pressure when required but can be off loaded to reduce power consumption."
  },
  {
    "question": "A turbo compressor air conditioning system (bootstrap system) includes two heat exchangers; the primary exchanger (P) and the secondary exchanger (S).\n\nThe functions of these heat exchangers are as follows:",
    "feedback": "P: precools the engine bleed air\nS: cools air behind the pack's compressor"
  },
  {
    "question": "The logic symbol shown represents (assuming positive logic) :",
    "feedback": "AND-Gate"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the engine is shut down after flight, this is accomplished by:",
    "feedback": "placing the mixture control in idle cut-off"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Formula for the ideal Transformator",
    "feedback": "ü= U1/U2"
  },
  {
    "question": "An airplane whose maximum approved passenger seating configuration is greater than 60 seats must be equipped with at least:",
    "feedback": "3 HALON 1211 fire-extinguishers."
  },
  {
    "question": "Loss of efficiency of turbine blade tips are minimized by:",
    "feedback": "blade tip shrouds."
  },
  {
    "question": "The expression \"primary flight controls\" applies to the:\n\n1) stabiliser\n2) rudder\n3) speed brake\n4) aileron\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The connection in parallel of two 12 volt/40 amp hours batteries will create a unit with the following characteristics:",
    "feedback": "12 volts, 80 ampere-hours."
  },
  {
    "question": "How do differential ailerons work?",
    "feedback": "Equalize the drag on up-going and down-going wings."
  },
  {
    "question": "Assess the statements given below regarding Halon fire extinguishers:\n1) When released from a venturi under pressure, Halon acts a a cooling agent2) Halon should only be used with caution, as it is highly corrosive on aluminium components",
    "feedback": "1) and 2) are incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Significant torsion effects in a wing during flight can be caused by:",
    "feedback": "aileron deflection"
  },
  {
    "question": "The conditions to be met to activate a shunt generator are:\n\n1) presence of a permanent field\n2) closed electrical circuit\n3) generator terminals short-circuited\n4) minimum rotation speed\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.\n\nGEN 2 can be used to feed the AC BUS 2, when:\n(NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumend to remain open)",
    "feedback": "C1.4 is closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements is correct regarding piston engine induction system icing?",
    "feedback": "Ice accretion affects both fuel injection systems and engines equipped with carburettors"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct about the flow in a divergent (subsonic) gas turbine engine intake?\n\n1) The dynamic pressure increases in flow direction\n2) The static temperature increases in flow direction",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The control surface that rotates the aircraft about its longitudinal axis is/are the",
    "feedback": "Ailerons."
  },
  {
    "question": "Static dischargers :\n\n1. are used to set all the parts of the airframe to the same electrical potential\n2. are placed on wing and tail tips to facilitate electrical discharge\n3. are used to reset the electrostatic potential of the aircraft to a value approximating 0 volts\n4. are located on wing and tail tips to reduce interference with the on-board radiocommunication systems to a minimum\n5. limit the risks of transfer of electrical charges between the aircraft and the electrified clouds\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "2,4,5."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a gas turbine combustion chamber:",
    "feedback": "secondary air is required for cooling of the inner casing"
  },
  {
    "question": "Variations in mixture ratios for carburettors are achieved by the adjustment of:",
    "feedback": "fuel flow"
  },
  {
    "question": "The expression \"secondary flight control\" applies to the:  1) trimmable stabiliser 2) rudder 3) speed brake 4) aileron  The combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The diagram shown represents a jet fuel system. The fuel-flow measurement is carried out :",
    "feedback": "after high pressure valve (item 4)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is true concerning the effect of the application of carburetor heat?",
    "feedback": "It reduces the density of air entering the carburetor, thus enriching the fuel/air mixture"
  },
  {
    "question": "Maximum power output and low mass of aircraft hydraulic systems can be achieved with:",
    "feedback": "high system pressure and low volume flow."
  },
  {
    "question": "A gas turbine engine turbine section may employ active clearance control:",
    "feedback": "to provide enhanced clearances between the blade tips and the casing."
  },
  {
    "question": "Both gas turbine and piston engines use a cycle made up of induction, compression, combustion and exhaust phases. Which of these statements about a piston engine are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The process in a piston engine is continuous\n2) Theoretically the combustion occurs at constant pressure",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Compressor surge during engine acceleration is prevented by:",
    "feedback": "controlling the fuel flow"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot normally uses the propeller autofeather system during :",
    "feedback": "Take-off and landing."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a turn, which scenario will cause the most bending moment at the wing root?",
    "feedback": "High Zero Fuel Mass, low fuel"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of a diffuser (compensating jet) is to:",
    "feedback": "maintain a constant mixture in a piston engine at low and high  power settings"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is it dangerous to use oxygen in the vicinity of oil or grease?",
    "feedback": "The interaction of oil-based products and oxygen creates a fire hazard"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cabin altitude is the:",
    "feedback": "cabin pressure expressed as altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "The use of igniters in a gas turbine engine is required:\n\n1) throughout the operating range of the engine\n2) during engine acceleration\n3) for in-flight relights\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Strainers are normally fitted:",
    "feedback": "in the return line."
  },
  {
    "question": "On board present aircraft, the batteries used are mainly Cadmium-Nickel. Their advantages are: 1. low risk of thermal runaway 2. high internal resistance, hence higher power 3. good charging and discharging capability at high rating 4. wider permissible temperature range 5. good storage capability 6. sturdiness owing to its metal casing 7. the electrolyte density remains unchanged during charging. The combination of correct statement is:",
    "feedback": "3, 4, 5, 6"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a diluter demand regulator in an oxygen system is to:",
    "feedback": "deliver oxygen flow when inhaling."
  },
  {
    "question": "An airplane whose maximum approved passenger seating configuration is 301 to 400 seats must be equipped with at least:",
    "feedback": "5 hand fire-extinguishers conveniently located in the passenger compartment."
  },
  {
    "question": "An axial flow compressor consist of two main parts:",
    "feedback": "rotor and stator"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following factors would be likely to increase the possibility of detonation occuring within a piston engine ?",
    "feedback": "using too lean a fuel/air mixture ratio"
  },
  {
    "question": "Assuming a constant speed drive (CSD) fault is indicated, the CSD should be disconnected :",
    "feedback": "provided the engine is running"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cabin heating in a large jet transport aeroplane is obtained from:",
    "feedback": "hot air bled from the compressors"
  },
  {
    "question": "With reference to structural stress, fatigue means damage to the structure, as a result of:",
    "feedback": "Load cycles."
  },
  {
    "question": "The control of free turbine engines on turboprops, is accomplished by:\n\n- a propeller control lever used to select:\n 1 - propeller RPM\n 2 - turbine temperature\n 3 - turbine RPM\n\n- a fuel control lever used to select:\n 4 - propeller RPM\n 5 - torque\n 6 - turbine temperature\n \nThe combination which regroups all of the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1 - 5 - 6"
  },
  {
    "question": "Both gas turbine and piston engines use a cycle made up of induction, compression, combustion and exhaust phases. Which of these statements about a piston engine are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The process in a piston engine is intermittent\n2) Theoretically the combustion occurs at constant pressure",
    "feedback": "1) is correct 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Select the correct answer from the following statements:\n1) When a DC generator is supplied with a current at the commutator, the armature rotates. The DC generator is converted into a DC motor2) When a DC generator is driven by the engine, an EMF will be induced. No current will flow when it is connected to a closed circuit",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is not correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The thrust of a turbo-jet, at the selection of full power :\n\n1 - is proportional to the mass of air expelled by the engine and to the velocity change imparted to it.\n2 - is obtained by pressure of the exhaust gas on the ambient air\n3 - is equivalent to zero mechanical power since the aeroplane is not moving\n4 - is independant of the outside air temperature\n\nThe combination which regroups all of the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1 - 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "If air is tapped from a gas turbine HP compressor, the effect on the engine pressure ratio (EPR) and the exhaust gas temperature (EGT) is that :",
    "feedback": "EPR decreases and EGT increases."
  },
  {
    "question": "If the pressure in the cabin tends to become lower than the outside ambient air pressure the :",
    "feedback": "negative pressure relief valve will open."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a compressor stage, if the axial air velocity increases more than the rotor blade velocity the:",
    "feedback": "stall margin increases"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of \"engine trending\" for a gas turbine engine is ....",
    "feedback": "to measure and analyse the current engine parameters and performance so that the future life of the engine can be predicted"
  },
  {
    "question": "Thermal plugs are installed in:",
    "feedback": "wheel rims."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about chemical oxygen generators are correct or incorrect?\n1) Chemical oxygen generators are used to supply the cockpit system\n2) The oxygen supply of chemical oxygen generators, once activated, cannot be switched off",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Two of the effects acting on a propeller are ATM and CTM. Which one tends to turn the propeller blade in which direction?",
    "feedback": "CTM to fine, ATM to coarse."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a four-stroke cycle aircraft engine, when does the ignition event take place?",
    "feedback": "Before the piston reaches TDC on compression stroke."
  },
  {
    "question": "An impulse turbine is a turbine in which the expansion takes place:",
    "feedback": "fully in the stator."
  },
  {
    "question": "As manifold pressure increases in a reciprocating engine the",
    "feedback": "density of air in the cylinder increases."
  },
  {
    "question": "On large transport category aircraft, trailing edge flaps are normally powered ......",
    "feedback": "hydraulically with electrical backup"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the first aid oxygen is to:",
    "feedback": "provide some passengers with additional respiratory assistance after an emergency descent following a depressurization."
  },
  {
    "question": "The station numbers before and after the HP turbine are:",
    "feedback": "5 and 6"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pneumatic de-ice system should be operated ..",
    "feedback": "When there is approximately 1,5 cm of ice on leading edges."
  },
  {
    "question": "The electronic engine control unit of a gas turbine engine FADEC uses data from:\n\n1) aircraft systems\n2) cockpit display units\n3) its own engine sensors\n4) electronic engine control units of the other engine(s)\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "An engine turbocharger is said to be \"ground boosted\"when it",
    "feedback": "maintains a manifold pressure above sea level conditions"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the main oil filter of a gas turbine engine becomes clogged, oil to the main bearings is still assured:",
    "feedback": "because the oil filter bypass valve opens"
  },
  {
    "question": "EPR can be defined as the ratio of:",
    "feedback": "the total turbine outlet pressure to the total compressor inlet pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a multi-cell lithium battery, one cell sets on fire. Which of the following is likely to happen?",
    "feedback": "The fire will spread to other cells within the battery"
  },
  {
    "question": "To ensure correct load sharing between AC generators operating in parallel :",
    "feedback": "both real an reactive loads must be matched."
  },
  {
    "question": "In an electric motor:\n1) Mechanical torque is proportional to the voltage x current and is inversely proportional to the generated field2) Mechanical torque is proportional to the voltage divided by the current and is proportional to the generated magnetic field",
    "feedback": "1) and 2) are not correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The capacity of a battery is the:",
    "feedback": "amount of Ampere-hour (Ah) that a fully charged battery can supply"
  },
  {
    "question": "An airplane has a maximum approved passenger seating configuration of 61 seats and 2 galleys located on the main passenger compartment. No cargo compartment is accessible to crew members in flight. According to EASA AIR OPS, the minimum total number of hand fire extinguishers on board is:",
    "feedback": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Most of the cabin pressurisation systems have two modes of operation:",
    "feedback": "The isobaric mode and the constant pressure differential mode."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a turbo compressor air conditioning system (bootstrap system), the purpose of the heat exchangers is to:",
    "feedback": "cool the bleed air in front of and behind the compressor of the air cycle machine"
  },
  {
    "question": "A circuit breaker has to be able to withstand a transient overcurrent due to ......",
    "feedback": "electrical motors (inductive loads)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ice protection for propellers of most turboprop aeroplanes works:",
    "feedback": "electrically"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Ram Air Turbine (RAT) provides emergency hydraulic power for :",
    "feedback": "flight controls in the event of loss of engine driven hydraulic power."
  },
  {
    "question": "The power output of a piston engine without turbocharging increases with decreasing altitude in standard atmosphere at constant MAP and RPM because of the:",
    "feedback": "increase of the air density behind the throttle valve"
  },
  {
    "question": "The most unfavourable conditions for adequate inlet air flow of a turbofan engine are:",
    "feedback": "maximum take-off thrust, zero forward speed and strong crosswind conditions"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"Frequency wild\" in relation to a AC generation system means the generator :",
    "feedback": "output frequency varies with engine speed."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the approximate thermal efficiency of a four-stroke engine?",
    "feedback": "30 %"
  },
  {
    "question": "The low pressure filter is prevented from being blocked by ice particles in the fuel by:",
    "feedback": "pre heating the fuel."
  },
  {
    "question": "What unit of measurement is used to express electrical work?",
    "feedback": "Joule"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is the correct statement regarding a large aircraft fitted with both inboard and outboard ailerons?",
    "feedback": "The outboard ailerons are typically used only when the flaps are extended."
  },
  {
    "question": "In the pneumatic supply system of a modern transport aircraft, the air pressure is regulated. This pressure regulation occurs just before the manifold by the :",
    "feedback": "low pressure bleed air valve"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the diagram showing the power output of a piston engine as a function of mixture ratio the mixture becomes richer when moving from:",
    "feedback": "point 4 to point 1"
  },
  {
    "question": "The vapour pressure of aviation gasoline is",
    "feedback": "lower than the vapor pressure of automotive gasoline."
  },
  {
    "question": "Main cabin temperature is:",
    "feedback": "controlled automatically, or by flight crew selection."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a bootstrap cooling system the supply air is:",
    "feedback": "compressed, passed through a secondary heat exchanger, and then across an expansion turbine."
  },
  {
    "question": "A piston engine compression ratio is the ratio of the :",
    "feedback": "total volume to the clearance volume."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct about the flow in a divergent (subsonic) gas turbine engine intake?\n\n1) The speed remains constant in flow direction\n2) The total pressure decreases in flow direction",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Derated or reduced take-offs save engine life primarily due to:",
    "feedback": "reduced low cycle fatigue damage"
  },
  {
    "question": "The feathering pump of a hydraulic variable-pitch propeller:",
    "feedback": "is an electrically driven oil pump, which supplies the propeller with pressure oil, when the engine is inoperative."
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a shuttle valve is to:",
    "feedback": "Supply an operating unit with the most appropriate system pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "Primary airflow is routed",
    "feedback": "to the fuel nozzle area for combustion"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the pilot operates the mixture control, what is being accomplished?",
    "feedback": "he changes the air to fuel ratio"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pressure for the braking system of a modern aircraft originates from:",
    "feedback": "the main hydraulic system."
  },
  {
    "question": "Integral fuel tanks ....",
    "feedback": "comprise a portion of the aircraft structure, which has been sealed to form a fuel tank"
  },
  {
    "question": "A battery capacity of 5 Ah means that the battery can provide:",
    "feedback": "5 Amperes for 1 hour"
  },
  {
    "question": "The colour of Aviation gasoline 100 LL is:",
    "feedback": "blue"
  },
  {
    "question": "Direct current generators in multi-engine aircraft are connected:",
    "feedback": "in parallel to provide maximum power"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an auto-brake system is correct?",
    "feedback": "When using manual braking during taxiing, the auto-brake system remains armed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following materials is a semi conductor?",
    "feedback": "Si"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a distributor in an ignition system of a piston engine is to distribute:",
    "feedback": "secondary current to the sparking plugs."
  },
  {
    "question": "A cantilever wing is:",
    "feedback": "a wing attached to the fuselage at the wing root only"
  },
  {
    "question": "Determine the main functions of the fuel system.",
    "feedback": "Provision of fuel to the engines, appropriate pressure to enable engine operation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding a jet engine:\n\n1) The maximum thrust decreases as the pressure altitude increases\n2) The specific fuel consumption is inversely proportional to pressure altitude, at constant TAS",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "The advantages of a gaseous oxygen source for the passenger cabin are :\n\n1. a greater autonomy,\n2. no risk of explosion,\n3. reversible functioning,\n4. easy storage and maintenance,\n5. possibility to regulate flow.\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "The component that converts the hydraulic pressure into a linear motion is called:",
    "feedback": "An actuator or jack"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the system depicted in the graph, which of these statements about this fuel system is correct?",
    "feedback": "It is impossible to transfer fuel from the centre tank to the wing tanks"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of a scissor (torsion link) in a landing gear is to:",
    "feedback": "prevent any rotation of the oleo strut in the landing gear shock absorber."
  },
  {
    "question": "Select the correct statement from the answers below:",
    "feedback": "Stress and strain are always present in an aircraft structure, both, when parked and during manoevring"
  },
  {
    "question": "The engine component between station numbers 3 and 4 is the:",
    "feedback": "HP compressor"
  },
  {
    "question": "Loads on the cylindrical part of the fuselage during pressurisation are carried by the:",
    "feedback": "skin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an auto-brake system (ABS) is correct?",
    "feedback": "When the pilot forgets to arm the auto-brake system, this will not generate a take-off warning during take-off"
  },
  {
    "question": "The heat for the anti-icing system of a turbofan engine intake is provided by:",
    "feedback": "bleed air from the HP compressor"
  },
  {
    "question": "An under-inflated tyre will:",
    "feedback": "experience increased wear at the shoulders"
  },
  {
    "question": "The station numbers before and after the exhaust are:",
    "feedback": "7 and 8"
  },
  {
    "question": "In case of smoke in the cockpit, the crew oxygen regulator must be set to:",
    "feedback": "100%"
  },
  {
    "question": "A force is applied to an object. When the force is removed, the object returns to its original form. This phenomenon is called ......",
    "feedback": "elastic deformation"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the maximum certified altitude of an aeroplane is limited by the pressurised cabin, this limitation is due to the maximum:",
    "feedback": "positive cabin differential pressure at maximum cabin altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of an accumulator in a hydraulic brake system is:",
    "feedback": "to supply a limited amount of brake energy in the event of failure of the hydraulic system normally supplying the brakes."
  },
  {
    "question": "Carburettor heating is generally not used with take-off and climb power settings because of the:",
    "feedback": "loss of power and possible detonation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about rudder pedal nose wheel steering of a jet transport areoplane is correct?",
    "feedback": "Rudder pedal nose wheel steering offers a smaller maximum deflection of the nose wheel than a tiller nose wheel steering"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider a scenario where all the hydraulic systems on a particular Fly-By-Wire aircraft have failed. Movement of the normal pilot's flight control input (sidestick) will result in:",
    "feedback": "A lack of any response in the control surface"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the worst case scenario if a thermal runaway occurs?",
    "feedback": "Fire"
  },
  {
    "question": "The compressor blades in a rotating gas turbine engine are held in position by:",
    "feedback": "the mountings and the resultant of aerodynamic and centrifugal forces"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which part of the main landing gear is shown by the number 1?",
    "feedback": "Torsion link"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram:\nChoose the answer which correctly states the outputs from the logic circuit shown:",
    "feedback": "Both, C and D are equal to zero."
  },
  {
    "question": "A pressure relieve valve in an oil system that does not seat correctly could result in:",
    "feedback": "low oil pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "The amount of fuel that flows through the carburettor is directly controlled by",
    "feedback": "Airflow through the carburettor venturi."
  },
  {
    "question": "The Maximum Zero Fuel Weight:\n1 Is a limitation set by regulation.\n2 Is designed for a maximum load factor.\n3 Is due to the maximum bending moment at wing root.\n4 Requires to empty external tanks first.\n5 Requires to empty internal tanks first.\nThe correct combinaison of true statements is :",
    "feedback": "1,2,3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The station numbers before and after the HP compressor are:",
    "feedback": "3 and 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is decreased?  1) The propeller blade angle remains constant 2) The free power turbine speed decreases",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "The generator of the auxiliary power unit (APU) can only be used when:",
    "feedback": "no other power source is feeding the bus bars"
  },
  {
    "question": "Real load sharing in a parallel AC system is achieved by :",
    "feedback": "automatic adjustment of the torque on each generator rotor via the CSD unit."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct about the flow in a divergent (subsonic) gas turbine engine intake?\n\n1) The static pressure decreases in flow direction\n2) The total temperature remains constant in flow direction",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Discounting the possibility of leak, the level in a hydraulic reservoir will :",
    "feedback": "fluctuate with jack displacement and accumulator pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "The cabin rate of descent:",
    "feedback": "results in cabin pressure increase."
  },
  {
    "question": "The reasons for disconnecting a constant speed drive (CSD) of an AC generator in flight are:\n\n1) low oil pressure in the CSD\n2) slight variation about the normal operating frequency\n3) high oil temperature in the CSD\n4) excessive variation of output voltage\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The tubes in the de-ice boots are usually inflated alternately. Why?",
    "feedback": "Because alternate inflation of de-ice boot tubes keeps disturbance of the airflow to minimum."
  },
  {
    "question": "The capacity of an accumulator is:",
    "feedback": "the quantity of electricity that the battery can supply during discharge."
  },
  {
    "question": "An artificial feel unit system:",
    "feedback": "must be mounted in parallel on an irreversible servo-control unit."
  },
  {
    "question": "In the event of an engine fire:",
    "feedback": "the fuel supply is isolated from the engine by pilot action"
  },
  {
    "question": "Flat rated jet engines are designed to provide constant maximum take-off thrust up to a certain level of:",
    "feedback": "ambient temperature"
  },
  {
    "question": "The frequency of the current provided by an alternator depends on...",
    "feedback": "its rotation speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main purpose of a Constant Speed Drive unit is to:",
    "feedback": "maintain a constant frequency."
  },
  {
    "question": "If two identical batteries are connected in parallel:",
    "feedback": "the output voltage will remain the same and the capacity expressed in ampere hours will double"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of an accelerator pump in the carburettor of a piston engine is to:",
    "feedback": "enable proper functioning of a piston engine during rapid throttle advance"
  },
  {
    "question": "On-board electrical systems are protected against faults of the following type:\n\n1) AC generator over-voltage\n2) AC generator under-voltage\n3) over-current\n4) over-speed\n5) under-frequency\n6) undue vibration of AC generators\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1,2,3,4,5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Fuel stored in aircraft tanks will accumulate moisture.The most pratical way to minimize this when a plane is used every day or so is to :",
    "feedback": "keep tanks topped off when plane is not in use"
  },
  {
    "question": "The internal geometry of a turbofan intake for a subsonic commerical aeroplane is:",
    "feedback": "divergent in order to reduce airflow velocity and increase static pressure in front of the fan"
  },
  {
    "question": "The air in a piston engine turbocharger enters the centrifugal compressor at:",
    "feedback": "the eye of the impeller and leaves it almost at a tangent to the periphery"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pre-ignition refers to the condition that may arise when :",
    "feedback": "the mixture is ignited by abnormal conditions within the cylinder before the spark occurs at the plug"
  },
  {
    "question": "Oil metering valves are normally fitted to the engine lubrication system  to ensure:",
    "feedback": "a balanced supply of oil is provided for the front bearing."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of this circuit diagram symbols represents a three phase star connection?",
    "feedback": "D"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pressurising a fuselage causes the following load in the skin:",
    "feedback": "Tension"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cabin pressurisation is regulated by the :",
    "feedback": "cabin outflow valve(s)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of stringers, used in fuselage construction, is to:",
    "feedback": "assist the skin to withstand longitudinal compressive loads."
  },
  {
    "question": "An asymmetric loading (p-factor) on the propeller exists ..",
    "feedback": "If the aeroplane has a large angle of attack."
  },
  {
    "question": "Windshield heating of a transport aeroplane is:",
    "feedback": "essential to improve the strength of the cockpit windows"
  },
  {
    "question": "On most transport jet aeroplane, the low pressure pumps of the fuel system are supplied with electric power of the following type:",
    "feedback": "115 V AC"
  },
  {
    "question": "In order to get the optimum efficiency of a piston engine, the positions of the intake and exhaust valve just after the power stroke are:",
    "feedback": "intake valve closed and exhaust valve open."
  },
  {
    "question": "If an engine fails to stop with the magneto switch in OFF position, the cause may be :",
    "feedback": "excessive carbon formation in cylinder head."
  },
  {
    "question": "A \"hydraulic fuse\" will:",
    "feedback": "Detect a sufficient pressure drop across itself, or a specified volume of fluid passing through itself, and then shut off the flow of fluid to prevent the system of emptying itself."
  },
  {
    "question": "The voltage of a fully charged lead-acid battery cell under no electrical load is :",
    "feedback": "2,2 volts."
  },
  {
    "question": "The gearbox of a fanjet engine is driven by:",
    "feedback": "The high pressure shaft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about compressor stall are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) A compressor stall is most likely to occur in a compressor designed for a high pressure ratio operating at low RPM\n2) A compressor stall is most likely to occur when the air flow stagnates in the front stages of the compressor",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of the drain valve in a gas turbine combustion chamber is to:",
    "feedback": "remove unburned fuel from the combustion chamber"
  },
  {
    "question": "The swirl assembly, or vanes, of a combustion chamber are fitted to generate a rotary motion to the:",
    "feedback": "air in the inlet to the primary combustion zone."
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a chip detector in the oil system of an engine/gearbox is to indicate that:",
    "feedback": "there are metal particles in the oil"
  },
  {
    "question": "Viscosity is:",
    "feedback": "the tendency of a liquid or gas to resist flow."
  },
  {
    "question": "Oxygen regulators used by the flight crew for most commercial jet aircraft are of the",
    "feedback": "Diluter demand type"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of the flap load relief system is to ....",
    "feedback": "protect against overload at certain flap positions"
  },
  {
    "question": "The type of hydraulic oil used in most large aeroplanes is:",
    "feedback": "synthetic oil"
  },
  {
    "question": "In very cold weather, a slightly higher than normal engine oil pressure during startup:",
    "feedback": "is acceptable, if it decreases after startup"
  },
  {
    "question": "Temperature regulation of an air conditioning system:",
    "feedback": "is automatically controlled by sensing the output temperature from the control valve in relation to the temperature set on the pilot's control panel."
  },
  {
    "question": "The conditions under which you obtain the highest engine power are :",
    "feedback": "cold and dry air at high pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "If a gas turbine engine fuel/oil heat exchanger is located downstream of the HP fuel pump, internal leakage of the heat exchanger will cause the oil level to:",
    "feedback": "rise"
  },
  {
    "question": "On an airplane, the Krueger flaps are:",
    "feedback": "leading edge flaps close to the wing root"
  },
  {
    "question": "The engine component between station numbers 3 and 4 is the:",
    "feedback": "HP compressor"
  },
  {
    "question": "Power plant fire extinguishers are operated by:",
    "feedback": "an electrically fired cartridge rupturing a seal in the head of the bottle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct about the flow in a divergent (subsonic) gas turbine engine intake?\n\n1) The speed remains constant in flow direction\n2) The total pressure remains constant in flow direction",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is located in box 4?",
    "feedback": "Transformer Rectifier Unit"
  },
  {
    "question": "The reason for using inverters in an electrical system is ..",
    "feedback": "To change DC into AC."
  },
  {
    "question": "According CS 25 the allowable quantitative average failure probability per flight hour for a major failure should be on the order of (^means to the power of):",
    "feedback": "between 10^-5 and 10^-7 (remote)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about fire-extinguishing agents are correct or incorrect?\n1) The fire extinguishing effect of Halon is mainly based on cooling when the agent exhausts via a venturi during discharge\n2) Halon should be used with caution because it is highly corrosive particularly for aluminium",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "The fuel cross-feed system:",
    "feedback": "allows feeding of any engine from any fuel tank"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cabin air for large aeroplanes is usually taken from:",
    "feedback": "the HP compressor."
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a battery protection unit is generally to isolate the battery:\n\n1 - from the bus when the battery charge is deemed satisfactory\n2 - when there is a battery overheat condition\n3 - in case of an internal short circuit\n4 - in case of a fault on the ground power unit\n\nThe combination which regroups all of the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1 - 2 -3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which factors can lead to thermal runaway of a lithium-ion battery?",
    "feedback": "Internal short circuit, external short circuit, overcharging, excessive currents due to rapid charging"
  },
  {
    "question": "Both gas turbine and piston engines use a cycle made up of induction, compression, combustion and exhaust phases. Which of these statements about a piston engine are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The process in a piston engine is intermittent\n2) Theoretically the combustion occurs at constant volume",
    "feedback": "1) is correct 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is true with respect to heating of pitot and static sensors on IFR certified aircraft?",
    "feedback": "Pitot tubes are always provided with a heater, while static ports may also be heated."
  },
  {
    "question": "The water separator of an air-conditioning unit is located at the cooling unit :",
    "feedback": "outlet and uses a centrifugal process."
  },
  {
    "question": "Control on the ground for small aeroplanes is provided by steering the nose wheel through connections to the rudder pedals, but large aeroplanes have normally:",
    "feedback": "Hydraulic power steering."
  },
  {
    "question": "Modern aircraft can have many different types of circuit breakers (CB).  Generally speaking a CB is an electric component that:",
    "feedback": "When excessive current flows through it, it will open the circuit, but a closed circuit \nis regained when it is reset."
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram:\nChoose the answer which correctly states the outputs from the logic circuit shown:",
    "feedback": "Both, C and D are equal to 0."
  },
  {
    "question": "In the event of an engine failure during flight the blades of a constant speed propeller in a single engine aeroplane not fitted with a feathering system tend to move:",
    "feedback": "towards the smallest blade angle by centrifugal twisting moment and/or spring force"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the pack cooling fans in the air conditioning system is to:",
    "feedback": "supply the heat exchangers with cooling air during slow flights and ground operation"
  },
  {
    "question": "The elements specifically protected against icing on transport aircraft are:\n\n1) engine air intake and pod.\n2) front glass shield.\n3) radome.\n4) pitot tubes and waste water exhaust masts.\n5) leading edge of wing.\n6) cabin windows.\n7) trailing edge of wings.\n8) electronic equipment compartment.\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "In accordance with EASA AIR OPS, an airplane whose maximum take-off mass exceeds 5 700 kg or whose maximum approved passenger seating configuration is greater than 9 seats and smaller than 200 seats must be equipped with a:",
    "feedback": "crash axe or a crow-bar in the pilot compartment."
  },
  {
    "question": "The pilot may be prevented from retracting the landing gear whilst the aircraft is on the ground by:",
    "feedback": "the electrical control system being routed through the weight on wheels switch."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct?\n\n1) The freezing point for Jet A is at a lower temperature than that for Jet B\n2) The flash point for Jet A is at a higher temperature than that for Jet B",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are visual identifiers of corrosion which a pilot must look out for during the pre-flight inspection?\n1) Powdering2) Paint discolouration3) Rust4) Etching5) Pitting6) Cracking7) Flaking",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.\n\nOn ground, APU GEN can be used to feed the AC BUS 1, when:\n(NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumend to remain open)",
    "feedback": "C1.3 and C2.1 are closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can wing bending moments be reduced in flight?",
    "feedback": "By using aileron up float and using the fuel in the wings last."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an auto-brake system are correct or incorrect? 1) Proper functioning of an auto-brake system requires proper functioning of the anti-skid system 2) In the RTO mode maximum anti-skid braking is applied",
    "feedback": "1) is correct,2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pressure regulator is used in a hydraulic system:",
    "feedback": "in conjunction with a constant delivery type pump."
  },
  {
    "question": "A \"Zener\" diode is used for:",
    "feedback": "voltage stabilisation"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a bleed air anti-icing system, the areas that are typically heated are:",
    "feedback": "the leading edges of the wings and empennage."
  },
  {
    "question": "The air-conditioning pack of a present-day aircraft consists of several components: these include two heat exchangers; the primary exchanger (P) and the secondary exchanger (S).\nThe functions of these heat exchangers are as follows:",
    "feedback": "P: precools the engine bleed air\nS: reduces the temperature of the air from the primary exchanger or from the pack's compressor."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which part of an aircraft's fuselage gives it its aerodynamic shape?",
    "feedback": "Skin"
  },
  {
    "question": "The following constructions for aircraft windows are given. What is the correct order with regard to decreasing stability, starting with the strongest (left to right, top to bottom)?",
    "feedback": "b, c, d, a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the system depicted in the graph, which of these statements about cross feeding is correct?",
    "feedback": "Fuel supply is possible from any tank to any main engine"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a bootstrap cooling system, the bleed air is compressed to:",
    "feedback": "ensure a sufficient temperature drop in the secondary heat exchanger"
  },
  {
    "question": "Maximum Zero Fuel Mass MZFM is:",
    "feedback": "the total maximum permissible mass of the aircraft without usable fuel."
  },
  {
    "question": "The principle of on condition maintenance is based on the:",
    "feedback": "monitoring of critical parameters and the replacement of parts if a limit value is exceeded"
  },
  {
    "question": "The type of hydraulic oil used in modern hydraulic systems is:",
    "feedback": "synthetic oil"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider a DC motor under load. With increasing load the motor will slow down, allowing the armature current to (1) .... . As a result the motor's torque will (2) .... .",
    "feedback": "(1) increase, (2) increase"
  },
  {
    "question": "On some large aeroplanes the fuel tanks may be vented through:",
    "feedback": "air intakes on the underside of the wing"
  },
  {
    "question": "The horsepower developed in the cylinders of a reciprocating engine is known as the",
    "feedback": "indicated horsepower."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the correct procedure to deal with a lithium battery fire?",
    "feedback": "Isolate the burning/heating device, address the fire itself by using halon fire extinguishers to extinguish the open flame and water (or non-alcoholic liquid) to cool the device down"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding a fly-by-wire control system (FBW):",
    "feedback": "A FBW flight control system comprises various electrical signalling paths, including, amongst others, pilot input to computer, computer to flight control surfaces, and feedback from aircraft response to computer"
  },
  {
    "question": "The middle layer of a heated windscreen is made of:",
    "feedback": "soft polycarbonate."
  },
  {
    "question": "On a typical gas turbine engine aircraft, the pneumatic air bleed system uses air supplied from the engine ....",
    "feedback": "compressor"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the components which give the fuselage its cross-sectional shape?",
    "feedback": "Frames and bulkheads"
  },
  {
    "question": "A continuous loop detector is used in a:",
    "feedback": "fire detection system"
  },
  {
    "question": "Igniter plugs are fitted:",
    "feedback": "to just two or three combustion chambers."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of a \"relief valve\" in the hydraulic system?",
    "feedback": "Make sure that the pressure does not exceed the max. permitted pressure in the system."
  },
  {
    "question": "Batteries are rated in :",
    "feedback": "Amperes x hours."
  },
  {
    "question": "A public transport aircraft has a cruising altitude of FL 390. It is fitted with individual oxygen masks for the passengers. In the event of depressurisation, the masks must be automatically released before the cabin pressure altitude exceeds:",
    "feedback": "14000 ft."
  },
  {
    "question": "The main purpose of the mixture control is to:",
    "feedback": "adjust the fuel flow to obtain the proper fuel/air ratio"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a commercial transport aeroplane the landing normal gear operating system is usually:",
    "feedback": "Hydraulically driven"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which part of the main landing gear is shown by the number 5?",
    "feedback": "Axle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is decreased?\n\n1) The propeller blade angle decreases\n2) The free power turbine speed remains constant",
    "feedback": "1) is correct,2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Maximum exhaust gas temperature (EGT) of a piston engine is theoretically associated with a:",
    "feedback": "fuel to air ratio of 1:15"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is/are correct?\n1) An autobrake system will either apply maximum braking (RTO or MAX) or result in a given rate of deceleration2) The amount of braking applied by an autobrake system may be affected by the use of reverse thrust and/or by a slippery runway",
    "feedback": "1) and 2) are correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "When comparing petrol engines with diesel engines, petrol engines:",
    "feedback": "have a lower compression ratio than diesel engines"
  },
  {
    "question": "Specific fuel consumption is defined as the :",
    "feedback": "mass of fuel required to produce unit power for unit time."
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the feathering stop on a variable pitch propeller is to:",
    "feedback": "prevent the propeller blades from moving beyond the feather position."
  },
  {
    "question": "Above what flight level must one pilot wear an oxygen mask at all times during commercial flight?",
    "feedback": "410."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements concerning a sandwich structural part are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The main function of the core material is to stabilise the covering sheets\n2) A sandwich structural part is well suited for absorbing concentrated loads",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "A twin-spool engine with a bypass mass flow of 250 kg/s and HP compressor mass flow of 250 kg/s has a bypass ratio of ....",
    "feedback": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "The difference between (1) a fuse and (2) a circuit breaker is:",
    "feedback": "(1)not resettable, (2)resettable."
  },
  {
    "question": "A fly-by-wire (FBW) system ......",
    "feedback": "uses computers to process the pilot's/autopilot's flight control inputs, and sends corresponding electrical signals to the flight control surfaces' actuators"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an auto-brake system (ABS) is correct?",
    "feedback": "For a given touchdown speed (GS) on a dry runway without use of reverse thrust the stopping distance is solely dependent on the selected ABS setting and independent of weight"
  },
  {
    "question": "During engine start, variable inlet guide vanes will be:",
    "feedback": "fully closed."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about rudder pedal nose wheel steering is correct?",
    "feedback": "Rudder pedal nose wheel steering provides a smaller deflection of the nose wheel than hand wheel steering (tiller)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Both gas turbine and piston engines use a cycle made up of induction, compression, combustion and exhaust phases. Which of these statements about a gas turbine are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The process in a gas turbine is continuous\n2) Theoretically the combustion occurs at constant pressure",
    "feedback": "1) is correct 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "A gas turbine engine, on starting, accelerates to a figure below idle rpm and fails to accelerate above that values. This indicates:",
    "feedback": "a hung start."
  },
  {
    "question": "At what speed must a crankshaft turn if each cylinder of a four-stroke cycle engine \nis to be fired 800 times a minute?",
    "feedback": "1600 RPM."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement about the storage capacity of a battery is correct?",
    "feedback": "5 Ah means that the battery will deliver 5 amperes for 1 hour"
  },
  {
    "question": "The boots of a pneumatic de-icing system are normally made of:",
    "feedback": "neoprene rubber"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the reason for heating flight deck windows?",
    "feedback": "To protect the windows against bird strike damage and ice formation"
  },
  {
    "question": "'Fail safe construction' is :",
    "feedback": "A type of construction in which the load is carried by other components if a part of the structure fails."
  },
  {
    "question": "The following thrust formula is given:F = m * (Δv) + A * ΔP\nWhich answer states the correct explanation of the two parts of the right side of the formula?",
    "feedback": "m * (Δv): the thrust caused by the acceleration of the air mass flowA * ΔP: the thrust caused by the pressure difference at the exhaust"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a conductor cuts the flux of a magnetic field :",
    "feedback": "an electromotive force (EMF) is induced in the conductor."
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a hydraulic fuse is to:",
    "feedback": "prevent leakage if the hydraulic line breaks."
  },
  {
    "question": "When checking the fuel for possible water content, the presence of water will be indicated by:",
    "feedback": "The water will be found at the bottom of the strainer, because it is heavier than the fuel."
  },
  {
    "question": "The fuel temperature, at which, under standard conditions, the vapour ignites in contact with a flame and extinguishes immediately, is the:",
    "feedback": "flash point"
  },
  {
    "question": "An anti-retract latch blocks the landing gear lever when:",
    "feedback": "an aircraft is on the ground"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about a gust lock system are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) A gust lock can be used in flight to reduce the effects of turbulence\n2) Reversible flight controls should have a gust lock",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "What engine controls are usually available on the flight deck for a FADEC-controlled piston engine?",
    "feedback": "A FADEC computer, an engine mode selector, engine master selectors, and power levers providing digital inputs"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about trimming in a irreversible flight control system of a conventional aeroplane are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The zero force position of the control column does not change when using the elevator trim\n2) The zero force position of the control wheel does not change when using the aileron trim",
    "feedback": "1) is correct 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Fuel dump systems are required:",
    "feedback": "on all transport category aircraft where the Maximum Take-Off Weight (MTWO) is significant higher than the Maximum Landing Weight (MLW)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Labyrinth seals in the lubrication system of a gas turbine engine are designed to provide a seal that is:",
    "feedback": "not completely tight, allowing some movement between rotating and static parts"
  },
  {
    "question": "A battery capacity of 100 Ah means that the battery can provide:",
    "feedback": "10 Amperes for 10 hours"
  },
  {
    "question": "AC generators operated in parallel must have the same:",
    "feedback": "voltage and phase"
  },
  {
    "question": "One advantage of having three instead of two spools in some high-bypass turbofan engines is that:",
    "feedback": "fewer variable stator vanes and variable inlet guide vanes are required to prevent compressor stall at low rotor speeds"
  },
  {
    "question": "With regard to a twin spool turbofan, an abortive start (hung start) will result in:",
    "feedback": "N2 speed stabilising at a lower than normal RPM and a subsequent increase in EGT"
  },
  {
    "question": "Assuming an accumulator is pre-charged to 1000 psi and the hydraulic system is pressurised to 1500 psi, the accumulator gauge will read :",
    "feedback": "1500 psi."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a multiple combustion chamber system:",
    "feedback": "two or sometimes three igniter plugs are fitted to the system."
  },
  {
    "question": "When excessively leaning the mixture for a better fuel economy, but still on the rich side of the peak EGT, the following engine parameter(s) may exceed their normal operating range:",
    "feedback": "cylinder head and exhaust gas temperatures"
  },
  {
    "question": "Excessive priming of a piston engine should be avoided because:\n\n1) it drains the carburettor float chamber\n2) the risk of engine fire\n3) the risk of flooding the engine\n4) it fouls the spark plugs\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The accurate method of removing snow and ice that has accumulated on the aircraft during parking, is;",
    "feedback": "De-ice all surfaces with approved de-ice fluid"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the battery ammeter shows \"+24\" the battery:",
    "feedback": "is being charged with 24 A"
  },
  {
    "question": "In transport aircraft equipped with retractable landing gear, there must be a clear indication to the pilot:",
    "feedback": "whenever the landing gear position is not consistent with landing gear selector lever position"
  },
  {
    "question": "A flight control surface actuator is said to be \"reversible\" when:",
    "feedback": "there is feedback to the pilot's controls of the aerodynamic forces acting on the control surface"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft whose maximum approved configuration for passenger seats is 200 seats must be equipped with:",
    "feedback": "3 manual fire-extinguishers in the cabin."
  },
  {
    "question": "A pressurized aeroplane is flying at FL 370 and experiences a rapid decompression.  Which of the following statements about the oxygen system is correct?",
    "feedback": "After an automatic mask presentation for cabin crew and passengers, oxygen starts to flow only after the mask has been firmly pulled"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a  hydraulic system, the reservoir is pressurised in order to:",
    "feedback": "prevent pump cavitation"
  },
  {
    "question": "One indication of inadequate electrical bonding of aircraft components may be:",
    "feedback": "static noise on the radio."
  },
  {
    "question": "The advantages of grounding the negative pole of the aircraft structure are:\n\n1. Weight saving\n2. Easy fault detection\n3. Increase of short-circuit risk\n4. Reduction of short-circuit risk\n5. Circuits are not single-wired lines\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a gas turbine engine, the propelling jet is generated by ....",
    "feedback": "expansion of hot gases resulting in a conversion of potential energy (pressure) into kinetic energy (velocity)"
  },
  {
    "question": "In accordance with EASA AIR OPS, 10 % of the passengers in a non-pressurized airplane must have an oxygen supply reserve for the entire flight time when the cabin altitude pressure is greater than:",
    "feedback": "10000 ft but not exceeding 13000 ft minus 30 minutes."
  },
  {
    "question": "The pilot's control input in a fly-by-wire system is ......",
    "feedback": "converted into an electrical signal and linked via a computer to the flight control surface"
  },
  {
    "question": "In theory, the fatigue life limit is reached sooner when an aircraft makes on a daily basis:",
    "feedback": "Six flights of 30 minutes each"
  },
  {
    "question": "State the advantages of the variable displacement hydraulic pump compared to the\nconstant displacement pump.",
    "feedback": "The variable displacement pump adjusts the fluid pumped to the fluid required, and the pump thereby adjusts the pressure output itself, and it moves fluid only when necessary."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the basic principle of a fully manual flight control system?",
    "feedback": "The flight control surfaces are connected to the flight deck controls by means of mechanical links only."
  },
  {
    "question": "The two deformation modes that cause wing flutter are:",
    "feedback": "torsion and bending."
  },
  {
    "question": "An impulse coupling is inhibited at higher than normal rotational starting speeds by:",
    "feedback": "centrifugal force"
  },
  {
    "question": "For a given type of oil, the oil viscosity depends on the:",
    "feedback": "oil temperature."
  },
  {
    "question": "Assume a constant speed DC generator providing a constant output voltage. If the electrical load increases, the voltage regulator will :",
    "feedback": "increase the intensity of the excitation current."
  },
  {
    "question": "On modern jet aeroplanes, where is the compressed air supply obtained from?",
    "feedback": "From the HP compressor lower stages (plus higher stages as required)"
  },
  {
    "question": "An exit is considered to be out of service when the following elements are inoperative the:\n\n1. external door opening mechanism\n2. internal door opening mechanism\n3. door opening aid device\n4. open door locking system\n5. auxiliary means of evacuation\n6. emergency lighting\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
    "feedback": "Short term overcurrent is normal"
  },
  {
    "question": "A constant speed drive (CSD) that has been disconnected in flight",
    "feedback": "can be reset only on the ground after engine shut-down"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the AC generators are connected in parallel, the reactive loads are balanced by means of the:",
    "feedback": "excitation current"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about composite and metal structures are correct or incorrect?  1) In a structural component with given dimensions constructed of composite materials, the strength is the same in all directions 2) Composite materials enable structures with lower strength/weight ratio than metal structures",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is increased?\n\n1) The HP spool speed increases\n2) The EGT increases",
    "feedback": "1) is correct,2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "A non-cantilever wing is:",
    "feedback": "a wing supported by braces or a strut connected to the fuselage"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an anti-skid system are correct or incorrect?\n1) The \"regulation of slip ratio\" function of an anti-skid system ensures optimum braking performance\n2) Careful brake application by the pilot in case of anti-skid failure can achieve the same performance as a properly functioning anti-skid system",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the attached diagram, which image represents the effect of more than one single force?",
    "feedback": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "What advantage has an airplane fitted with an electric-pneumatic system compared to one fitted having a bleed air source?",
    "feedback": "Longer range due to increased efficiency"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a free turbine engine:",
    "feedback": "there is no mechanical connection between the compressor and the power output shaft."
  },
  {
    "question": "The main purpose of an exhaust section of a turbojet is to....",
    "feedback": "direct the flow rearward and ensure a high final velocity of the hot gases"
  },
  {
    "question": "One reason to fit a tip shroud to a turbine blade is to:",
    "feedback": "increase turbine efficiency"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the electrical load of an AC generator providing a constant output voltage increases, the voltage regulator will:",
    "feedback": "increase the excitation current"
  },
  {
    "question": "Most high-bypass (unmixed) turbofan engines are equipped with a cold exhaust reverser (fan reverser) only in order to:",
    "feedback": "save costs and mass at the expense of a reduction in available reverse thrust"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider a variable pitch propeller operating in a low RPM/high pitch condition. To select reverse thrust, the ....",
    "feedback": "power lever is moved to the reverse position and the blades move from low pitch directly to reverse pitch"
  },
  {
    "question": "The failure of an anti-skid system:",
    "feedback": "always increases the minimum braking distance irrespective of runway condition"
  },
  {
    "question": "Filters in hydraulic systems often incorporate pop out indicators to:",
    "feedback": "warn of an impending by-pass situation."
  },
  {
    "question": "In the event of the normal hydraulic pressure regulation system failure, the following component is fitted in a typical hydraulic system:",
    "feedback": "a pressure relief valve."
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the purposes of the bleed valves fitted to axial flow compressors is to:",
    "feedback": "prevents stall of the LP compressor"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a gas turbine engine, with take-off thrust set, when the bypass mass is 888kg/sec and the core engine passing mass is 111kg/sec: What is the bypass ratio (BPR)?",
    "feedback": "8:1"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft whose maximum approved configuration for passenger seats is 10 seats must be equipped with:",
    "feedback": "one fire extinguisher only in the cockpit."
  },
  {
    "question": "Emergency extension of landing gear systems can be performed:\n\n1) with compressed CO2\n2) with compressed nitrogen\n3) with compressed oxygen\n4) by mechanical/manual means\n5) by free fall\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "The moving part in an AC generator is usually referred to as the :",
    "feedback": "rotor."
  },
  {
    "question": "Obvious disadvantages using Lead-Acid batteries in airplanes are:",
    "feedback": "They have insufficient capacity and are volume and weight inefficient."
  },
  {
    "question": "The wing anti-ice system has to protect",
    "feedback": "the leading edge or the slats, either partially or completely"
  },
  {
    "question": "In very cold weather, the pilot notices during startup, a slightly higher than normal oil pressure.\nThis higher pressure :",
    "feedback": "is normal, if it decreases after startup."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an auto-brake system are correct or incorrect?\n1) An auto-brake system can function properly, even when the anti-skid system is inoperative\n2) In the RTO mode a maximum constant deceleration is applied",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an aircraft equipped with a float-type carburetor and a constant-speed propeller, carburetor icing would probably first be detected by:",
    "feedback": "A drop in manifold pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "The illumination of the green lamp indicator corresponding to a landing gear means that the landing gear is :",
    "feedback": "locked-down."
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding a jet engine:\n\n1) The maximum thrust remains constant as the pressure altitude decreases\n2) The specific fuel consumption remains constant as the pressure altitude decreases at constant TAS",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "On an aircraft, the Krueger flap is a:",
    "feedback": "leading edge flap close to the wing root"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the cabin pressure controller in the automatic mode is to:\n\n1) control cabin altitude\n2) controle rate of change of cabin altitude\n3) limit differential pressure\n4) ventilate the cabin\n5) keep a constant differential pressure throughout all the phases of flight\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an anti-skid system are correct or incorrect?\n1) The \"regulation of slip ratio\" function of an anti-skid system ensures optimum braking performance\n2) Careful brake application by the pilot in case of anti-skid failure can never achieve the same performance as a properly functioning anti-skid system",
    "feedback": "1) is correct,2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding an FBW FCS (flight control system):",
    "feedback": "If an FCS system fails the remaining FCS systems will ensure operation of different control surfaces, providing full system redundancy. Thus, several control surfaces are required for each aircraft axis."
  },
  {
    "question": "The DILUTE position of a cockpit oxygen mask should not be used when:",
    "feedback": "when there is smoke in the cockpit"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a battery is almost fully discharged there is a tendency for the :",
    "feedback": "voltage to decrease even under light loads"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is a correct unit, used for hydraulic pressure?",
    "feedback": "PSI"
  },
  {
    "question": "If an abortive start (hung start) occurs when starting a gas turbine engine, the correct action is to:",
    "feedback": "shut down the engine"
  },
  {
    "question": "If an engine fails to start, the high pressure cock should be closed:",
    "feedback": "as soon as failure to start becomes apparent."
  },
  {
    "question": "The reason for a double switch on the elevator trim is:",
    "feedback": "to reduce the probability of a trim runaway"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the cabin pressure controller, in the automatic mode, is to perform the following functions:\n\n1. control of cabin altitude,\n2. control of cabin altitude rate-of-change indicator,\n3. limitation of differential pressure\n4. balancing aircraft altitude with cabin altitude\n5. cabin ventilation\n6. keeping a constant differential pressure throughout all the flight phases.\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Generally, for large aeroplanes, electrical heating for ice protection is used on:",
    "feedback": "pitot tubes"
  },
  {
    "question": "An automatic cut-out valve is used in a:",
    "feedback": "fixed volume pressure control system."
  },
  {
    "question": "Both gas turbine and piston engines use a cycle made up of induction, compression, combustion and exhaust phases. Which of these statements about a gas turbine are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The process in a gas turbine is continuous\n2) Theoretically the combustion occurs at constant volume",
    "feedback": "1) is correct 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is breathed in when using a passenger oxygen mask?",
    "feedback": "cabin air and oxygen"
  },
  {
    "question": "In accordance with EASA AIR OPS, during and following an emergency descent, each occupant of the cockpit seats on duty must have access to a minimum amount of oxygen in:  1. order to maintain a supply throughout the entire flight time where the cabin altitude pressure is greater than 13000 ft. 2. order to maintain a supply throughout the entire flight time where the cabin altitude pressure is greater than 10000 ft and smaller than 13000 ft minus 30 minutes. 3. no case less than 30 minutes for airplanes certified to fly up to 25000 ft. 4. no case less than 2 hours for airplanes certified to fly at over 25000 ft.  The combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4."
  },
  {
    "question": "During climbing flight using a turbocharged airplane, the manifold pressure will remain approximately constant until:",
    "feedback": "The engine's critical altitude is reached."
  },
  {
    "question": "From the cruise, with all the parameters correctly set, if the altitude is reduced, to maintain the same mixture the fuel flow  should:",
    "feedback": "increase"
  },
  {
    "question": "The type of hydraulic fluid which has the highest resistance against cavitation is :",
    "feedback": "Synthetic fluid."
  },
  {
    "question": "The station numbers before and after the LP turbine are:",
    "feedback": "6 and 7"
  },
  {
    "question": "The crank assembly of a piston engine comprises the:",
    "feedback": "crankshaft, connecting rods and pistons"
  },
  {
    "question": "The viscosity of a hydraulic fluid should be:",
    "feedback": "low to minimise power consumption and resistance to flow"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a manually operated system, the cabin altitude rate of change is normally controlled by :",
    "feedback": "a rate of change selector."
  },
  {
    "question": "The main function of a carburettor in a piston engine is to .......",
    "feedback": "supply a correct fuel-air mixture at all speeds"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the condensator in the one phase asynchronus motor for?",
    "feedback": "To generate an elliptic field"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ventilation system in a fuel tank ....",
    "feedback": "prevents low pressure or excessive overpressure in the tank"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"Conditioned\" air is air that has :",
    "feedback": "been controlled in respect of temperature and pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "When the wing skin is not able to carry loads, the structural elements of the wing, which carry the bending moment, are:",
    "feedback": "the spars"
  },
  {
    "question": "The characteristics of an axial compressor are:\n\n1) a low pressure ratio per stage\n2) a high pressure ratio per stage\n3) the possibility of compressing a large mass airflow\n4) the inability of compressing a large mass airflow\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "In jet transport aeroplanes, oxygen for the flight deck oxygen system is stored as:",
    "feedback": "gas"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the event a surge is suspected in the compressor of a gas turbine engine, the:",
    "feedback": "throttle must be closed slowly."
  },
  {
    "question": "The conditions which can cause detonation are :",
    "feedback": "High manifold pressure and low revolutions per minute."
  },
  {
    "question": "Fixed-pitch propellers are usually designed for maximum efficiency at :",
    "feedback": "cruising speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "For a turbine engine, the term self-sustaining speed relates to the speed at which the engine :",
    "feedback": "will run without any starter motor assistance"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct?\n\n1) The freezing point for Jet A is at a higher temperature than that for Jet B\n2) The flash point for Jet A is at a higher temperature than that for Jet B",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements concerning oxygen on board of passenger transport aeroplanes is correct?",
    "feedback": "Portable oxygen bottles are primarily intended for first aid purposes"
  },
  {
    "question": "The international symbol of electrical power is",
    "feedback": "P and it is measured in watts."
  },
  {
    "question": "The power source for hot air in the de-icing/anti-icing system on jet aeroplanes is:",
    "feedback": "bleed air from the engine's compressor."
  },
  {
    "question": "The fuel supply system on a jet engine includes a fuel heating device, upstream of the main fuel filter so as to:",
    "feedback": "prevent, at low fuel temperature, the risk of ice formation from water contained in the fuel."
  },
  {
    "question": "Air drawn through the compressor will:",
    "feedback": "decrease in axial velocity."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about oxygen in transport aeroplanes is correct?",
    "feedback": "A chemical oxygen generator cannot be switched off"
  },
  {
    "question": "A test to assess the state of charge of a lead-acid battery would involve :",
    "feedback": "comparing the \"on-load\" and \"off-load\" battery voltages."
  },
  {
    "question": "With which instrument(s) do you monitor the power output of an aeroplane fitted with a fixed pitch propeller?",
    "feedback": "RPM indicator."
  },
  {
    "question": "Alternating current can be derived from direct current by:",
    "feedback": "an inverter"
  },
  {
    "question": "A cabin pressure controller maintains a pre-set cabin altitude by regulating the:",
    "feedback": "position of the outflow valve(s)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is decreased?\n\n1) The gas generator speed remains constant\n2) The EGT increases",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about compressor stall are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) A compressor stall is most likely to occur in a compressor designed for a high pressure ratio operating at high RPM\n2) A compressor stall is most likely to occur when the air flow stagnates in the rear stages of the compressor",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is decreased?\n\n1) The HP spool speed decreases\n2) The EGT decreases",
    "feedback": "1) is correct,2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements concerning a sandwich structural part are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The main function of the core material is to stabilise the covering sheets\n2) A sandwich structural part is unsuitable for absorbing concentrated loads",
    "feedback": "1) is correct,2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of a turbocharger system for a small reciprocating aircraft engine?",
    "feedback": "Feedback not found"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a jet aircraft fuel heaters are :",
    "feedback": "located on the engines"
  },
  {
    "question": "The portable emergency beacons which are used after an emergency landing or ditching have a duration of :",
    "feedback": "48 h"
  },
  {
    "question": "A combustion heater system is normally supplied from by:",
    "feedback": "fuel from the aircraft fuel system."
  },
  {
    "question": "Shimmy is:",
    "feedback": "sinusoidal and possibly damaging movement of the nose wheel on the ground."
  },
  {
    "question": "GEN 1 suffers from a voltage overload and as a result the internal exciter breaker opens. The flight crew is instructed to switch off the generator using the overhead push button. Which statement describes the new configuration?",
    "feedback": "Generator breaker 1 (C1-1) opens and both bus tie breakers close"
  },
  {
    "question": "A transformer with 2400 windings on the primary coil shall give 28 VAC output from the secondary coil when 115 VAC is connected to the primary coil. How many windings are needed on the secondary coil ?",
    "feedback": "585 windings."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a compensated capacitance type quantity indicating system, the contents gauge of a half-full fuel tank indicates a fuel mass of 8000 lb. If a temperature rise increased the volume of fuel by 5 %, the indicated fuel weight would :",
    "feedback": "remain the same."
  },
  {
    "question": "Excessive pressure in the cylinders of an engine equipped with a constant speed propeller can be caused by the combination of:",
    "feedback": "high manifold pressure with low RPM."
  },
  {
    "question": "During a power change on an engine equipped with a constant speed propeller, a wrong combination of manifold pressure and RPM values results in excessive pressures in the cylinders. This is the case when one simultaneously selects a ...",
    "feedback": "high manifold pressure and low RPM."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following must be considered if all generators fail in flight, and only battery power remains?",
    "feedback": "Since the only remaining source of electrical power is the aircraft battery the consumption of electrical power is time-limited"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of ribs in a wing is to:",
    "feedback": "give the wing the desired aerodynamic shape"
  },
  {
    "question": "Electrical bonding of an aircraft is used to:\n\n1. protect the aircraft against lightning effects.\n2. reset the electrostatic potential of the aircraft to a value approximating 0 volt\n3. reduce radio interference on radiocommunication systems\n4. set the aircraft to a single potential\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about rudder pedal nose wheel steering is correct?",
    "feedback": "Rudder pedal nose wheel steering functions on the ground only"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do the gas parameters change within the stator of a compressor stage?\nWhen temperature increases:",
    "feedback": "Pressure increases and the speed decreases"
  },
  {
    "question": "A stage in an axial compressor:",
    "feedback": "is made of a rotor disc followed by a row of stator blades"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the cockpit of a transport airplane, at least one manual fire-extinguisher must be conveniently located containing :",
    "feedback": "halon."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement comprises the favourable qualities of hydraulic fluid?",
    "feedback": "High flash point, low volatility, low compressibility and low flammability"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main purpose of the mixture control is to",
    "feedback": "adjust the fuel flow to obtain the desired air/fuel ratio."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an impulse turbine are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The pressure drops across the nozzle guide vanes\n2) The pressure remains constant across the rotor blades",
    "feedback": "1) is correct,2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider brake wear indicators on multi disc-type brakes. The indicators show brake wear as a measure of the .....",
    "feedback": "thickness of the brake unit's lining material"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the contact breaker is to:",
    "feedback": "control the primary circuit of the magneto"
  },
  {
    "question": "The source of air to pressurise the reservoir or an aircraft's hydraulic system is normally ......",
    "feedback": "the aircraft's pneumatic system"
  },
  {
    "question": "The flash point of fuel is:",
    "feedback": "lowest temperature of vapour"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of cowl flaps on an aeroplane?",
    "feedback": "Air flow across the engine is increased when they are open, which increases cooling efficiency"
  },
  {
    "question": "The engine component between station numbers 1 and 2 is the:",
    "feedback": "intake"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft hydraulic system which has a low-pressure fluid flow in the system when the system actuating mechanisms are at idle is referred to as ......",
    "feedback": "an open centre hydraulic system"
  },
  {
    "question": "The primary reason for venting an engine oil tank is to:",
    "feedback": "prevent excessive pressure in the tank"
  },
  {
    "question": "A variable displacement type hydraulic pump:",
    "feedback": "Moves fluid quantity dependent of the system demand."
  },
  {
    "question": "The engine component between station numbers 6 and 7 is the:",
    "feedback": "LP turbine"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is decreased?\n\n1) The propeller blade angle remains constant\n2) The free power turbine speed remains constant",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an auto-brake system are correct or incorrect?\n1) An auto-brake system can function properly, even when the anti-skid system is inoperative\n2) In the RTO mode maximum anti-skid braking is applied",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of pressurising some hydraulic reservoirs is to:",
    "feedback": "provide a positive feed to the main pump"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a normally aspirated engine (non turbo-charged), the manifold pressure gauge always indicates...",
    "feedback": "a lower value than atmospheric pressure when the engine is running."
  },
  {
    "question": "The pneumatic system accumulator is useful :",
    "feedback": "to eliminate the fluid pressure variations."
  },
  {
    "question": "With an aircraft fitted with a fixed pitch propeller, during flight at normal cruising speed, one magneto fails completely. This will first cause:",
    "feedback": "loss of approximately 100 RPM"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an air start system air is:",
    "feedback": "supplied to an air starter motor."
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpse of baffles fitted in fuel tanks is to:",
    "feedback": "restrict undesirable fuel movement"
  },
  {
    "question": "The principles underlying the effects of jet propulsion are set out in:",
    "feedback": "Newton's 3rd Law of Motion"
  },
  {
    "question": "What unit of measurement is used to express electrical resistance?",
    "feedback": "Ohm"
  },
  {
    "question": "The torsion box of a modern aircraft wing structure consists of:",
    "feedback": "spars, skin, stringers and ribs"
  },
  {
    "question": "Creep of turbine blades is caused by:",
    "feedback": "high blade temperatures whilst under centrifugal loading."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements about stator vanes in axial flow compressors is correct?",
    "feedback": "Pressure increases due to the air's kinetic energy being converted into pressure energy"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a piston engine, turbocharger boost pressure may be monitored by :",
    "feedback": "a manifold pressure gauge only."
  },
  {
    "question": "A sandwich structural part is unsuitable for absorbing:",
    "feedback": "concentrated loads"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements regarding cockpit windows are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) On some aeroplanes the cockpit windows have an additional speed restriction, related to bird impact, when window heating is inoperative\n2) Cockpit side windows are usually defogged only",
    "feedback": "1) is correct 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding the certification specifications issued by EASA:",
    "feedback": "CS-23 applies for Nomal, Utility, Aerobatic and Commuter Aeroplanes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Wings without exterior support is called:",
    "feedback": "Cantilever"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main reasons for using pressurised hydraulic reservoirs on jet transport aircraft is/are:",
    "feedback": "To assure that an adequate supply of fluid free from foaming always is present at the pump inlet."
  },
  {
    "question": "The fan of a turbo-fan engine is driven by:",
    "feedback": "the LP turbine"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the mode in which 100% oxygen is inhaled on demand?",
    "feedback": "100%"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct about the flow in a divergent (subsonic) gas turbine engine intake?\n\n1) The speed decreases in flow direction\n2) The total temperature decreases in flow direction",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "A free power turbine is:",
    "feedback": "not connected to the compressor."
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the causes of high oil temperature in a gas turbine engine at constant power setting is:",
    "feedback": "malfunction of the heat exchanger"
  },
  {
    "question": "A twin spool gas turbine engine is one in which the:",
    "feedback": "LP turbine drives the LP compressor and the HP turbine drives the HP compressor"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft electrical circuit which uses the aircraft structure as a return path to earth, may be defined as a",
    "feedback": "single pole circuit."
  },
  {
    "question": "The gas temperature:",
    "feedback": "reduces as it passes through the turbine."
  },
  {
    "question": "The correct statement about rain protection for cockpit windshields is that :",
    "feedback": "rain repellent should never be sprayed onto the windshield unless the rainfall is very heavy"
  },
  {
    "question": "The output of a generator is controlled by :",
    "feedback": "varying the field strength."
  },
  {
    "question": "At the end of a rejected take-off performed with an auto-brake system with the setting RTO:",
    "feedback": "the brakes will lock the wheels"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about the fuel system depicted in the graph are correct or incorrect?\n1) If the AC fuel pumps are not running in the system configuration shown, it is still possible to feed both engines from the main tanks\n2) In the system configuration shown the DC fuel pump can supply fuel to the engines",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider a piston-engined aircraft with a constant speed propeller. At cruising altitude when less power is required, engine power is ....",
    "feedback": "reduced by lowering the manifold pressure and increasing the blade angle, to decrease RPM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hydraulic fluids of synthetic origin are:",
    "feedback": "purple."
  },
  {
    "question": "According CS 25 the worst effect of a major failure on the aeroplane could be:",
    "feedback": "significant reduction in functional capabilities or safety margins"
  },
  {
    "question": "The most common extinguishing agent used in gas turbine engine fire protection system is:",
    "feedback": "Halon"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cabin pressurisation is controlled by:",
    "feedback": "the outflow valve(s)"
  },
  {
    "question": "As altitude increases, compressor load:",
    "feedback": "decreases."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following formulas describes how the torque of an electrical motor is determined by the supplied voltage and current and the resulting RPM?\n(T = Torque, U = Voltage, H = RPM, I = Current)",
    "feedback": "T = (U x I) / H"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following statements about diesel engines:\n\n1) power is regulated by the throttle valve\n2) there is no throttle valve\n3) power is set by the fuel flow \n4) thermal efficiency is lower than that for a petrol engine\n5) diesel fuel is less inflammable than petrol\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a continuous loop wire type fire detection system is tested:",
    "feedback": "the wiring and the warning are tested"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following will decrease volumetric efficiency of a reciprocating engine?",
    "feedback": "High cylinder head temperature."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can you tell when metallic bonding is incorrect?",
    "feedback": "Corrosion at skin joints"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main reason for opening the cowl flaps is to control the:",
    "feedback": "C.H.T. (cylinder head temperature)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Assuming cabin differential pressure has reached the required value in normal flight conditions, if flight altitude and air conditioning system settings are maintained:",
    "feedback": "the mass airflow through the cabin is constant"
  },
  {
    "question": "The shunt-wound generator produces an output in which:",
    "feedback": "the voltage decreases slightly with increase in load."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about a reaction turbine are correct or incorrect?  1) The pressure drops across the nozzle guide vanes 2) The pressure remains constant across the rotor blades",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the diagram showing the power output of a piston engine as a function of mixture ratio, best economy on rich side of the EGT top is shown at:",
    "feedback": "point 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the main components of a turbine engine starting system?",
    "feedback": "A starter and an igniter to ignite the air/fuel mixture in the combustion chamber"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a landing gear, movement is damped by:",
    "feedback": "nitrogen and liquid."
  },
  {
    "question": "Once the engine has started, ignition systems of piston engines are:",
    "feedback": "independant from the electrical system of the aeroplane."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a typical hydraulic system, the overheat detectors are usually installed:",
    "feedback": "at the pumps."
  },
  {
    "question": "The pyrotechnic means used in case of an emergency to indicate your position to the emergency teams are a flare:",
    "feedback": "which is used at night and a smoke device which is used in the daytime."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an auto-brake system are correct or incorrect?\n1) During landing and rejected take-off auto-brakes keep operating until the pilot presses the brake pedals\n2) During landing auto-brakes keep operating when idle reverse thrust is selected",
    "feedback": "1) is correct,2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The fuel crossfeed system:",
    "feedback": "allows feeding of any engine from any fuel tank."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about structural design principles are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) In structural design, fail safe implies parallel structural parts\n2) In structural design, safe life implies the structure will never fail during a declared time period or number of cycles",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "The primary purpose of bonding the metallic parts of an aircraft is to :\n\n1) prevent electrolytic corrosion between mating surfaces of similar metals\n2) ensure zero voltage difference between aircraft components\n3) isolate all components electrically \n4) provide a single earth for electrical devices\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pilot identifies a compressor stall by:",
    "feedback": "an increase in EGT"
  },
  {
    "question": "What unit of measurement is used to express electrical power?",
    "feedback": "Watt"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pressurized aeroplane is flying at FL 370 and experiences a rapid decompression. \n\nWhich of the following statements is correct about the oxygen system?",
    "feedback": "Flight crew members must put on their oxygen masks themselves"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an ignition system during a normal start of a gas turbine engine, igniter activation:",
    "feedback": "should commence prior to fuel entering the combustion chamber"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the best method to stop a running engine if the magneto switch ground wire becomes disconnected?",
    "feedback": "Shut off fuel"
  },
  {
    "question": "The maximum differential pressure of a transonic transport category airplane is approximately:",
    "feedback": "9.0 psi"
  },
  {
    "question": "The engine component between station numbers 2.5 and 3 is the:",
    "feedback": "LP compressor"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a pressurized transport aircraft, the protective breathing equipment:",
    "feedback": "protects the members of the crew against fumes and noxious gases."
  },
  {
    "question": "The type of windings commonly used in DC starter motors are :",
    "feedback": "series wound."
  },
  {
    "question": "A jet aircraft is certified for the carriage of 120 passengers. 42 passengers are on board and the expected Flight Level on route Paris-Alger is FL 330. The first aid oxygen to be on board at departure shall provide breathing supply for at least:",
    "feedback": "1 passenger for the entire flight after cabin depressurisation at cabin altitude of more than 8000 ft."
  },
  {
    "question": "A corrosive environment and sustained tensile stress can lead to:",
    "feedback": "Stress corrosion"
  },
  {
    "question": "An airplane whose maximum approved passenger seating configuration is greater than 600 seats must be equipped with at least:",
    "feedback": "8 hand fire-extinguishers conveniently located in the passenger compartment."
  },
  {
    "question": "According CS 25 the worst effect of a catastrophic failure on the flight crew could be",
    "feedback": "fatalities or incapacitation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following parts is a typical semiconductor part?",
    "feedback": "Diode"
  },
  {
    "question": "The most appropriate statement concerning multi engine jet aeroplane fuel systems, is:",
    "feedback": "The fuel system may have provisions for heating the fuel before it enters the fuel filter."
  },
  {
    "question": "The capacitance type fuel gauging system indicates the fuel quantity by measuring the:",
    "feedback": "dielectric change between fuel and air."
  },
  {
    "question": "The mechanism to change the propeller blade angle of a small piston engine aeroplane in flight is operated:",
    "feedback": "hydraulically by engine oil"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a steep turn to the left, when using spoilers ...",
    "feedback": "The right aileron will descend, the left one will ascend, the right spoiler will retract and the left one will extend."
  },
  {
    "question": "After putting an additional load on an electric motor, the motor slows down. This causes the current to (1) ...... and the torque of the motor to (2) ......",
    "feedback": "(1) increase, (2) increase"
  },
  {
    "question": "The number in the graph that shows the bogie beam is:",
    "feedback": "6"
  },
  {
    "question": "The cause of rather violent vibration of the nose wheel, described as shimmy, is often:",
    "feedback": "both, A and C are correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is decreased?\n\n1) The gas generator speed decreases\n2) The EGT remains constant",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following parts is a typical semiconductor part?",
    "feedback": "Diode"
  },
  {
    "question": "On detection of a persistent phase imbalance between an AC generator connected to the main bus bars and other AC generators, the protection device that opens is/are the:",
    "feedback": "tie breaker(s)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dual ignition provides a factor of reliability and:",
    "feedback": "improves combustion efficiency"
  },
  {
    "question": "During the compression stroke of a piston engine during the practical cycle, valves are open as follows:",
    "feedback": "the intake valve is open in the first part of the stroke, then both valves are closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Tyre \"creep\" may be described as the :",
    "feedback": "circumferential movement of the tyre in relation to the wheel flange."
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following statements about diesel engines:\n\n1) power is set by the mixture control\n2) there is no mixture control\n3) the amount of power is determined by the fuel flow only\n4) thermal efficiency is higher than that for a petrol engine\n5) diesel fuel is more inflammable than petrol\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The engine type represented in the drawing is a:",
    "feedback": "twin-spool turbofan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding certain aircraft using sidesticks for manual control:",
    "feedback": "In certain cases, different dual inputs made by the pilots, demanding contradictory movement of the flying controls, are algebraically summed by the flight computer"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a modern large pressurized transport aircraft, the maximum cabin differential pressure is approximately:",
    "feedback": "7 - 9 psi"
  },
  {
    "question": "The engine component between station numbers 2 and 2.5 is the:",
    "feedback": "fan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which part of the main landing gear is shown by the number 5?",
    "feedback": "Axle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following items are performed as part of the pilot's pre-flight inspection of an aircraft's tyres?\n1) An inspection for excessive tyre creep2) A check of the ply and speed rating of each tyre3) Measurement of the actual tread depth using a tread-depth gauge4) Visual tyre inspection for embedded objects5) Measurement of the tyre pressure using a pressure gauge",
    "feedback": "1, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the figure.\nFrom which tank(s) can the APU receive fuel?",
    "feedback": "all three tanks"
  },
  {
    "question": "The mixture of impulse and reaction blade shape in the average turbine blade is that the.....",
    "feedback": "inner half is impulse and the outer half is reaction"
  },
  {
    "question": "A warning will be given if the cabin altitude exceeds:",
    "feedback": "10000 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "When applying precautionary carburettor heating on a reciprocating engine with a constant speed propeller in its constant speed range:",
    "feedback": "the RPM remains constant"
  },
  {
    "question": "The extinguisher in a fixed fire extinguisher system is activated:",
    "feedback": "electrically."
  },
  {
    "question": "During cruising flight, when the throttle is slightly advanced on an aeroplane equipped with a constant speed propeller, the propeller pitch automatically:",
    "feedback": "increases and the RPM remains the same"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is increased?\n\n1) The propeller blade angle remains constant\n2) The free power turbine speed remains constant",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The frequency of an AC generator is dependent on the :",
    "feedback": "number of pairs of poles and the speed of the moving part."
  },
  {
    "question": "The operating principle of magnetos in a piston engine ignition system consists of:",
    "feedback": "opening the primary circuit in order to induce a low amperage, high voltage current, which is distributed to the spark plugs"
  },
  {
    "question": "To ensure efficient combustion in a gas turbine engine ....",
    "feedback": "it must be capable of creating the optimal mixture of air and fuel"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some secondary air is directed through the dilution holes in the combustion chambers to:",
    "feedback": "cool the gas before it reaches the turbine."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a piston engine if the ratio of air to fuel, by weight, is approximately 9:1, the mixture is said to be :",
    "feedback": "rich"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a reciprocating four-stroke engine, the only \"driving\" stroke is the:",
    "feedback": "power stroke"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is increased?\n\n1) The gas generator speed increases\n2) The EGT decreases",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "The effect of ram air on the operation of a gas turbine engine is:",
    "feedback": "an increase in the efficiency of the engine"
  },
  {
    "question": "An electrically activated and operated fuel valve is called a(n):",
    "feedback": "Solenoid valve."
  },
  {
    "question": "Gear retraction systems are classified according to the power source used for\nretraction and extension.  Which are the most frequently used on larger aircraft?",
    "feedback": "Hydraulic"
  },
  {
    "question": "On which stroke or strokes are both valves on a four-stroke cycle reciprocating engine cylinder open during a part of the strokes?",
    "feedback": "Exhaust and intake"
  },
  {
    "question": "A large transport aircraft is fitted with flight spoilers, speed brakes, trailing edge flaps, and a moveable horizontal stabilizer. If this aircraft's ailerons are jammed, roll control may be achieved by using the ......",
    "feedback": "flight spoilers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding fire detection, ion detectors are used to detect:",
    "feedback": "smoke."
  },
  {
    "question": "Fuel pressure is measured ....",
    "feedback": "in the line between the booster pump and the engine or at the outlet of the high pressure filter"
  },
  {
    "question": "The probe heater operates",
    "feedback": "automatically, when the probe detects ice."
  },
  {
    "question": "If the automatic control of an air conditioning system fails:",
    "feedback": "the pilot can revert to manual control and set the control valve to the required setting."
  },
  {
    "question": "In addition to energy storage the accumulator of the hydraulic system is used :",
    "feedback": "for dampening pressure surges in the system."
  },
  {
    "question": "The disadvantages of a chemical oxygen source compared with a gaseous one for the passenger cabin are :\n\n1) A flow which cannot be modulated\n2) Less capacity\n3) Risk of fire and/or explosion\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The inflatable boot de-icing system removes ice by:",
    "feedback": "Deformation."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a gas turbine engine, the highest gas temperature is attained:",
    "feedback": "within the combustion chamber."
  },
  {
    "question": "When applying carburettor heating:",
    "feedback": "the mixture becomes richer"
  },
  {
    "question": "The overheat warning system of a transport aeroplane consists of a warning:",
    "feedback": "light and warning bell."
  },
  {
    "question": "Evacuation slide inflation is ensured by :",
    "feedback": "a pressurized gas canister combined with the slide itself."
  },
  {
    "question": "When starting the engine, or when the engine is running at idle RPM on the ground, the mixture is:",
    "feedback": "rich, to make starting possible and to cool the engine sufficiently when idling"
  },
  {
    "question": "The power output of a generator is controlled by:",
    "feedback": "varying the field strength"
  },
  {
    "question": "Usually, in conductive materials",
    "feedback": "the resistance increases with increasing temperature."
  },
  {
    "question": "Select the correct statement(s) regarding fly-by-wire control systems (FBW):\n1) For system redundancy, several differently designed computers of dissimilar type are installed2) Contradictory movement of the flying controls may be demanded by the pilots through dual inputs",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is not correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "A wing spar typically consists of:",
    "feedback": "a web and girders"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about composite and metal structures are correct or incorrect?  1) For a structural component with given dimensions composite materials enable a structural component's strength to be tailored to the direction of the load 2) Composite materials enable structures with higher strenght/weight ratio than metal structures",
    "feedback": "1) is correct,2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The engine component between station numbers 5 and 6 is the:",
    "feedback": "HP turbine"
  },
  {
    "question": "The compression ratio of a piston engine is the ratio of the:",
    "feedback": "volume of the cylinder with the piston at bottom dead centre to that with the piston at top dead centre."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an auto-brake system are correct or incorrect?\n1) During landing and rejected take-off auto-brakes stop operating below a certain low speed\n2) During landing auto-brakes stop operating and disarm when reverse thrust is selected",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a turbine engine, what is provided with the engine ignition in continuous ignition mode?",
    "feedback": "Low power ignition for flameout risk situations"
  },
  {
    "question": "An air cycle machine (air conditioning pack):",
    "feedback": "causes a pressure and temperature drop in the bleed air"
  },
  {
    "question": "Tne number in the graph that shows the torsion link is:",
    "feedback": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which part of a wing, other than stressed skin construction, takes upward loads?",
    "feedback": "Spars"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider a piston engined aircraft. Which source is pneumatic air taken from?",
    "feedback": "Supercharger air"
  },
  {
    "question": "What mission does the strut have, often observed between the fuselage and the wing, on small high wing aircraft?",
    "feedback": "Supporting the wing while the aircraft is on ground and when airborne."
  },
  {
    "question": "The fuel tanks in small aircraft are mainly located:",
    "feedback": "In the wings"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft with a pressurised cabin has a maximum cabin altitude of 8.000 feet, which equals 10,9 psi. Present flight altitude is 30.000 feet, which equals 4,36 psi. Pressure at sea level equals 14,7 psi.  Calculate the pressure differential:",
    "feedback": "6,54 psi"
  },
  {
    "question": "Turbine blade stages may be classed as either \"impulse\" or \"reaction\". In an impulse blade section :",
    "feedback": "the pressure drops across the nozzle guide vanes and remains constant across the rotor blades ."
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding a jet engine:\n\n1) The maximum thrust increases slightly as the pressure altitude increases\n2) The specific fuel consumption decreases slightly as the pressure altitude increases at constant TAS",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pneumatic mechanical devices that provide ice protection:",
    "feedback": "are usually used as de-icing devices"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the diagram showing the power output of a piston engine as a function of mixture ratio, the chemically correct ratio (stoichiometric) is shown at:",
    "feedback": "point 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the cabin, when the oxygen mask is pulled downwards, the passenger breathes :",
    "feedback": "a mixture of oxygen and cabin air."
  },
  {
    "question": "A fault protection circuit in a fire detection system will:",
    "feedback": "inhibit the fire detector when the detection line is connected to ground."
  },
  {
    "question": "The electrolyte in a nickel cadmium battery is ....",
    "feedback": "Potassium hydroxide"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the oil and the nitrogen in an oleo-pneumatic strut is:",
    "feedback": "the oil supplies the damping function and the nitrogen supplies the spring function"
  },
  {
    "question": "A \"trip-free\" type circuit breaker is a circuit protection device which :",
    "feedback": "will not allow the contacts to be held closed while a current fault exists in the circuit."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about a gust lock system are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) Irreversible flight controls should have a gust lock\n2) There is no need for a gust lock on manual flight controls",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "The use of too low an octane fuel may cause:",
    "feedback": "detonation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is correct about an integrated drive generator (IDG) of a turbine engine? It is ....",
    "feedback": "lubricated by an internal oil system"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some components of a turbine engine are required to operate at their maximum temperature. What combination of the following components are exposed to the greatest thermal loads?",
    "feedback": "First stage turbine nozzle guide vanes and the first stage of the HP turbine"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"Nose wheel shimmy\" may be described as :",
    "feedback": "a possibly damaging vibration of the nose wheel when moving on the ground."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a multi-spool turbofan engine, the fan is driven by:",
    "feedback": "the rearmost turbine."
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens when the rotor of an electrical motor seizes?\nThe current in the stator (1) ......, the current in the rotor (2) ......, and the torque (3) ...... .",
    "feedback": "(1) increases, (2) increases, (3) increases"
  },
  {
    "question": "Rudder trim adjustment in an aeroplane with irreversible flight controls is:",
    "feedback": "an adjustment of the zero force rudder position"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.\n\nGEN 2 can be used to feed the DC ESS BUS:\n(NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumend to remain open)",
    "feedback": "via AC BUS 2 when C1.4, C3.2 and C5.2 are closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "A cable operated control system has external locks:",
    "feedback": "When fitted to the control surface, they will prevent movement of the control column if the controls are not fitted with servo tabs."
  },
  {
    "question": "Compressor surge may be identified by:",
    "feedback": "an indication of vibration."
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.\n\nGEN 2 can be used to feed the AC BUS 1, when:\n(NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumend to remain open)",
    "feedback": "C1.4, C2.1 and C2.2 are closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a theoretical gas turbine cycle, combustion takes place at constant:",
    "feedback": "pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "The number of crash axes on board an airplane, whose maximum approved configuration of passenger seats is 201, is :",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeroplane equipped with fully powered flight controls (irreversible type):",
    "feedback": "requires the use of an artificial feel system"
  },
  {
    "question": "A hot rod ice detection system indicates aircraft ice accretion by ....",
    "feedback": "the ice build-up on the probe, which can be viewed from the cockpit"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a jet engine, active clearance control is achieved by controlling the turbine (1) .... temperature, with the use of cool (2) .... to adjust the turbine blade to case clearance",
    "feedback": "(1) case, (2) air"
  },
  {
    "question": "A twin-spool engine with an inlet air mass flow of 220 kg/s and HP compressor mass flow of 220 kg/s has a bypass ratio of ....",
    "feedback": "0"
  },
  {
    "question": "The working cycle of a four-stroke engine is :",
    "feedback": "intake, compression, power, exhaust."
  },
  {
    "question": "An airplane whose maximum approved passenger seating configuration is 401 to 500 seats must be equipped with at least:",
    "feedback": "6 hand fire-extinguishers conveniently located in the passenger compartment."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the control surface that rotates an aeroplane about its vertical axis?",
    "feedback": "The rudder"
  },
  {
    "question": "How much vent space is required in fuel tanks by EASA CS-23 and CS-25 rules?",
    "feedback": "2 % of the total tank space in each individual tank."
  },
  {
    "question": "In an air cycle machine (bootstrap system), bleed air downstream of the first heat exchanger is:",
    "feedback": "compressed, passed through the second heat exchanger and then passed across an expansion turbine"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about the fuel system depicted in the graph are correct or incorrect?\n1) If the AC fuel pumps are not running in the system configuration shown, it is still possible to feed both engines from the main tanks\n2) If the APU isolation valve opens, the APU fuel shut off valve is closed and there is no AC power, the DC fuel pump can supply fuel to the engines",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "AVGAS grade 100 can be identified by the colour code ....",
    "feedback": "green"
  },
  {
    "question": "The engine component between station numbers 7 and 8 is the:",
    "feedback": "exhaust"
  },
  {
    "question": "The flight level from which regulation requires for the flight crew members in pressurized aircraft a quick donning type mask is:",
    "feedback": "FL 250."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are contributing factors on the development of fatigue?\n1) Corrosion2) Number of cycles3)Type of flight maneuvres4) Stress level5) Level and quality of maintenance",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hydraulic fluids should have the following characteristics:  1) thermal stability2) anti-corrosive3) high flash-point4) high compressibility5) high volatility\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of an air conditioning pack inlet flow valve (pack valve) is to:",
    "feedback": "Maintain a constant and sufficient mass air flow to ventilate the cabin and minimise cabin pressure surges."
  },
  {
    "question": "An intake designed for transonic speeds will be a:",
    "feedback": "diverging duct."
  },
  {
    "question": "Pascal's law states that:",
    "feedback": "Pressure in an enclosed container is transmitted equally and undiminished to all parts of the container and acts at right angles to the enclosing walls."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about structural design principles are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The damage tolerance principle takes cracking of the structure into account\n2) The safe life principle is based on the replacement of parts after a given number of cycles or flight hours",
    "feedback": "1) is correct,2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The maximum horsepower output which can be obtained from an engine when it is operated at specified rpm and manifold pressure conditons established as safe for continuous operation is termed :",
    "feedback": "rated power."
  },
  {
    "question": "Special fuel consumption schedules during flight are designed due",
    "feedback": "to minimise the wing G-loads and preserve main tank fuel for landing."
  },
  {
    "question": "The reason for the fact that an aeroplane designed for long distances cannot simply be used for short haul flights at higher frequencies is that",
    "feedback": "the lifetime of the fatigue sensitive parts has been based on a determined load spectrum"
  },
  {
    "question": "The station numbers before and after the combustion chamber are:",
    "feedback": "4 and 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements is correct about a flight crew oxygen mask?",
    "feedback": "Most oxygen masks can be selected into three positions: NORMAL and/or DILUTE, 100%, and EMERGENCY"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following materials is a semi conductor?",
    "feedback": "Ge"
  },
  {
    "question": "At constant fuel flow, if engine compressor air is bled off for engine anti-icing or a similar system, the turbine temperature:",
    "feedback": "will rise"
  },
  {
    "question": "Engine temperature limitations of a gas turbine are usually imposed due to temperature limitations on the:",
    "feedback": "turbine section"
  },
  {
    "question": "A magnetic circuit-breaker:",
    "feedback": "is a protection system that has a quick tripping response."
  },
  {
    "question": "The primary function of a constant speed drive (CSD) in an AC generating system is to:",
    "feedback": "drive the generator at a constant speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "The station numbers before and after the fan are:",
    "feedback": "2 and 2.5"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a landing is performed with an auto-brake system selected to a high deceleration level:",
    "feedback": "this deceleration level may not be constant when the runway has local slippery spots"
  },
  {
    "question": "The engine type represented in the drawing is a:",
    "feedback": "twin-spool turbojet"
  },
  {
    "question": "The highest load on the torsion link in a bogie gear is:",
    "feedback": "whilst turning on the ground with a small radius"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which describes best the component (2) in a main landing gear assembly?",
    "feedback": "Shock strut"
  },
  {
    "question": "According CS 25 the allowable quantitative average failure probability per flight hour for a catastrophic failure should be on the order of (^means to the power of):",
    "feedback": "less than 10^-9 (extremely improbable)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The bypass ratio:\n\n1) is the ratio of bypass air mass flow to HP compressor mass flow\n2) can be determined from the inlet air mass flow and the HP compressor mass flow",
    "feedback": "1) is correct,2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "In transport aeroplanes overheat detection systems are installed in the:",
    "feedback": "landing gear bays / wheel wells."
  },
  {
    "question": "A basic gas turbine engine consists of ....",
    "feedback": "an air intake, compressor, combustion chamber, turbine, and exhaust nozzle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cabin air for a large aeroplane during flight:",
    "feedback": "is temperature controlled."
  },
  {
    "question": "Pulling the fire shutoff handle causes a number of devices to disconnect. In respect of the AC generator it can be said that the:",
    "feedback": "exciter control relay and the generator breaker open."
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding a jet engine:\n\n1) The maximum thrust decreases as the pressure altitude increases\n2) The specific fuel consumption decreases slightly as the pressure altitude increases at constant TAS",
    "feedback": "1) is correct,2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a turbo-prop aeroplane decelerates during the initial part of the landing roll, a constant speed propeller within the beta range:",
    "feedback": "produces negative thrust"
  },
  {
    "question": "Engine compartment decking and firewalls are manufactured from:",
    "feedback": "stainless steel or titanium sheet."
  },
  {
    "question": "The main purpose of using anti-skid units in the wheel-brake system is to:",
    "feedback": "reduce tyre wear"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct regarding \"unusable fuel\"?",
    "feedback": "Fuel always remaining in the tank irrespective of the aircraft attitude, due to design limitations"
  },
  {
    "question": "Assuming the same swept volume and no turbo charger, diesel engines compared to petrol engines:",
    "feedback": "produce less maximum power output"
  },
  {
    "question": "The nozzle guide vanes are normally:",
    "feedback": "convergent."
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.\n\nIn case of failure of the static inverter:\n(NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumend to remain open)",
    "feedback": "AC ESS BUS can be powered, if required, by the EMER GEN if C4.1 is closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FADEC of a gas turbine engine normally includes:",
    "feedback": "an engine overspeed and/or an EGT protection function"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft whose maximum approved passenger seating configuration is 7 to 30 seats must be equipped with at least:",
    "feedback": "1 hand fire-extinguisher  conveniently located in the passenger compartment."
  },
  {
    "question": "The principle upon which the vibrating probe (Rosemount) ice detector is based, is:",
    "feedback": "accretion"
  },
  {
    "question": "In addition to providing \"customer\" bleed for aeroplane systems, air may be bled from compressors of a turbofan engine to increase stall margin:",
    "feedback": "at low rotor speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Creep in a gas turbine engine is:",
    "feedback": "the permanent increase in length of metal parts due to a combination of tensile stress and high temperatures over a prolonged period"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of oil do most engine manufacturers recommend to new reciprocating engine break-in?",
    "feedback": "Straight mineral oil."
  },
  {
    "question": "The power output of a piston engine is directly proportional to:",
    "feedback": "torque and RPM"
  },
  {
    "question": "The primary input signals for a hydro-mechanical gas turbine engine fuel control system include:",
    "feedback": "N2, compressor discharge pressure, compressor inlet temperature, fuel shut-off, thrust lever angle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ice formation on turbofan engine intakes is usually:",
    "feedback": "prevented by using compressor bleed air"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about structural design principles are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The damage tolerance principle assumes cracks in the structure will never occur\n2) The safe life principle is based on the replacement of parts after a given number of cycles or flight hours",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a hydraulic system, a shuttle valve :",
    "feedback": "allows two possible sources of pressure to operate one unit."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about rudder limiting are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) A rudder ratio changer system reduces the rudder deflection for a given rudder pedal deflection as the IAS increases\n2) A variable stop system limits both rudder and rudder pedal deflection as the IAS increases",
    "feedback": "1) is correct 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The term \"cabin pressure\" applies when an aeroplane:",
    "feedback": "has the means to maintain the cabin pressure at a higher level than the ambient pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "The static thrust of a turbo-jet:\n\n1) equals the product of the exhaust gas mass flow and the exhaust gas velocity\n2) is obtained by pressure of the exhaust gas on the ambient air\n3) produces zero propulsive power since the aeroplane is not moving\n4) is independent of the outside air temperature\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a continuous element of a fire detection system is heated:\n\n1. its resistance decreases.\n2. its resistance increases.\n3. the leakage current increases.\n4. the leakage current decreases.\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about a reaction turbine are correct or incorrect?  1) The pressure remains constant across the nozzle guide vanes 2) The pressure remains constant across the rotor blades",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct with regard to the fly-by-wire system?",
    "feedback": "PCUs are operated by analogue signals"
  },
  {
    "question": "How is electrical power defined?",
    "feedback": "P = electrical energy / time"
  },
  {
    "question": "When engine power is increased, the constant-speed  propeller tries to function so that it will",
    "feedback": "maintain the RPM, increase the blade angle"
  },
  {
    "question": "On most large aeroplanes, the type of low pressure fuel pumps is:",
    "feedback": "centrifugal"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main advantage of Halon 1301 over CO2 for extinguishing an aircraft cabin fire?",
    "feedback": "Halon 1301 can extinguish a fire with much lower concentration than is required\nfor CO2, and it will not deprive the occupants of the cabin of the needed oxygen."
  },
  {
    "question": "In accordance with EASA AIR OPS, each occupant of the cockpit seats on duty in a non-pressurized airplane must have an oxygen supply reserve for the entire flight time at pressure altitudes greater than:",
    "feedback": "10000 ft."
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.\n\nOn ground, external power (EXT PWR) can be used to feed the AC BUS 1 when:\n(NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumend to remain open)",
    "feedback": "C1.2 and C2.1 are closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about a gust lock system are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) A gust lock can be used in flight to reduce the effects of turbulence\n2) There is no need for a gust lock on reversible flight controls",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "The operating principle of an anti skid system is as follows : the brake pressure will be :",
    "feedback": "Decreased on the slower turning wheels."
  },
  {
    "question": "When air is compressed for pressurization purposes, the percentage oxygen content is:",
    "feedback": "unaffected."
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.\n\nGEN 1 can be used to feed the DC BAT BUS:\n(NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumend to remain open)",
    "feedback": "via AC BUS 1 and DC BUS 1, when C1.1, C5.1 and C7.1 are closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "The so-called \"hot buses\" or \"direct buses\" are:",
    "feedback": "directly connected to the battery."
  },
  {
    "question": "Electrical bonding of an aircraft is used to.....",
    "feedback": "equalise the electrical potential of the different aircraft parts"
  },
  {
    "question": "The part of a piston engine that transforms reciprocating movement into rotary motion is termed the:",
    "feedback": "crankshaft"
  },
  {
    "question": "The most suitable extinguishant for use on magnesium fires is :",
    "feedback": "sand."
  },
  {
    "question": "Inlet guide vanes are used to:",
    "feedback": "impart an angular change to the air flow"
  },
  {
    "question": "To allow for failure of the normal method of system pressure limiting control, a hydraulic system often incorporates",
    "feedback": "a high pressure relief valve."
  },
  {
    "question": "In the attached diagram, the type of stress acting on the point indicated by the image number 2 is the:",
    "feedback": "compression"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do smoke detectors operate?",
    "feedback": "A labyrinth optical detector - light reflects towards the photosensitive cell and the labyrinth has a shielding function"
  },
  {
    "question": "If at take-off power and full rich mixture, the mixture control is slowly moved towards lean and as a result the RPM of a piston engine with a fixed pitch propeller increases, indicate the corresponding area in the diagram:",
    "feedback": "from point 1 to point 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "To ensure ignition in conditions of high altitude and low temperature, a gas turbine ignition system:",
    "feedback": "Supplies a heat-intense spark"
  },
  {
    "question": "The hydraulic oil, entering the hydraulic pump, is slightly pressurised to :",
    "feedback": "prevent cavitation in the pump"
  },
  {
    "question": "The opening of the doors giving access to the oxygen masks for the passengers is :\n\n1. pneumatic for the gaseous oxygen system,\n2. electrical for the chemical oxygen system,\n3. pneumatic for the chemical oxygen system,\n4. electrical for the gaseous oxygen system.\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The bleed air gauge measures air pressure relative to:",
    "feedback": "Atmospheric pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "Select the correct answer from the following statements:\n1) When a DC generator is supplied with a current at the commutator, the armature rotates. The DC generator is converted into a DC motor2) The larger and heavier an engine spool is, the higher the required torque is to accelerate the spool from standstill to engine self-sustained rotation speed",
    "feedback": "1) and 2) are correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The expression \"primary flight control\" applies to the:\n\n1) elevator\n2) speed brake\n3) lift-augmentation devices\n4) roll spoiler\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the statements about frequency definition and its SI unit are correct or incorrect?\n1) The SI unit for frequency is revolutions per minute (RPM)2) Frequency is defined as a number of cycles per unit of time",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.\n\nGEN 2 can be used to feed the DC BUS 1, when:\n(NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumend to remain open)",
    "feedback": "C1.4, C3.1, C3.2 and C5.1 are closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "How much ice should be allowed to accumulate on the leading edge of the wing before the \"de-ice boot\" system is activated?",
    "feedback": "1/4\" - 1/2\""
  },
  {
    "question": "A safe life aircraft structural component:",
    "feedback": "may be used during a declared number of cycles or flight hours"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the normal method of lowering the hydraulic operated retractable landing gear fails, there has to be an alternate method, this usually works as?",
    "feedback": "A system integrated with the original that allows the gear, by mean of its own weight and aerodynamic resistance, to mechanically lock in place."
  },
  {
    "question": "The power of a normally aspirated piston engine decreases during a climb with a constant power lever setting because of the decreasing:",
    "feedback": "air density"
  },
  {
    "question": "During re-fuelling the automatic fuelling shut off valves will switch off the fuel supply system when:",
    "feedback": "the fuel has reached a predetermined volume or mass."
  },
  {
    "question": "A modern hydraulic system typically includes hydraulic fuses. Their function is:",
    "feedback": "to prevent total system loss in case of a leaking hydraulic line."
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft magneto is switched off by",
    "feedback": "grounding the primary circuit"
  },
  {
    "question": "The logic symbol shown represents (assuming positive logic) :",
    "feedback": "a NOR-Gate."
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding carburettor ice, state the environmental caution areas for the formation of this type of ice.",
    "feedback": "Temperature between - 5° C and + 18° C, visible moisture or relative humidity greater than 60 %."
  },
  {
    "question": "Ohm's law states that in an electric circuit:",
    "feedback": "the current passing through a resistor between two points is inversely proportional to the resistance between those two points"
  },
  {
    "question": "A significant increase in battery temperature during charge is an indication of ....",
    "feedback": "thermal runaway"
  },
  {
    "question": "The oil reservoir in a hydraulic system has the purpose to serve as:",
    "feedback": "All of the given alternatives are correct."
  },
  {
    "question": "The power of a piston engine decreases during climb with a constant power lever setting, because of the decreasing :",
    "feedback": "air density."
  },
  {
    "question": "In which sections of the carburettor would icing most likely occur?",
    "feedback": "venturi and the throttle valve"
  },
  {
    "question": "Fuel is fed to the engine from the supply system via the:",
    "feedback": "fuel manifold."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements concerning a sandwich structural part are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) A sandwich structural part consists of two thin sheets enclosing a light core material\n2) A sandwich structural part is suitable for absorbing concentrated loads",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
    "feedback": "Aircraft certification specifications cover aspects such as design, material quality and build quality"
  },
  {
    "question": "When changing power on engines equipped with constant-speed propeller, engine overload is avoided by :",
    "feedback": "increasing the RPM before the manifold pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "If a current is passed through a conductor which is positioned in a magnetic field :",
    "feedback": "a force will be exerted on the conductor."
  },
  {
    "question": "The reason for the trim switch on a control column to consist of two separate switches is",
    "feedback": "To reduce the probability of a trim-runaway"
  },
  {
    "question": "Large transport aircraft hydraulic systems usually operate with a system pressure of approximately:",
    "feedback": "3000 psi"
  },
  {
    "question": "The maximum quantity of fuel that can be dumped with the jettisoning system is:",
    "feedback": "All up to a defined reserve quantity."
  },
  {
    "question": "A gas turbine engine operates in accordance with the:",
    "feedback": "Brayton cycle."
  },
  {
    "question": "A sandwich type structure is often used in aircraft because of its:",
    "feedback": "low mass and high stiffness"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does active clearance control work?",
    "feedback": "It tries to minimize the gap between the turbine blades and the casing, therefore the outer casing is being cooled to minimize the separation"
  },
  {
    "question": "The metal box surrounding a lithium battery is used:",
    "feedback": "To withhold a thermal runaway"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where are spoilers fitted?",
    "feedback": "Symmetrically on the wing upper surface."
  },
  {
    "question": "During a compressor surge, thrust will:",
    "feedback": "decrease."
  },
  {
    "question": "The maximum cabin differential pressure of an aeroplane with a maximum certified altitude of 41000 ft is approximately:",
    "feedback": "9.0 psi"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about oxygen in transport aeroplanes is correct?",
    "feedback": "Chemical oxygen generators are not used in the cockpit to supply the flight crew because they cannot be switched off"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why do the deice boots inflate alternately?",
    "feedback": "Alternate inflation of the tubes keeps the disturbance of the airflow to a minimum."
  },
  {
    "question": "The fan in a high by-pass ratio turbo-jet engine produces:",
    "feedback": "the greatest part of the thrust"
  },
  {
    "question": "When TRU 1 has a failure:",
    "feedback": "DC BUS 1 can be restored through  DC X-TIE function"
  },
  {
    "question": "The advantages of nickel-cadmium, compared with lead acid batteries, are:\n\n1) lower risk of thermal runaway\n2) higher internal resistance, hence higher power\n3) reduced charging time\n4) constant output voltage\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is decreased?\n\n1) The propeller blade angle increases\n2) The free power turbine speed increases",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "What can be the consequence during a descent with a fully open throttle if the waste gate is seized?",
    "feedback": "The manifold air pressure (MAP) value may exceed the maximum allowed value."
  },
  {
    "question": "The capacity of a typical lead acid battery for aviation use is",
    "feedback": "12-18 Ah."
  },
  {
    "question": "Increasing the frequency of variations in the thrust setting during normal operation is detrimental to the life of HP turbine blades because:",
    "feedback": "low cycle fatigue damage is more severe"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a persistent over-excitation limit fault exists on an AC generator connected to the aircraft mains with another AC generator, the over-excitation protection device opens:",
    "feedback": "the exciter breaker and the generator breaker."
  },
  {
    "question": "When applying precautionary carburettor heating on a reciprocating engine with a constant speed propeller in its constant speed range:",
    "feedback": "the mixture becomes richer"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the profile grooves or the tread of a new aircraft tyre are worn, the tyre can be:",
    "feedback": "Repaired several times."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is (are) the damping element(s) in a landing gear shock absorber used on larger aircraft ?",
    "feedback": "Nitrogen and a viscous liquid."
  },
  {
    "question": "The bleed air pressure gauge on the flight deck shows the bleed air pressure relative to ....",
    "feedback": "atmospheric static pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning passenger oxygen mask presentation, the oxygen flow starts:",
    "feedback": "after pulling the oxygen mask towards the face"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a turbo compressor air conditioning system (bootstrap system), the main water separation unit is located:",
    "feedback": "after the cooling turbine."
  },
  {
    "question": "In order to enable a fire to be controlled as quickly as possible, the fire detectors are located in the highest risk compartments. Theses compartments are :\n\n1. the main landing gear wheel wells\n2. the fuel tanks\n3. the oil tanks\n4. the auxiliary power unit\n5. around the engines\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1,4,5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Shimmy occurs on the nosewheel landing gear during taxiing when:\n\n1. the wheels tend to describe a sinusoidal motion on the ground\n2. the wheels no longer respond to the pilot's actions\n\nThis effect is overcome by means of:\n\n3. the torque link\n4. an accumulator associated with the steering cylinder\n\nThe combination of correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 4."
  },
  {
    "question": "Determine the maximum operating altitude for an aircraft with a maximum differential pressure of 7,04 psi and a cabin altitude of 4.000 ft from the figure below:",
    "feedback": "24.000 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is required to create stress corrosion cracking?",
    "feedback": "Tensile stress and a corrosive environment"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cabin differential pressure means the pressure difference between:",
    "feedback": "cabin pressure and ambient air pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about rudder pedal nose wheel steering of a jet transport areoplane is correct?",
    "feedback": "Manual or tiller nose wheel steering offers a larger maximum deflection of the nose wheel than rudder pedal nose wheel steering"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FADEC (Full Authority Digital Engine Control):\n1) Provides fully automatic engine starting\n2) modifies aircraft airspeed in order to allow for the lowest fuel consumption\n3) counters any yaw movement in case of engine failure\n4) provides thrust reverser control\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The power output of a diesel engine without a turbo charger is regulated by:",
    "feedback": "fuel flow only"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is increased?\n\n1) The propeller blade angle remains constant\n2) The free power turbine speed decreases",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Using compressor bleed air to power systems:",
    "feedback": "decreases aircraft performance"
  },
  {
    "question": "The compressor pressure ratio is the ratio between the:",
    "feedback": "compressor pressure at the outlet of the compressor and the pressure at the inlet of the compressor"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements regarding most gust lock systems is correct?",
    "feedback": "When the gust lock is ON there is protection to prevent take-off"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pressurized aeroplane is flying at FL 370 and experiences a rapid decompression.  Which of the following statements about the oxygen system is correct?",
    "feedback": "If the automatic presentation of passenger oxygen masks does not function, dropping the passenger oxygen masks can be manually activated from the flight deck"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pressure in the individual combustion chambers is balanced:",
    "feedback": "by pressure balanced tubes between each combustion chamber."
  },
  {
    "question": "In the airflow through a single-spool axial flow turbo-jet engine, the axial velocity of the air is greatest:",
    "feedback": "on exit from the propelling nozzle."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is increased?\n\n1) The propeller blade angle increases\n2) The free power turbine speed decreases",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "The automatic ground spoiler extension system is normally activated during landing by:",
    "feedback": "main wheel spin up"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Number in the graph that shows the side stay/strut is:",
    "feedback": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Full Authority Digital Engine Control (FADEC) of a turbojet engine has the following functions:\n\n1) flow regulation (fuel, decelerations and accelerations monitoring)\n2) automatic starting sequence\n3) transmissions of engine data to the pilot's instruments\n4) thrust monitoring\n5) engine limit protection\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "After experiencing a loud bang, you notice a master caution annunciator and a large yawing moment to the right, that you correct by pressing the left rudder. As the pilot flying in this twin engine jet aircraft, you ask the pilot monitoring to \"state the malfunction\" and thereafter you get the following reply:\n\"Number 2 engine - no N1 rotation, high EGT, no N2 rotation, no fuel flow, high oil temperature, low oil pressure, high vibration\".\nWhat has most likely happened?",
    "feedback": "The right engine has ingested FOD"
  },
  {
    "question": "The type of gate that requires all \"true\" inputs for a \"true\" output is:",
    "feedback": "AND"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about a gust lock system are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) There should be suitable design precautions to prevent flight with the gust lock engaged\n2) Reversible flight controls should have a gust lock",
    "feedback": "1) is correct 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an air cycle machine (boostrap system), the main water separation unit is located:",
    "feedback": "after the cooling turbine"
  },
  {
    "question": "The aircraft tyres could undergo a pre-flight inspection. Which of the following options best characterises a condition when a tyre may still be acceptable (airworthy)?",
    "feedback": "A couple of cuts within the tyre tread"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which logic gate is represented by symbol 2?",
    "feedback": "NAND"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Number in the graph that shows the main leg oleo strut is:",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an aircraft equipped with a DC main power system, AC for instrument operation may be obtained from :",
    "feedback": "an inverter."
  },
  {
    "question": "Vibration sensors are used in a gas turbine engine to indicate:",
    "feedback": "imbalance of one or both of the spools"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the total volume in the cylinder of a four stroke engine?",
    "feedback": "Swept volume plus clearance volume."
  },
  {
    "question": "The turbine in a cold air unit (air cycle machine):",
    "feedback": "drives the compressor in the unit, creating a temperature drop in the conditioning air."
  },
  {
    "question": "In flight, if the temperature of the constant speed drive (CSD) indicator is in the red arc the:",
    "feedback": "pilot must disconnect it, and the generator is not available for the rest of flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of an air conditioning pack inlet flow valve (pack valve) is to:",
    "feedback": "maintain a constant and sufficient air mass flow to ventilate the cabin."
  },
  {
    "question": "A passenger emergency mask is a :",
    "feedback": "continuous flow mask and cannot be used if there is smoke in the cabin."
  },
  {
    "question": "A wing structure consists primarily of:",
    "feedback": "a front and rear main spar with ribs and stringers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements regarding variable inlet guide vanes (VIGVs) and variable stator vanes (VSVs) on a high-bypass engine is correct?",
    "feedback": "VIGVs are located at the front of the HP compressor and, together with the VSVs, control compressor airflow"
  },
  {
    "question": "The octane rating of a fuel and compression rating of a piston engine have which of the following relations?",
    "feedback": "the higher the octane, the higher the possible compression"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of a feed box in the fuel tank is to",
    "feedback": "increase the fuel level at the boost pump location"
  },
  {
    "question": "Oxygen systems are systems used on pressurized airplanes in :\n\n1. an emergency in the case of depressurization.\n2. an emergency in the case of the indisposition of a passenger.\n3. normal use in order to supply oxygen to the cabin.\n4. an emergency in the case of smoke or toxic gases.\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1,4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The best power mixture is that fuel/air ratio at which:",
    "feedback": "The most power can be obtained for any given throttle setting."
  },
  {
    "question": "A manifold pressure gauge of a piston engine measures:",
    "feedback": "absolute pressure in intake system behind the throttle valve"
  },
  {
    "question": "Complete the following statement:\nThe purpose of the active clearance control system in a gas turbine engine is to maintain a (1) .... separation between the turbine and the outer casing, by providing cooling air to the turbine (2) ....",
    "feedback": "(1) minimum, (2) outer case"
  },
  {
    "question": "An airplane whose maximum approved passenger seating configuration is 501 to 600 seats must be equipped with at least:",
    "feedback": "7 hand fire-extinguishers conveniently located in the passenger compartment."
  },
  {
    "question": "On large modern transport aircraft, the brake assembly consists of?",
    "feedback": "Multiple disk brake type."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a piston engine, the purpose of an altitude mixture control is to :",
    "feedback": "correct for variations in the fuel/air ratio due to decreased air density at altitude."
  },
  {
    "question": "When altitude increases without adjustment of the mixture ratio, the piston engine performance is affected because of a :",
    "feedback": "decreasing of air density for a constant quantity of fuel."
  },
  {
    "question": "One essential law of magnetism is:",
    "feedback": "A permanent magnet bar will always have a north and a south pole."
  },
  {
    "question": "According CS 25 the worst effect of a hazardous failure on the flight crew could be",
    "feedback": "physical distress or excessive workload, impairs ability to perform tasks"
  },
  {
    "question": "The diffuser in a gas turbine engine is a device in which the:",
    "feedback": "pressure rises and velocity falls."
  },
  {
    "question": "Under normal running conditions a magneto draws primary current :",
    "feedback": "from a self-contained electro-magnetic induction system."
  },
  {
    "question": "On the diagram showing the power output of a piston engine as a function of mixture ratio the mixture becomes leaner when moving from:",
    "feedback": "point 1 to point 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The automatic fuelling shut-off valve:",
    "feedback": "stops fuelling as soon as a certain fuel level is reached inside the tank"
  },
  {
    "question": "The 'slipstream effect' of a propeller is most prominent at:",
    "feedback": "low airspeeds with high power setting."
  },
  {
    "question": "If there is a single input data failure on a FADEC gas turbine engine:",
    "feedback": "the engine continues to operate normally"
  },
  {
    "question": "One function of a rib is:",
    "feedback": "to maintain the aerodynamic shape of the wing"
  },
  {
    "question": "During start of an engine fitted with a brushless AC generator with no commutator rings, the generator is activated by:",
    "feedback": "a set of permanent magnets"
  },
  {
    "question": "The reason for a double switch on the elevator trim is:",
    "feedback": "to reduce the probability of a trim runaway."
  },
  {
    "question": "The anti-icing method for the wings of large jet transport aeroplanes most commonly used in flight is:",
    "feedback": "thermal (use of hot air)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of variable by-pass valves in a high bypass turbofan engine between the LP compressor and the HP compressor (HPC) is to:",
    "feedback": "prevent fan stall and LP compressor stall during engine start and low rotor speeds"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a hydraulic system, a shuttle valve:",
    "feedback": "enables an alternate system to operate the same actuators in case of normal system failure"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of the cabin pressurisation system outflow valves?",
    "feedback": "To maximize the cabin pressure differential up to cruising altitude."
  },
  {
    "question": "In hydraulic systems of modern transport category aircraft the fluids used are:",
    "feedback": "Synthetic oil."
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the advantages of a turbocharger is that:",
    "feedback": "to make the power available less affected by altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "Whilst performing a regular flight, the pilots notice a fuel imbalance, with the right wing tank holding more fuel than the left wing tank. The crew manage to confirm that there is no fuel leak causing the imbalance. Which of the following should the crew do to restore the aircraft balance?",
    "feedback": "Open the crossfeed valve and shut off the left wing tank fuel pump(s)"
  },
  {
    "question": "When an electrical supply becomes \"open circuit\" the  :",
    "feedback": "loss of continuity will prevent its working components from functioning."
  },
  {
    "question": "To reverse the direction of rotation of a shunt-type (parallel field) DC electric motor, it is necessary to:",
    "feedback": "reverse the polarity of either the stator or the rotor"
  },
  {
    "question": "The heating facility for the windshield of an aircraft is:",
    "feedback": "Used on a continual basis as it reduces the thermal gradients which adversely affect the useful life of the components."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is true regarding a thermal runaway?\n1) A thermal runaway is an uncontrolled positive feedback loop2) A lithium-ion battery that has been damaged externally may suffer from a thermal runaway",
    "feedback": "1) and 2) are correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Nozzle guide vanes:",
    "feedback": "give the gas a swirl."
  },
  {
    "question": "When pressurising the cabin of an aircraft, the cabin pressure controller operates the",
    "feedback": "outflow valve"
  },
  {
    "question": "A \"slat\" on a wing is?",
    "feedback": "A leading edge device that causes some of the high energy air to flow over the upper surface of the wing."
  },
  {
    "question": "A turbofan engine with an inlet air mass flow of 220 kg/s and HP compressor mass flow of 20 kg/s has a bypass ratio of ....",
    "feedback": "10"
  },
  {
    "question": "A fire warning will indicate as:",
    "feedback": "Continuous bell, red master warning light, red light on engine fire extinguisher button"
  },
  {
    "question": "On most high by-pass ratio (fan) engines, reverse thrust is achieved by reversing:",
    "feedback": "only the direction of the fan airflow"
  },
  {
    "question": "During climb with constant throttle and RPM lever setting (mixture being constant) the :",
    "feedback": "Manifold Air Pressure (MAP) decreases."
  },
  {
    "question": "The emergency lighting system must be able to function and supply a certain level of lighting after the main electric power system has been cut off for at least:",
    "feedback": "10 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "What regulates the fuel-mixture ratio in a FADEC-equipped piston engine?",
    "feedback": "FADEC computer"
  },
  {
    "question": "The built-in passenger oxygen system can be activated by :",
    "feedback": "switching the passenger oxygen ON."
  },
  {
    "question": "The auxiliary fuel pumps are:",
    "feedback": "electrically driven and are connected in series with the main fuel booster pump."
  },
  {
    "question": "The mixture control for a carburettor achieves its control by:",
    "feedback": "varying the fuel supply to the main discharge tube."
  },
  {
    "question": "Static gas temperature decreases when flowing at a subsonic speed through a jet engine exhaust nozzle, because the:",
    "feedback": "exhaust nozzle is convergent"
  },
  {
    "question": "In aeronautics, the most commonly used batteries are NiCd because...",
    "feedback": "they weigh less than lead-acid batteries."
  },
  {
    "question": "In an aircraft utilising a constant frequency AC power supply, DC power is obtained from a :",
    "feedback": "Transformer Rectifier Unit."
  },
  {
    "question": "If the turbocharger waste gate is completely closed",
    "feedback": "All the exhaust gases are directed through the turbine"
  },
  {
    "question": "When in flight, a piston engine is stopped and the propeller blade pitch angle is near 90°, the propeller is said to be...",
    "feedback": "feathered."
  },
  {
    "question": "The kind of compressor normally used as a turbocharger is :",
    "feedback": "a radial compressor."
  },
  {
    "question": "On starting, in a brushless AC generator with no commutator rings, the generator is activated by:",
    "feedback": "a set of permanent magnets."
  },
  {
    "question": "The engine component between station numbers 2 and 3 is the:",
    "feedback": "LP compressor"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the control stick of an aircraft is moved forward and to the right, the left aileron will move:",
    "feedback": "Down, and the elevator will move down."
  },
  {
    "question": "If two constant frequency AC generators are operating independently, then the phase relationship of each generator:",
    "feedback": "is unimportant."
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens to the indications on a cabin VSI, cabin altimeter and differential pressure gauge if an aircraft suffers a decompression?",
    "feedback": "VSI up, altimeter up, differential pressure gauge down."
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft flying in conditions of continuous heavy rain and high ambient temperatures may require the precautionary use of:",
    "feedback": "engine igniters"
  },
  {
    "question": "The cabin pressure is regulated by the:",
    "feedback": "Outflow valve."
  },
  {
    "question": "The logic symbol shown represents (assuming positive logic) :",
    "feedback": "an INVERT or NOT gate."
  },
  {
    "question": "On most aircraft fitted with gas turbine engines, prior to engine shut down, if the engine temperatures are too high:",
    "feedback": "the engine must be run at idle rpm until it cools down."
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a voltage regulator is to control the output voltage of the :",
    "feedback": "generator at varying loads and speeds."
  },
  {
    "question": "The equipment of an oxygen supply installation must be kept absolutely free of oil or grease traces as:",
    "feedback": "these substances catch fire spontaneously in the presence of oxygen under pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an anti-skid system are correct or incorrect?\n1) In case of failure of an anti-skid system the auto-brake system takes over the regulation of the slip ratio\n2) Careful brake application by the pilot in case of anti-skid failure can never achieve the same performance as a properly functioning anti-skid system",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the attached diagram, the type of stress acting on the point indicated by the image number 3 is the:",
    "feedback": "torque"
  },
  {
    "question": "Modern fly-by-wire systems feature different modes of operation. Which one is the most basic?",
    "feedback": "Direct mode"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hydraulic fluids used in aircraft are mainly synthetic and mineral fluids. Can both types of fluids be used together?",
    "feedback": "No, because the system components are specifically made for used of one of them."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of the pack cooling fans in the air conditioning system?",
    "feedback": "Supplying the heat exchangers with cooling air during slow flights and ground operation."
  },
  {
    "question": "Viscosity is",
    "feedback": "the tendency of a liquid or gas to resist flow"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct about the flow in a divergent (subsonic) gas turbine engine intake?\n\n1) The static pressure increases in flow direction\n2) The total temperature increases in flow direction",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot can determin the amound of oxygen in a bottle by observing its:",
    "feedback": "pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "A lithium-ion battery can be considered most unsafe.......",
    "feedback": "When the battery has an internal short circuit"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the advantages of an annular combustion chamber over a multiple can is that:",
    "feedback": "the thermal load distribution on the HP turbine is more favourable"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some gas turbine engines have multiple stages in the HP and LP turbines:",
    "feedback": "because one stage does not generate sufficient shaft power"
  },
  {
    "question": "An airplane whose maximum approved passenger seating configuration is 61 to 200 seats must be equipped with at least:",
    "feedback": "3 hand fire-extinguishers conveniently located in the passenger compartment."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the colour code associated with AVGAS 100?",
    "feedback": "green"
  },
  {
    "question": "A booster or LP compressor in a twin spool turbofan:",
    "feedback": "rotates at the same rotor speed as the fan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Compressor surge may be controlled by means of:",
    "feedback": "bleed valves"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about the working principle of an electrical motor are correct or incorrect?\n1) The amount of mechanical torque (T) an electrical motor produces is proportional to the voltage (E) multiplied by the current supplied to the motor (T is proportional to E x I) and inversely proportional to the resulting magnetic field within the motor.\n2) The amount of mechanical torque an electrical engine produces is proportional to the voltage divided by the current supplied to the motor (T is proportional to E/I) and also to the resulting magnetic field within the motor",
    "feedback": "1) and 2) are incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "An axial compressor stage is represented by:",
    "feedback": "figure 1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Most transport aeroplanes are provided with protection against control jamming. This means that:",
    "feedback": "the flight control system has provisions to disconned the part of the control system that becomes blocked"
  },
  {
    "question": "For internal cooling,reciprocating engines are especially dependent on:",
    "feedback": "the circulation of lubricating oil"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a compressor bleed valve is to prevent surging:",
    "feedback": "at low compressor RPM"
  },
  {
    "question": "The primary reason for a limitation being imposed on the temperature of gas flow in a gas turbine is to :",
    "feedback": "ensure that the maximum acceptable temperature at the turbine blades is not exceeded."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is identified as the cambered or curved side of a propeller\nblade, corresponding to the upper surface of a wing airfoil section ?",
    "feedback": "Blade back."
  },
  {
    "question": "The logic symbol shown represents (assuming positive logic) :",
    "feedback": "OR-Gate"
  },
  {
    "question": "The operating principle of float-type carburettors is based on the:",
    "feedback": "difference in air pressure at the venturi throat and the air inlet"
  },
  {
    "question": "NiCad batteries need to be tested by a regular maintenance schedule. The interval is dependent on ....",
    "feedback": "the result of the efficiency test"
  },
  {
    "question": "For a CS 25 aeroplane, spoilers are:",
    "feedback": "upper wing surface devices, their deflection is symmetrical or asymmetrical."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which part of the main landing gear is shown by the number 3?",
    "feedback": "Side stay/strut"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding a jet engine:\n\n1) The maximum thrust remains constant as the pressure altitude increases\n2) The specific fuel consumption decreases slightly as the pressure altitude increases at constant TAS",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a two generator system, a differential relay will ensure that :",
    "feedback": "generator voltages are almost equal before the generators are paralleled."
  },
  {
    "question": "In accordance with EASA AIR OPS, 100 % of the passengers in a non-pressurized airplane must have an oxygen supply reserve for the entire flight time at pressure altitudes greater than:",
    "feedback": "13000 ft."
  },
  {
    "question": "The bending loads on a cantilever wing due to lift are carried by the:\n\n1) upper skin surface\n2) lower skin surface\n3) wing root fairing\n4) spar or spars\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which logic gate is equivalent to symbol 5?",
    "feedback": "NOR"
  },
  {
    "question": "The most common voltage / frequency used in jet transport A/C is:",
    "feedback": "115 VAC / 400 Hz"
  },
  {
    "question": "Primary flight controls are:",
    "feedback": "ailerons, elevators and rudder"
  },
  {
    "question": "The output voltage of DC generators used in aircraft is normally regulated by:",
    "feedback": "Controlling the current in the field windings."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the engine control element the pilot may expect on the flight deck of an aircraft with a piston engine controlled by FADEC?",
    "feedback": "Crank switch"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is decreased?  1) The propeller blade angle remains constant 2) The free power turbine speed increases",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the pressure controller malfunctions and the outflow valve malfunctions (remains fully open), what happens to:\n\n(i)   cabin ROC\n(ii)  cabin altitude\n(III) differential pressure",
    "feedback": "(i) increase; (ii) increase; (iii) decrease"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of stringers in the construction of the fuselage is:",
    "feedback": "to provide support for the skin and to absorb some of the pressurization strain as tensile loading."
  },
  {
    "question": "The principle of aeroplane propulsion is to generate a propelling force by:",
    "feedback": "accelerating air or gas in order to obtain a reaction force"
  },
  {
    "question": "For a piston engine, the chemically correct fuel/air ratio is:",
    "feedback": "1:15"
  },
  {
    "question": "A FADEC piston engine has two .... to achieve redundancy",
    "feedback": "power supplies and two separate but identical channels"
  },
  {
    "question": "A modern small turbine engine, for example an APU, has.....",
    "feedback": "an electrical starter motor that uses battery power"
  },
  {
    "question": "Torching is a term sometimes used to describe:",
    "feedback": "an internal engine fire."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the function of an auto-slat system?",
    "feedback": "It provides improved stall characteristics at high angles of attack during take-off, approach, and landing"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the diagram showing the power output of a piston engine as a function of mixture ratio take-off power setting at sea level is shown at:",
    "feedback": "point 1"
  },
  {
    "question": "An impulse magneto coupling",
    "feedback": "gives a retarded spark at starting"
  },
  {
    "question": "The power of a piston engine which will be measured by using a friction brake is :",
    "feedback": "Brake horse power."
  },
  {
    "question": "The number of emergency exits in transport aeroplanes",
    "feedback": "must be arranged to allow all passengers and all crew members to leave the aeroplane within 90 sec. through 50 % of the available emergency exits."
  },
  {
    "question": "If the manifold pressure gauge of a piston engine shows an increase shortly after carburettor heat is turned on, it indicates:",
    "feedback": "ice was forming in the carburettor"
  },
  {
    "question": "The auto-brake system stops operating during landing:",
    "feedback": "by the pilot pressing the brake pedals"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information about an aeroplane with a turbojet engine:\n\nmass air flow 50 kg/s\nTAS 90 m/s\nexhaust nozzle gas velocity 150 m/s\nexhaust nozzle static pressure 1050 hPa\nambient static pressure 1000 hPa\ncross-sectional area of the nozzle 0.10 m2\n\nNet engine thrust equals:",
    "feedback": "3500 N"
  },
  {
    "question": "Carburettor icing can occur when the outside airtemperature is between:",
    "feedback": "-5° C to + 18° C."
  },
  {
    "question": "Check the following statements regarding the implications of mode degradation:\n1) Mode degradation affects flight envelope protection, allowing control commands that may force the aircraft to exceed its structural and aerodynamic operating limits.2) Mode degradation may increase pilot workload significantly.",
    "feedback": "1) and 2) are correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The advantage of  mounting the tailplane on top of the vertical stabilizer is :",
    "feedback": "to withdraw it from the influence of wing turbulence"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the venturi in a carburettor is to:",
    "feedback": "create the depression necessary to cause fuel to flow through the carburettor jets."
  },
  {
    "question": "An impulse coupling does not function at such speeds above those encountered in starting. Its engaging pawls are prevented from operating at higher speeds by",
    "feedback": "centrifugal force"
  },
  {
    "question": "The bypass ratio:\n\n1) is the ratio of inlet airflow to HP compressor flow\n2) can be determined from the inlet air mass flow and the HP compressor mass flow",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a wire type fire system is tested:",
    "feedback": "the wiring and the warning are tested."
  },
  {
    "question": "On the ground, the Auxiliary Power Unit (APU) can be substituted for the following ground support equipment:",
    "feedback": "ground power unit, the starting system, the air conditioning unit."
  },
  {
    "question": "What does valve overlap promote?",
    "feedback": "Better scavenging and cooling characteristics."
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the figure below:  In a pressurized aircraft whose cabin altitude is 6000 ft, a crack in a cabin window makes it necessary to reduce the differential pressure to 7 psi. The flight level to be maintained in order to keep the same cabin altitude is:",
    "feedback": "28000 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "A primary stop is mounted on an elevator control system in order to:",
    "feedback": "restrict the range of movement of the elevator."
  },
  {
    "question": "The safety precautions to be taken whenever using oxygen are:\n\n1. refrain from smoking, avoid sparkes.\n2. Avoid operation of radio communication equipment.\n3. Slowly operate oxygen system valves.\n4. Avoid greasy matter.\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4."
  },
  {
    "question": "The number of manual fire-extinguishers, on board the passenger cabin of an airplane, whose maximum approved configuration for passenger seats is 31, is:",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a modern transport aircraft, in the event of a total AC generator failure, ......",
    "feedback": "a static inverter converts 24V DC from the batteries to 115V AC for essential AC services"
  },
  {
    "question": "A twin-spool engine with a bypass mass flow of 500 kg/s and HP compressor mass flow of 250 kg/s has a bypass ratio of ....",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The blade angle of a constant-speed propeller",
    "feedback": "increases with increasing true air speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "What would the corrective action be if engine detonation occurs in a climb out?",
    "feedback": "Retard throttle"
  },
  {
    "question": "On Airbus airplanes, both sidesticks are not mechanically linked. This means that both sticks may be operated independently of each other. How does a pilot take control over the other sidestick?",
    "feedback": "A priority push-button is provided on each stick. By pressing this button, a pilot may cancel the inputs of the other pilot"
  },
  {
    "question": "The cylinder head and oil temperatures may exceed their normal operating ranges if:",
    "feedback": "a lower octane rating than specified for the engine is used"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.\n\nGEN 1 can be used to feed the DC BUS 2, when:\n(NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumend to remain open)",
    "feedback": "C1.1, C3.1, C3.2 and C5.3 are closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Parameters to monitor a hydraulic system in the cockpit can be:",
    "feedback": "pressure, fluid temperature and quantity"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pressurization of tanks is maintained by the fuel:",
    "feedback": "vent system."
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeroplane equipped with reversible flight controls:",
    "feedback": "does not require an artificial feel system"
  },
  {
    "question": "The constant speed propeller has",
    "feedback": "only above and below the design point a better efficiency than the fixed propeller with the same design speed."
  },
  {
    "question": "If the discharge valves fail in the closed position in flight, the effect will be:",
    "feedback": "the cabin pressure will rise to maximum differential pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot is required to check the wheels and tyres during the pre-flight check. Which statement is correct or incorrect?\n1) Tread separation is easily detected by visual inspection2) Small bulb or tread separation is acceptable as long as it is reported in the flight log",
    "feedback": "1) incorrect, 2) incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Select the correct statement(s) regarding fly-by-wire control systems (FBW):\n1) FBW flight Control Laws/Modes depend on data from several sensors such as airspeed, attitude and angle of attack2) Dual inputs by the pilots, commanding contradictory movement of the flying controls, are not possible",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is not correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "A short circuit can be caused by....",
    "feedback": "poor insulation of electric wire"
  },
  {
    "question": "A force gradient unit is used to:",
    "feedback": "add artifical feel into a hydraulically powered flight control system."
  },
  {
    "question": "The functions of an LP booster pump in a gas turbine fuel system are to:",
    "feedback": "avoid vapour locking and prevent cavitation of the HP fuel pump"
  },
  {
    "question": "The gas turbine illustrated comprises a:",
    "feedback": "free turbine and centrifugal compressor"
  },
  {
    "question": "The principle of the safe life design of an aircraft is based on the:",
    "feedback": "replacement of parts after a given number of cycles or hours of use"
  },
  {
    "question": "An oxygen regulator has 3 controls :\n\n- a power lever : ON/OFF\n- an \"O2\" lever : NORMAL/100%\n- an emergency lever : ON/OFF\n\nAmong the following statements, the correct proposition is :",
    "feedback": "the power lever on ON, and, the \"O2\" lever on NORMAL allows the oxygen to enter the regulator and enables breathing of a mixture of air/oxygen according to altitude."
  },
  {
    "question": "Given an aeroplane with irreversible primary flight controls, how is control maintained if one hydraulic system is lost due to a hydraulic leak?",
    "feedback": "The remaining systems will take over control"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a reciprocating engine oil system, the temperature bulb senses oil temperature",
    "feedback": "at a point after the oil has passed through the oil cooler."
  },
  {
    "question": "In general, in twin-engine aeroplanes with 'constant speed propeller'",
    "feedback": "the oil pressure turns the propeller blades towards smaller pitch angle."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following types of aircraft tyre damage, if identified during an inspection, require a tyre to be replaced before the next flight?\n1) Asymmetrical tread wear2) Small cuts in the tread surface3) Detachment of tread, exposing the tyre carcass4) A bulge in the sidewall5) Oil contamination on the tyre surface",
    "feedback": "3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "To prevent the landing gear from collapsing when the aircraft is parked on the ground by, following device is used:",
    "feedback": "locking pins with flags"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeroplane engine usually has two idle settings: Flight idle and ground idle.  Flight idle corresponds to a higher power setting.  This is because ......",
    "feedback": "engine thrust needs to be readily available upon go-around"
  },
  {
    "question": "Bleed air is used to",
    "feedback": "cabin pressurizing"
  },
  {
    "question": "The thermal efficiency of a gas turbine engine will increase with a:",
    "feedback": "decrease in ambient air temperature."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the two main types of landing gear used on modern aircraft?",
    "feedback": "Telescopic and sprung leg."
  },
  {
    "question": "When the AC generators are connected in parallel, the reactive loads are balanced by means of the:",
    "feedback": "energizing current."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is 'hard time' maintenance of an aircraft component?",
    "feedback": "A component that is overhauled or replaced after a set number of hours, cycles or operations."
  },
  {
    "question": "A complete air-conditioning system includes at least:",
    "feedback": "air cycle machine"
  },
  {
    "question": "If two identical batteries are connected in series:",
    "feedback": "the output voltage will double and the capacity expressed in ampere hours will remain the same"
  },
  {
    "question": "On most transport aircraft, the low pressure pumps of the fuel system are:",
    "feedback": "Centrifugal pumps."
  },
  {
    "question": "The use of a hot air wing anti-icing system:",
    "feedback": "does not affect aerodynamic performance of the wing and causes a reduction in maximum thrust"
  },
  {
    "question": "Assume that during cruise flight with air conditioning packs ON, all the outflow valves close:",
    "feedback": "the pressure differential would go to the maximum value"
  },
  {
    "question": "As regards passengers oxygen in public transport aircraft, information must be given to passengers through a demonstration. If a flight is to be carried out at Flight Level FL 290, this demonstration must be completed before :",
    "feedback": "take-off."
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens if both pilots move their sidesticks in an FBW controlled aircraft at the same time?",
    "feedback": "Their commands are algebraically summed together"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the function of the X-TIE?",
    "feedback": "To allow DC BUS 2 to be supplied in the case of a failure of TRU 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of gas turbine engine trending is:",
    "feedback": "to enhance maintenance planning and detect anomalies"
  },
  {
    "question": "The presence of carburetor ice, in an airplane equipped with a fixed-pitch propeller\ncan be verified by applying carburettor heat and noting",
    "feedback": "a decrease in RPM, followed by an increase in RPM."
  },
  {
    "question": "Over-tensioned cables in a flight control system could result in:",
    "feedback": "excessive friction in the system."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is braided wire built into some electrical cables?",
    "feedback": "To protect the cable from electromagnetic induction from other electrical systems"
  },
  {
    "question": "Assuming the initiating cause is removed, which of these statements about resetting are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) A fuse is resettable\n2) A circuit breaker is resettable",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is increased?  1) The propeller blade angle increases 2) The free power turbine speed decreases",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning the twisting force acting on a propeller blade",
    "feedback": "the centrifugal twisting force tends to decrease the blade angle"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pilot detects a low oil pressure in the Integrated Drive Generator (IDG). The pilot ......",
    "feedback": "must operate the IDG disconnect switch"
  },
  {
    "question": "The number in the graph that shows the shock absorber is:",
    "feedback": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Compare the pressure ratio of a centrifugal compressor with the pressure ratio of an axial flow compressor stage. A typical value of the pressure ratio of a centrifugal compressor stage is:",
    "feedback": "4:1"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can you see the wear of a multi disk brake system commonly found on a commercial airliner?",
    "feedback": "Measuring the amount that the lining pin extends from the spring housing"
  },
  {
    "question": "An AC generator driven by a constant speed drive (CSD):",
    "feedback": "requires a voltage controller to maintain constant voltage under load."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an anti-skid system are correct or incorrect?\n1) In case of failure of an anti-skid system the auto-brake system takes over the regulation of the slip ratio\n2) Careful brake application by the pilot in case of anti-skid failure can achieve the same performance as a properly functioning anti-skid system",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Engine auxiliary gearboxes:",
    "feedback": "provide the drives for a wide variety of services and may even provide for the support of the engine in the airframe"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning the starting procedure of a gas turbine engine:",
    "feedback": "The selected igniters are activated before fuel is delivered to the fuel nozzles"
  },
  {
    "question": "The viscosity of a hydraulic fluid should be:",
    "feedback": "the lowest to minimize power consumption and resistance to flow."
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider a transport aircraft with dual hydraulic systems. How will the loss of hydraulic pressure from one system normally be indicated in the cockpit?",
    "feedback": "Master caution light, dedicated amber light and loss of pressure reading for the affected system"
  },
  {
    "question": "Relationships between the force, pressure and area",
    "feedback": "force = pressure x area"
  },
  {
    "question": "Compressor stall in a gas turbine engine:",
    "feedback": "can be caused by an axial airflow velocity that is low relative to the rotor speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Trailing edge flaps:",
    "feedback": "increase lift at a lower AOA."
  },
  {
    "question": "When using magnetic measuring-type dip sticks, the quantity of fuel in the aircraft is determined by using the measurements ....",
    "feedback": "from the dip sticks and data tables in the aircraft documentation"
  },
  {
    "question": "A current limiter fuse in a DC system is used to :",
    "feedback": "allow a short term overload before rupturing."
  },
  {
    "question": "When the magneto selector switch is set to \"OFF\" position, the piston engine continues to run normally.\nThe most probable cause of this failure is that:",
    "feedback": "On a magneto, a grounding wire is broken."
  },
  {
    "question": "On turbojet aircraft the primary source of compressed air is:",
    "feedback": "bleed air from an engine driven compressor."
  },
  {
    "question": "In accordance with EASA AIR OPS and with the exception of amphibians and hydroplanes, the carriage of a life jacket per person on board is compulsory when the airplane is :  1. cruising at such a distance from the shore that it would not be able to return in the case of an engine failure. 2. is flying over a water surface at more than 50 NM off shore. 3. is using departure and arrival paths above the water and when a ditching probability exists in the case of a problem. 4. is flying over a stretch of water at more than 100 NM off shore.  The combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "According CS 25 the worst effect of a catastrophic failure on the aeroplane could be:",
    "feedback": "hull loss"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a hydraulic system the master cylinders inner diameter is 10 mm2, and the actuator \ncylinders inner diameter is 100 mm2.  If you press the master-cylinder 2 cm by using a 100 N force, the actuator cylinder will move:",
    "feedback": "2 mm and produce a force of 1000 N"
  },
  {
    "question": "The term \"bootstrap\", when used to identify a cabin air conditioning and pressurisation system, refers to the:",
    "feedback": "cold air unit (air cycle machine) arrangement."
  },
  {
    "question": "On the diagram showing the power output of a piston engine as a function of mixture ratio, best power is shown at:",
    "feedback": "point 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a hydraulic system, overheat detectors are mostly installed:",
    "feedback": "at the pumps."
  },
  {
    "question": "The maximum cabin differential pressure of a pressurized aeroplane operating at FL 370 is approximately:",
    "feedback": "9,0 psi"
  },
  {
    "question": "In order to produce an alternating voltage of 400 Hz, the number of polepairs required in an AC generator running at 6000 rpm is:",
    "feedback": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "One pound of air at altitude produces:",
    "feedback": "more thrust than it would at sea level."
  },
  {
    "question": "A unit that converts electrical DC into AC is :",
    "feedback": "an inverter."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements concerning oxygen on board of passenger transport aeroplanes is correct?",
    "feedback": "Lavatories also have an oxygen drop out system to protect passengers in case of decompression"
  },
  {
    "question": "The electronic engine control (EEC) of a gas turbine engine uses data from which of the following?\n1) Aircraft systems2) Cockpit display units3) Its own engine sensors4) Electronic engine control units of the other engine(s)",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Generators, when connected to the same bus bar, are usually connected:",
    "feedback": "in parallel mode"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the bootstrap system in cabin pressurisation?",
    "feedback": "The low pressure bleed air Cold Air Unit."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about a reaction turbine are correct or incorrect?  1) The pressure drops across the nozzle guide vanes 2) The pressure drops across the rotor blades",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "During climb with constant Manifold Air Pressure (MAP) and RPM indication and constant mixture setting, the power output of a piston engine :",
    "feedback": "increases."
  },
  {
    "question": "One strategy taken to contain battery thermal runaway is the installation of a ....",
    "feedback": "vented metal box that completely covers the battery"
  },
  {
    "question": "During hydroplaning, the friction coefficient between tyre and runway surface is approximately:",
    "feedback": "zero"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the typical hydraulic system represented, assuming hydraulic pressure throughout and no internal leakage:",
    "feedback": "a condition of hydraulic lock exists and no movement of the piston will take place"
  },
  {
    "question": "The output of the engine driven oil pump:",
    "feedback": "remains constant at all engine rpm values."
  },
  {
    "question": "During an exterior walkaround of the aircraft the pilot notices a yellow/brown leak on the engine cowling. This is likely to be ......",
    "feedback": "an oil leak from the engine or IDG (Integrated Drive Generator)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main purpose of a turbocharger is to:",
    "feedback": "maintain power with increasing altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hydraulic fluids should have the following characteristics:  1) thermal stability2) low emulsifying characteristics3) non-corrosive4) good resistance to combustion5) high compressibility6) high volatility7) high viscosity\n The combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "During cruising flight, when the throttle is slightly advanced on an aeroplane equipped with a constant speed propeller, the propeller pitch automatically:",
    "feedback": "increases and the RPM remains the same"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which part of the main landing gear is shown by the number 2?",
    "feedback": "Main leg oleo strut"
  },
  {
    "question": "A thermal relief valve is installed in order to?",
    "feedback": "Sense the ambient fluid temperature and when this temperature exceeds a pre-determined value, the valve depressurises the hydraulic system."
  },
  {
    "question": "If the manifold pressure is increased, the blade angle of a constant speed propeller:",
    "feedback": "will increase"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding a jet engine:\n\n1) The maximum thrust remains constant as the pressure altitude decreases\n2) The specific fuel consumption decreases slightly as the pressure altitude decreases, at constant TAS",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "A linear actuator has a damaged seal, resulting in an internal leak. In addition to a loss of actuator efficiency, this will result in:",
    "feedback": "an increase in fluid temperature."
  },
  {
    "question": "A flat rated turbofan engine has a constant maximum rated thrust level:",
    "feedback": "up to a specific OAT"
  },
  {
    "question": "Assuming the initiating cause is removed, which of these statements about resetting are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) A fuse is not resettable\n2) A circuit breaker is not resettable",
    "feedback": "1) is correct 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "A capacitor in parallel with breaker points:",
    "feedback": "prevents arcing across the breaker points"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a gas turbine engine is fitted with can-type combustion chambers:",
    "feedback": "a total of only two igniters are usually fitted since the chambers are inter-connected"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a Constant Speed Drive (CSD), often connected to a generator, is to keep",
    "feedback": "Constant speed on the generator."
  },
  {
    "question": "Engine bleed air used for air conditioning and pressurization in turbo-jet aeroplanes is usually taken from the:",
    "feedback": "compressor section."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is the capacitance-type fuel quantity gauge system the system that is most \noften used on large turbine aircraft?",
    "feedback": "Because it measures the mass of fuel rather than the volume of fuel in the tank."
  },
  {
    "question": "A waste gate is used to control a turbocharger's output by varying the quantity of exhaust gases passing to the turbocharger's (1) .... . A fully (2) .... waste gate will achieve the maximum turbocharger rotational speed.",
    "feedback": "(1) turbine, (2) closed"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an aircraft fitted with spoilers for lateral control, and not deployed as speed brakes, a roll to the right is initiated by:",
    "feedback": "Right spoiler extended, left spoiler retracted"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft climbs and in order to maintain the same cabin pressure during climb, what mode of operation will the pressurisation system make use of?",
    "feedback": "Isobaric."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the reason for putting the horizontal stabilizer on top of the fin?",
    "feedback": "To be out of the way of the wing down wash"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the diagram showing the power output of a piston engine as a function of mixture ratio, theoretical best economy is shown at:",
    "feedback": "point 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Baffles can be mounted inside the tanks to",
    "feedback": "prevent fuel sloshes."
  },
  {
    "question": "Immediately after starting engine(s) with no other electrical services switched on, an ammeter showing a high charge rate to the battery :",
    "feedback": "would be normal and is only cause for concern if the high charge rate persists."
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider a jet engine whose control is based on the Engine Pressure Ratio (EPR):\n\n1. with a constant EPR, the thrust decreases when the altitude increases\n2. with a constant EPR, the thrust is independent of the Mach number\n3. At same environmental conditions, a given EPR setting maintains the thrust irrespective of engine wear due to ageing.\n4. the EPR is determined by the impact pressure difference between the turbine outlet and the compressor inlet\n5. on take-off, in the event of icing not detected by the crew, the indicated EPR is lower than the real EPR\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 3."
  },
  {
    "question": "A diluter demand oxygen regulator selected to 100%:",
    "feedback": "delivers oxygen flow when inhaling."
  },
  {
    "question": "What could be a cause of a loop fault in a gas-filled fire detection system?",
    "feedback": "Decrease in loop pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about an auto-brake system during RTO (Rejected Take Off) is correct?",
    "feedback": "Without pilot interference an auto-brake system continues to operate until standstill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Engine Pressure Ratio (EPR) is the ratio of:",
    "feedback": "the total turbine outlet pressure to the total compressor inlet pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which logic gate is represented by symbol 1?",
    "feedback": "AND"
  },
  {
    "question": "The advantages of alternating current on board an aircraft are:\n1. simple connection\n2. high starting torque\n3. flexibility in use\n4. lighter weight of equipment\n5. easy to convert into direct current\n6. easy maintenance of machines\nThe combination of correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3, 4, 5, 6"
  },
  {
    "question": "The propeller blade angle is defined as the acute angle between the airfoil section chord line (at the blade reference station) and which of the following?",
    "feedback": "The plane of rotation."
  },
  {
    "question": "A semi-monocoque aircraft fuselage structure usually consists of:",
    "feedback": "skin, frames, stringers"
  },
  {
    "question": "If an artificial feel unit is fitted, it would be connected:",
    "feedback": "in parallel with the primary controls."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about a gust lock system are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) There is no need for a gust lock on irreversible flight controls\n2) There is no need for a gust lock on manual flight controls",
    "feedback": "1) is correct 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the auto-brakes are armed before landing one condition for the system to start operating is:",
    "feedback": "main wheel spin-up"
  },
  {
    "question": "During taxiing before take-off the normal auto-brake system selection before take-off is made. Immediately afterwards, but still before commencement of the take-off, heavy braking is applied. This causes the auto-brake system:",
    "feedback": "to remain in the selected mode"
  },
  {
    "question": "The wing ice protection system currently used on most modern jet aeroplanes is a(n):",
    "feedback": "hot air system"
  },
  {
    "question": "There are 60 passengers and crew members on board a turbo-prop aircraft. Its speed is 240 kt. At a point along the course steered, above the sea, the aircraft is at 1h45 min from an aerodrome suitable for emergency landing. The minimum equipment complying with regulations is :",
    "feedback": "60 life jackets and three 30-seat life boats"
  },
  {
    "question": "What will occur in a DC motor if it were to seize mechanically?\nThe current in the stator (1) ...., the current in the rotor (2) ...., and the torque (3) ....",
    "feedback": "(1) increases, (2) increases, (3) increases"
  },
  {
    "question": "Diesel engines, compared to petrol engines have:",
    "feedback": "a higher compression ratio"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the ground, the Auxiliary Power Unit (APU) of a large jet transport aeroplane directly provides:\n1) Electricity\n2) Air for main engine starting\n3) Hydraulic pressure\n4) Air for air conditioning\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "In flight the cantilever wing of an aircraft containing fuel  is subjected to vertical loads that produce a bending moment which is:",
    "feedback": "highest at the wing root"
  },
  {
    "question": "Prior to starting a reciprocating engine at sea level the manifold pressure gauge usually indicates approximately 29 inch Hg. This is because the:",
    "feedback": "pressure in the manifold is the same as atmospheric pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "One stage of an axial compressor comprises:",
    "feedback": "a row of rotor blades followed by a row of stator vanes"
  },
  {
    "question": "The term used to describe a permanent and cumulative deformation of the turbine blades in a gas turbine engine is:",
    "feedback": "creep"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the best way to test the charge level of a lead acid battery ?",
    "feedback": "By checking the specific gravity of the electrolyte."
  },
  {
    "question": "The voltage regulator of a DC generator is connected in :",
    "feedback": "series with the shunt field coil."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the indication that a dual control input is being made on an Airbus-type sidestick control?",
    "feedback": "Both inputs would be summed to the fly-by-wire computer"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of the primer pump in a reciprocating engine is to:",
    "feedback": "provide additional fuel for engine start"
  },
  {
    "question": "The hydraulic system that works correctly is shown in figure:",
    "feedback": "diagram 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a refuelling volumetric top-off unit (VTO) is:",
    "feedback": "to close the fuelling valve when the tank is full."
  },
  {
    "question": "On a FADEC gas turbine engine during normal flight, the power for the FADEC's sensors comes from:",
    "feedback": "the FADEC power source(s) on the engine"
  },
  {
    "question": "Describe the design principle of a horizontal stabiliser trim system in a fully powered flight control system:",
    "feedback": "The entire horizontal tail assembly moves in response to the trim system to stabilise the aircraft in the pitch axis"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of static wick dischargers is to :",
    "feedback": "dissipate static charge of the aircraft inflight thus avoiding radio interference as a result of  static electricity."
  },
  {
    "question": "In accordance with EASA AIR OPS, an airplane constituted of only one passenger deck, equipped with 61 seats and effectively carrying passengers, must be equipped with :",
    "feedback": "1 megaphone."
  },
  {
    "question": "An auxiliary gearbox is driven by.....",
    "feedback": "a rotating engine shaft, via an internal gearbox, to an external gearbox"
  },
  {
    "question": "The function of a vibrator in some gas turbine ignition systems is to provide:",
    "feedback": "a DC current to the transformer to facilitate the generation of a higher voltage to the igniters"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct about the flow in a divergent (subsonic) gas turbine engine intake?\n\n1) The static pressure remains constant in flow direction\n2) The total temperature decreases in flow direction",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "A propeller blade is twisted in order to:",
    "feedback": "maintain a constant angle of attack along the blade"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hydraulic pressure typically used in the system of large transport aircraft is:",
    "feedback": "3000 - 4000 psi"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about structural design principles are correct or incorrect?  1) In structural design, fail safe implies redundant load paths 2) A safe life structure is based on a declared number of cycles or time period",
    "feedback": "1) is correct,2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main advantage of a constant speed propeller as compared to a fixed pitch propeller is that it:",
    "feedback": "maintains its maximum propeller efficiency over a wider range of airspeeds"
  },
  {
    "question": "In computer technology, an input peripheral is a:",
    "feedback": "keyboard"
  },
  {
    "question": "Under normal flight conditions, cabin pressure is controlled by:",
    "feedback": "regulating the discharge of air through the outflow valve(s)"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the axial flow compressor of a turbo-jet engine, the flow duct is tapered. Its shape is calculated so as to:",
    "feedback": "maintain a constant axial speed in cruising flight."
  },
  {
    "question": "The following problems may occur when starting a twin-spool turbofan engine:",
    "feedback": "no N1 rotation, although N2 may accelerate normally"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the common operating pressure of the hydraulic system on most large transport aeroplanes?",
    "feedback": "3000 psi"
  },
  {
    "question": "The advantages of fly-by-wire control are:\n\n1. reduction of the electric and hydraulic power required to operate the control surfaces\n2. lesser sensitivity to lightning strike\n3. direct and indirect weight saving through simplification of systems\n4. immunity to different interfering signals\n5. improvement of piloting quality throughout the flight envelope\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "3 and 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "A control surface has its limitations in movement by:",
    "feedback": "primary stops at the surface."
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding a jet engine:\n\n1) The maximum thrust increases as the pressure altitude decreases\n2) The specific fuel consumption is proportional to pressure altitude at constant TAS",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which modes of operation can be found in fly-by-wire aircraft?",
    "feedback": "Normal, Alternate (Secondary), Direct, Mechanical"
  },
  {
    "question": "A condenser in parallel with breaker points will",
    "feedback": "intensify current in secondary winding"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cockpit indications associated with a windscreen heating system usually comprise:",
    "feedback": "a green system \"ON\" information light and an amber system failure light."
  },
  {
    "question": "At constant RPM with a normally aspirated engine and a fixed pitch propeller, as altitude increases, if the mixture is not leaned:",
    "feedback": "both the density of air entering the carburettor and the fuel flow decrease"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Throttle Lever Angle (TLA) information of a FADEC controlled gas turbine engine is provided:",
    "feedback": "to the electronic engine control unit by a direct electrical wiring connection"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sort the following environments from the highest rates of corrosion to the lowest:\n1) Desert2) Mediterranean3) Rainforest4) The arctic",
    "feedback": "3, 2, 1, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many megaphones are required in an airplane with a maximum approved passenger seating configuration of 85 seats and only 5 passengers on board?",
    "feedback": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "The cross-feed fuel system is used to :",
    "feedback": "feed every engine from any fuel tank."
  },
  {
    "question": "After air has passed through the compressor of a gas turbine engine the:",
    "feedback": "temperature will be higher than the inlet temperature."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct for a gas turbine engine with a constant speed propeller and free power turbine, when the power setting is decreased?\n\n1) The propeller blade angle decreases\n2) The free power turbine speed decreases",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "A gaseous fire loop system is tested by:",
    "feedback": "heating up the sensor"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a jet engine the propelling nozzle:",
    "feedback": "must be designed to obtain the correct balance of pressure and velocity changes."
  },
  {
    "question": "Fixed oxygen systems in pressurised aeroplanes are used to provide oxygen:\n\n1) in the event of depressurisation\n2) in the event of any passenger indisposition\n3) during a normal flight\n4) in the event of smoke or toxic fumes in the cockpit\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the principle advantage of using propeller reduction gears?",
    "feedback": "To enable the engine RPM to be increased with an accompanying increase in power and allow the propeller to remain at a lower, more efficient RPM."
  },
  {
    "question": "Icing of the carburetor can take place?",
    "feedback": "When the temperature drops and sufficient moisture is present for sublimation."
  },
  {
    "question": "The trim tab :",
    "feedback": "reduces hinge moment and control surface efficiency."
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the diagram.  GEN 1 can be used to feed the AC BUS 1, when: (NB: all contactors not mentioned are assumed to remain open)",
    "feedback": "C1.1 is closed"
  }
]